hello everybody this is etho and guess
what I installed a light in my house now
and it really brings the place together
feels a lot more cozy and yeah you guys
owe me big because I'm recording in an
HD now and I finally broke down it's
it's a real pain I have to change my
desktop resolution to record in HD
because for some reason not still hasn't
added the ability to change your
resolution in the game don't really know
why and yes I know there are mods and
stuff to resize the window but if you're
not playing the game in full-screen it
actually doesn't run as fast because
it's not freeing up resources that like
it still needs the resources to run your
desktop if you're playing in window mode
so that's why you want it in full-screen
and so I record that mop the system to
twirl and right after that I went caving
got tons of iron now like more than I
could ever need don't have a whole lot
of coal I usually don't pick it up
got lots of clay not from there though
not a whole lot of gold though
every time I go looking for redstone I
keep finding these weird blue shiny
rocks I don't know what to do with them
but I got quite a few of them now 75
what else do we have
my minecart system is currently broken a
bunch of water spilt and wrecked all my
wiring so now I need to fix things and
make it waterproof I got a bunch of this
stuff he's doing a test here I wanted to
see if wolves could shear sheeps
Wolves ruined or like if a wolf is here
and the Sheep is on the other side of
the door and all that yeah I tried
switching the door around to it they are
myself still brainstorming ideas on how
to get my automatic wool shearing
working well I know ways of doing it but
I'm still looking for like them
perfectly yeah got the glass now lots of
stench and stone lots of sand and I'll
show you why later let's see
this is gonna be kinda like a general
video with no specific purpose I like it
all this mossy cobblestone been finding
lots of dungeons and I even have some
redstone now so I'm pretty happy about
that
I haven't found a whole lot like when I
go caving I I don't know I just keep
finding these blue rocks instead yeah so
anyway I built a little room here still
need to extend this out more I might
build a dock or something out here I
think not really sure I've got some
flowers which is just lovely
and I did these spiral water staircases
again for my new Baconator probably
gonna do a few changes to this yet so
the pigs fall down I raised the lava 1
square or one block I mean and that's
still they still found through it's
pretty nice storing the cooked bacon in
here beginning Lots it's not really
working fast now it does at night though
because I still have a lot of grass to
get rid of I like to replace some of
this with brick maybe this one stone I
don't know and I might get rid of this
glass wall here
not sure and then we just have to exit
here the water break and it takes you
back here so I liked it it works but
yeah we had a specific goal today I said
I was going to I'm probably not going to
actually because I don't know where I'm
gonna put it for one thing and I don't
feel like it really but I will show you
I will show you how to move the squids
up in case you want to build your own
split farms I was working on digging out
more of the collection points and I
found some squids so I did some tests to
them actually I got a look up to the
ones name one section yeah so like I
think when squids came out I did this
test to see if they could go up half
slabs and stairs and they weren't able
to they would get stuck like if water
was pushing them towards the half slab
or stair to see if they would go up it
they wouldn't then a guy - master one
thank you - master he sent me a video
response telling me to try fences and I
never did because I had no splits around
and I kind of didn't think it would be
any different than what I had tried with
half slabs and stairs but when I was
digging out the collection points other
day I found some squids and I still
remembered his response so I thought hey
might as well try it out now and to my
surprise it worked
but here's the interesting thing I tried
it again with the half step I just
killed the squid was it my fault what
was I saying
yeah I tried half slabs and stairs again
and they also work now so something
changed with their I don't know what you
call it their behavior so they can go up
half slabs and stairs now and I will
prove that to you now with this fatty so
we have a water stream going towards a
half slab here and this sign keeps the
water from back flowing towards this
screen and over here is a fence which
they're going up as well to push this
guy in he should go up the half slab or
stair or fence whatever you use
so far this hasn't turned out too well I
almost think fences do work better hey
what are you doing dude
they're finally they do go up
I think fences do work better but they
have a problem I think if you log out
and they're over top of fence they'll
get stuck in the fence like they'll fall
down the block into the fence kind of
like how mobs go through class if you
log out and they're being pushed against
it so yeah
fences may work better I don't know for
sure but they have that problem too yes
those thing works a lot better at night
got way more bacon than I ever need it's
pretty cool and then below you can watch
and burn it's pretty much exactly what I
wanted
if you did want the cooked bacon to fall
into a water stream I think the way I
would do that is drop them down one by
one tube like this through the lava like
I'm doing here
but drop them on top of a fence post
with water stream above and I think I
think that would work I haven't tested
it but I think they would still on be
fun they would still be on fire and the
gravity would kill them I'm falling and
they should drop cook pork chops even
though they're landing in water
I think they'll hit the fence post first
before they get sting
I think but I haven't tested it so I'm
gonna grab a nap here and we'll go back
to the squids yeah that's fine
one day I'll light up the area around
you the thing is I think they'll take a
lot of the fun under the game if there's
absolutely no mobs around I hope I
killed that guy okay so try to get these
guys I don't want to you know die in
here
oh he did this Oh different oh that was
weird
okay so what I'm going to show you is
how you can move them up vertically as
quickly as I know how
actually I'll pause it and do it off
camera because there's other things I
want to do this episode and then this
will take a while okay nevermind I
changed my mind I'll do it on camera
because a lot of people have been asking
me how to make these spiral staircases
so may as well show it this here will be
the center and I'm using glass even
though I'm going to destroy this
and so you need to keep the water in
position and you do that using these
signs they're a little bit tedious to
build but I like them they're pretty
cool
I'm sure you could build them pretty
fast if you made a few of them okay so
nope I guess the sign is one two I place
it there and then we place our water
yeah so it pulls you in okay so I
usually just place the signs on the
inside column here and you keep going up
one level next one will go here and if
you keep going you just keep going
around I think that's as high as I'm
gonna make this test here
you know I'm pleased glass all around
here
I hate wasting glass but but lots of
people are watching this so might as
well not be stingy these that whole pots
of people are watching this and yeah you
just keep going so you can go up every
two blocks horizontally you go you can
go one block up maybe I should take this
down off camera but you guys seem to
like me building things on camera and I
aim to please
watch it's not work when it's all said
and done oh yeah I made a bunch of signs
and you just fill your water and all
right well let's call this the top so
I'm gonna push a squid in and it should
somehow make his way to the top over
time
he'll probably fight climbing up though
but you will see they can swim against
the current so if you want to keep them
from going back you can have a drop like
I have here I got you can't even get up
here
usually they gets spazzing the walls
like that it might work better if you
make your canals too wide but I haven't
tried that yet you should give it enough
time make his way up so but he'll try to
go down
yeah it's not it's not gonna be fast
that's for sure you can make it buddy
no you don't want to go that way I
believe in you Oh big like 15 frames per
second but yeah anyway that's the idea
he's slowly making his way up and every
now and then he goes back down and then
comes back up it's like a tug-of-war
but since the screens are pulling him in
general he will make his way up
given enough time and he is stuck now
they can't swim once they're on dry land
so he made it congratulations
ok so you guys can go ahead and make
your squid farms before me if you want I
don't really know exactly what I'm gonna
do with mine yet but if you're new to my
channel if you don't know how this works
I'll explain it to you again
the idea is to set up these collection
points every so often in your world
because since there's thousands and
thousands of water source blocks all
around my base there's pretty much an
endless number of locations where the
squid can spawn so in order to control
them you need to
try to make it so that they all funnel
to a central point since they can't swim
they'll go to the lowest point in the
ocean and you find all these little
points you can terraform the bottom of
the ocean to to make them and then you
dig down place a sign try to do it
against the wall like I have here so the
squid will align with the wall and then
fall down they fall through these things
into water streams make sure they can't
get out of the water streams and it just
keeps pulling them and pulling them all
towards a central point where you want
them all to collect and you make him
wheel up or you can make a drop oh
that's bad that's bad now I need to fix
that
yeah
and so you need to yeah so with these
spiral staircase things you can bring
them up vertically quickly doing this or
you can just gradually bring them up
vertically if you want or you know
however you want to do it and it should
be possible to hook up an automatic
killing thing using lab and stuff which
I might get into I probably will make it
manual though because there won't be
tons of squid so I'll want them to all
collect and then I'll choose to kill
them and so I don't miss picking up
their ink sacs before they D spawn and
so yeah set up your collection points in
the ocean I have I think two that way
I've got one over there there's one in
that area there I think there's one over
here so I got them kind of spread around
all around my base I haven't started
doing this yet but if you have a bunch
of collection points you can share water
streams like I could if I had one over
here see over there I could make it go
to the right and connect with this
stream here and then branch them all
together if you want or you can make
separate streams or you know figure it
out on your own I guess I'm saying do
what you want to do yeah so I think
that's all we're going to do with the
squid farm today
I just wanted to show you what's off in
this direction and while we're traveling
there talk about a few things and I want
to give a shout out to in frizam and to
everybody on a server they're a bunch of
cool guys and they recently made a very
interesting video I'm gonna link it in
the description it's a I guess you could
say a musical but it's not corny it's
pretty funny
that is a lot of cool people on his
servers that Doc and Stephen Scott Joker
HD Onix tiger and a bunch of other
people aren't forgetting at the moment
and most of these people have their own
YouTube channels as well so yeah look
around you'll find their channels and
don't know if I'm gonna link them in the
description it sounds like a bit of work
but I might we'll see and well I guess
I'm out of time yeah so this is where
I've been getting my sand from in case
you've been wondering and my sandstone I
clean this all out using shovels found a
bunch of clay around here too
hey-ya I hate mining sand no it's brutal
probably my least favorite thing to do
in this game actually cuz I you guys
probably don't know this but I don't
have any strip mines anywhere I don't
like strip mining either what I do is I
go is be lunching and I've built many
mob systems there's one right over there
and when I build these I did a lot of
resources and then I also hopefully I
can sleep here without dying
wow I can't believe that worked
when I build these mob systems I have to
light up the tunnels around the area too
and as I do that I get tons of iron and
redstone not so much I get those blue
shiny rocks sometimes so that's where
all my resources are coming from I'm not
cheating but yeah I hate strip mining so
I don't do it except for collecting sand
which has changed now I have a new
method of getting sand that I'm much
prefer so I'll show you what that is I
just started doing this very recently I
found a desert finally there's one over
here it's not a huge desert but just I
don't think it is I haven't explored the
whole thing yet
I'm sure a lot of added skeletons around
here huh let's see let's go to sweet
spots
[Music]
yeah let's go over there probably start
exploring some land here haven't walked
this far yet that's actually a pretty
big desert I'm surprised
okay so my new method is I grab T and T
of course and I dig down as deep as I
can space it's four blocks apart you
might be able to go further I haven't
experimented too much with this yet not
real science to it or anything just
[Music]
yeah so you do that 3/4 and what I do is
I place TT over top some schools it's
not as efficient as using a shovel but
boy it's a lot more fun and it's a lot
more fast and that's what I like and
then once you're done that you go and
pick all the pickup all the cool little
blocks everywhere the TMT destroys some
of them but who cares it's like an
infinite number of deserts out there
that I can go hunting for more sand if I
want and I'm gonna experiment with this
more there's probably better ways of
doing this too like if you saw my up mop
succinct oral I have a new way of mining
where the TNT does a chain reaction
blast and every T&T mines out of three
by five by four area
just pretty cool
keep the cave system around here is
insane
you guys play my world go check it out
it is so huge and complex
I was down there for I think two hours
today just exploring and collecting
resources lighting up the tunnels and I
am probably only 1/3 done all right so
you got one two one two three four about
four and a half stacks of sand doing
that and about two stacks of sand stone
so works out pretty good I think
and that wasn't that many TNT and I have
pretty much infinite gunpowder I just
don't have infinite sand so it's nice to
have fast ways of getting sand ok these
ones are spaced 5 apart now let's see
let's see if they do is need of a job
[Music]
well it's that time again boys and girls
the time that we're out of time and it's
got one last thing to talk about I'm
gonna be building my tree farm so more
as I talk so the month of May is here
and what that means is I start working
10 to 12 hour days so I'm not gonna have
a whole lot of time for Minecraft for
the next month
and that means don't expect a whole lot
of videos from me unfortunately
I'm still gonna try to release at least
once a week is my goal but hopefully at
least two a week that's what I'm aiming
for I basically get back at around 10
p.m. and good thing is I pretty much
only feel like playing on my computer so
good chance I will be playing Minecraft
when I'm not working actually know what
I'm gonna build
I should have brought an axe with me I
might be putting some lava on the top
here so I'm gonna use wooden half slabs
but yeah don't expect much from me
unfortunately good news is once May is
over I'll have lots of time so you
should be able to attempt some bigger
projects then and because I've actually
been pretty busy lately
and I still managed to get tons of
Minecraft videos out somehow but yeah
and June arrives I should have a lot
more time again and I'll start the
secret project then I think and I might
try to do dual comms with people they'll
be easier to arrange my stitch will then
so we'll see how things turn out I
probably won't have time to go through
your video responses anymore and I'm not
very good at responding to PM's but I'll
probably be doing that even less if you
can believe it so yeah good news is you
guys don't have to work ten or twelve
hour days I do seasonal work
and I'm not gonna tell you what it is
you can
I'm sure someone also tell you I was
thinking about building this out of
sandstone the second half but I might
look a little bit weird might stand out
too much yeah but anyway that's the
dealio um I thank you guys for watching
my videos I hope you continue to even
though there won't be as many and I'll
see you again next time
I forgot to mention even though I won't
really have time to respond to your PM's
and stuff I still will be reading them
also you don't need to stop sending me
them I do always read them this it takes
a lot more time responding to them and
same with your comments I always read
your comments so don't feel like you
need to stop that okay bye bye