hey everybody says evil thank you for
joining me it again and so I thought I'd
do a follow up a blast episode on
general spaz because many of you were
wondering how this all worked so I might
as well reveal my secrets this thing
took a while to set up I did not use any
mods or external editors like embed it
or anything like that it's all done
naturally I should say this is the tower
general spazzes tower how did I get him
up there there's a little elevator in
here very simple originally I had a
spiral staircase a water spiral
staircase kind of like it I've been
building at my base and that did not
work he would not go up it so I found I
just did this it's much simpler and it's
just two water sources I actually
learned something really interesting
about this what I was doing is that when
night came I ran into the forest then
got a creeper to chase me general spaz
ran through the tower with them chasing
me then I ran out round the backside
used f3 to see where he was and when he
got to the elevator there he would swim
up into the tower and then he was stuck
in the tower is how it worked but the
thing I found interesting is originally
when I did this I just had the one water
source at the top and none down here and
what happened when he walked into the
tower he just sat here the first time I
tried it
he wouldn't swim up so by placing a
water source here I learnt that when I
tried it again he swam up to the top
so that's a pretty interesting thing
about how mobs work if they touch a
water source a solid water source they
start swimming up but if it's just a
stream it doesn't change their state so
that information is going to help me
later I'm sure
and yeah okay let's go back up Tower I
have the dispensers here which were full
of arrows and those were simply fired by
spazz by stepping on these pressure
plates I discovered I had to punch holes
in the glass so that his pathfinding to
actually see me because before that he
was just wandering randomly up here and
quite often he while I got it on my
third take actually that's seen but the
first two were very short because spaz
messed up up here I think I have a video
of it actually uh-huh
I knew it well I didn't know so the
really hard part was a getting all four
Beach troopers or whatever you want to
call them
oh crap without messing everything
so to do it properly I had to run around
at night and click creepers like that
into the holes all four holes with
general spaz in the tower I had a boat
with me in case any skeletons or
whatever spawn nearby I had to deal with
them so that I could go get more
creepers and at the same time I wasn't
allowed to leave this area like if I
walked 32 blocks away there's a chance
mobs will despawn I have to beg creepers
that's not good Lots gonna mess up
explanation here right where is he so in
order to do this required many mini
backups like hit messing up basically I
got them in the hole covered it up I had
to get four guys in the holes spaz in
the tower wasn't allowed to leave the
area for very long to click more
creepers have to deal with other mobs
[Music]
and the thing is so I had a TNT really
been sick of Steel
TNT fell on a pressure plate which
activate a bunch of repeaters here that
were covered by sand the final or Peter
went right where that stone block is
which sand is being held up by these
torches here the water flows down here
destroys the torches causes the sand to
fall which releases the creepers because
like this block of sand falls Stroh's
assigns sand over top falls down which
creates the stairs for the creepers to
climb out and hit me is how it worked
very complicated so the repeater passes
a current through this block here which
caused the water update which is set up
like this and this had to be all covered
the water poured down cause the sand
fall release the creepers but one thing
I discovered is I didn't have this setup
right so I actually had to with the
creeper still here dig them out which
was near impossible without them on dead
end it what the heck
oh it was very challenging to set up
that's that's all I'm going to tell you
my explanation is ruined now so not much
more I can explain here because
everything is destroyed now required
many backups oh yeah okay on with the
show yeah I wasn't too happy about them
blowing up my Beach so I just loaded
another backup so here we are again back
back like it was but yeah I realized
like when I tested it out with the way
it is here and creeper was where the
stone is here and the sand fell on him
and he was supposed to jump up and jump
on top the sand but what I found was
most of the time they wouldn't do that
they were unable to see me because the
sand was inside of them so they just
stood there and I could actually walk
right up to the creeper and touch him
without them blowing up it's kind of
weird so what I had to do was with the
creeper still in here I had to extend
this make it one longer and place a
torch at the bottom
dig this down place a torch and oh yeah
another thing I had a chest here hidden
under the sand so that when I was all
done I could hide whatever was in my
inventory that wasn't supposed to be
there like tea and tea or pressure
plates or anything like that
going to make a sign here so what
happened is I had another sign this was
longer had the creeper stand where the
torch is and so when the sand falls on
him this time the torch destroys the
sand so there were he would be inside
air then so it was fine but I had to
make some more sand blocks fall down so
that their pathfinding could see me was
uh this is a big challenge the
pathfinding was the main issue I had and
keeping the mobs from despawning while I
collected more well yeah that's it
that's how it worked so obviously these
towers aren't very useful if you plan on
loading them with creepers because the
creepers will just be spawn but they
might be useful if if you plan on
operating them yourselves because it's a
really easy way of setting up a defense
that you can choose where you're going
to fire like if I want to shoot in front
of me just have to walk forward you can
set up big walls lined with dispensers
and arrows I don't know do whatever you
want to do now let's head back to the
base now
okay so I think I want to talk about is
the mob systems I've built I've kind of
been home humming about them about what
I'm going to do because to be completely
honest I'm not totally happy with the
way they're turning out like don't get
me wrong they're really neat and
everything but I started building the
mob system back in episode 15 actually
which was a long time ago and at that
time I didn't know very much about mob
behavior or how to build spawning pads
or anything like that I kind of figured
it out as I went along and pieced it all
together and this is what we have now a
few things I redid try to improve
certain things it's working so so but in
all honesty it's kind of sloppy in my
opinion so in trying to figure out what
to do I can't really tear it down and
start fresh because that would involve
redesigning the storage room and
everything to do what I want to do so
I'm not going to do that the plan is I'm
going to finish this up as well as I can
and then if I like I want everything
working to the point where I'm happy
with it so for example this pig
separator here I'm very happy with this
it works perfect in my opinion the only
issue is it like seven pigs fall down at
the same time they might not get split
here they might go with the sheep and
cows not a big deal I can extend that if
I want to all right
I could make it so that they don't
converge to a one widescreen here and
make it wider and I won't have any
issues the other thing I'm really happy
with is the wolf separator that seems to
work perfect some things I'm not happy
with at the moment are the chicken
killing thing because they seem to get
stuck in the doors kind of so I might
work on fixing that obviously that
Junction is not to my liking because it
was a sheep stuck there I don't like
this being a two-by-two area because
mobs can get stuck like this quite
frequently so we're going to change that
yeah so I'm just going to try figure out
how to get this working well all the
individual parts and then if I ever make
a base somewhere else in my an LP series
when I redo it all it'll be really easy
to figure out and I'll have everything
working neatly and cleanly and organized
the way I want it nice and compact
instead of having like a long tunnel
here for the pig to get killed I'm also
really happy with the way I'm getting
cooked pork chops there that seems to
work really well
spawning pads if I ever build them again
in the future they will probably be an
odd number with all the mobs converging
to one by one area I know how to do that
now properly before when I tried it like
if I make all these streams merge
together with a one block opening only
instead of this 2x2 area the mobs won't
fall down the one they won't fall down
the one block wide area the one by one
they'll just keep bumping each other and
it takes forever for them to fall down
if they do but I know how to fix that
now which I won't show you now but later
I will if I do that these spawning pads
I'll probably change in the future if I
do it again I have issues with chickens
getting stuck in the stairs here
sometimes this chickens are really small
they can fit in that quarter cut out
section and then they don't move
oh yeah so I think next episode we're
going to work on cleaning this one up we
want this one working well as well as we
can get it too so we're going to fix it
up one thing I'm going to do next
episode I think is get rid of this 2x2
area and try and make it a one by one so
that they don't get stuck here and then
later we're going to hopefully build our
barn or whatever down there where the
Sheep of cows go and the holes one thing
I have to figure out yet is how to shear
the wool off sheep well like obviously
wolves the untamed wolves can do it but
I just can't throw a bunch of wolves and
sheep together and expect it to work
well because problem with that is
eventually there'll be so many wolves
that no more other mobs will spawn so I
only need one to shear the sheep and I
have to make a way for it to auto detect
that there's only one and if you ever
despond
I need a way for it to know he's the
spawned so that'll send another wolf and
only one wolf and it's kind of
complicated
I actually experimental with it I got
some footage of it I'll show you here
the idea is I had a wolf on one
individual block floating in the air and
I thought if I made a sheep pass right
by him
that he'll shear the sheep off the sheep
as it falls down but the problem is he
just jumps to his death like an idiot so
[Music]
unfortunately that test didn't go the
way I wanted it to the idea was the wolf
would be standing on a pressure plate on
one block in midair and if he was on the
pressure plate the door would be closed
that would determine whether a wolf
would be let onto the pressure plate and
that was how I was going to control only
having one wolf to shear the sheep and I
was hoping he wouldn't jump off the
block as the sheep came by but he did so
it didn't work so need to come up with
another method and like I tried before
he can't shear the wool off sheep
through a door because I could have a
pressure plate just outside the door
here that he would be standing on I
don't know I've been thinking about this
a lot and there's just no good way of
doing it I think no automatic way I
might just make it manual like I might
have to let in one wolf manually I don't
know how else to do it but anyway that's
the end of this episode sorry for making
it a talky one the next episode will
actually do something so thank you for
watching and I'll see you next time