hello everyone this is etho today is a
great day in Minecraft because the beta
1.7 pack why is that creeper Oh what ok
well this episode we're going to play on
peaceful
yeah the beta 1.7 patch came out so I've
been playing around with it already got
sticky pistons Pistons I'll show you how
to make them even though you probably
already know what you need is some iron
cobblestone redstone and some planks and
that makes a piston it's a little bit
different then the the mod the crafting
recipe is different from the mods
crafting recipe once you have a piston
you can use slime balls to make a sticky
piston that's all slime balls that I
have so I can only have 24 right now I
so I'm going to need to make some kind
of slime farm eventually kind of late
games been doing and many other
minecrafters one other thing we also
have shears now and I'll get to that a
little bit as well so I'm very happy
with this updates I've been playing
around with it quite a bit maybe we'll
take care of the little stuff first get
it out of the way Wow one thing that's
changed of course by the way if you guys
want a full nice and concise update
about the updates information about that
date that's why I should say I check out
statics video I'll link in the
description but here's my
unprofessional version Oh one thing
that's changed you can stack stop and
stack fences on top of fences now before
you weren't able to do that you can also
put stuff on top torches
can't put levers any redstone torches
yep what else can we try I guess that's
it so that's different
another thing that's changed and stick
that back TNT has changed in the new
update the 1.7 you can no longer
detonate it using your fists like it
used to be able to you have to use
redstone or fire to set it off and you
can pick it up again after you after you
hit it so kind of a good thing kind of a
bad thing if you ever misplaced TNT it's
really easy to pick it up now where are
the Sheep there's the Sheep so with the
shears you right-click on the sheep to
harvest their wool wow you get four wool
so I guess you get more than you did
before
if the sheep dies with its wool still on
it
he will give you one role so if you
drown them or if they burn or fall to
death or something like that then he'll
get one name from them just like that
that's pretty cool uh one other really
neat thing about the shears that I am
really happy with let's head out side
here you can use them to harvest leaves
from trees so that you can actually
place leaf blocks which is really neat
let's let's go look for some buggy trees
here um there's a good one so left click
drops leaf blocks like that you can pick
them up and then replace them you have
to place them next to a wood block
otherwise they will disappear so they
follow the same rules as leaves normally
do but one neat thing is you can cut
through them really quick with the
shears as well there's actually three
different types of leaf blocks get your
regular kind from regular trees this
color here is from the birch trees I
believe and then this blueish is from
the evergreen type trees and snowy
regions and to pick this stuff up you
need a separate inventory for all three
kinds
although I can't pick this one up for
some reason so maybe there's four kinds
well very strange anyway so I really
like that new feature I was playing
around with the Pistons a bit already
gays will show you some things I tried
one thing I see if you could use them to
harvest reeds without destroying the
plant you can so that's really cool so
that's probably how I'm going to do my
Reed farm whenever I get around to doing
that if you do it from above it kind of
knocks the reed block onto the soil
block below so okay I need to do it from
a side like this and it pushes it aside
that's one neat thing as also playing
around with light switches now they do
work for making light switches I got a
little switch here completely dark and
it a sticky piston which is pulls a
block back
that's cool definitely some uses for
that um all right I'm going to collect
my thoughts a bit I'll actually you know
what I wanted to do fix this guy so now
that we can place leaf blocks it's very
easy to do stuff with leaves don't have
to grow trees to make the leaves take
the shape you want just put them
wherever you want yeah I'm going to
collect my thoughts and then we'll we
got a look at pistons yet and maybe a
few other things
all right maybe we'll do a sheep test I
know if you kill them and they still
have their wool they will always drop
one every time I want to see how much on
average you get shearing them four four
four so I'm guessing it's for every time
oh that guy dropped two for the four was
at five
that was three get quite a bit more than
punching them before
a lot more
three three so it seems to be between
two and four although I've gotten for a
lot more often that's pretty cool okay
let's go over to my experiment island
one other thing that's changed too I
noticed this right away the cobblestone
texture is different it's a lot there's
a lot less contrast to it so it looks
softer I think I like it more but I know
some people are complaining about it
it'll kind of blend in a little bit
better to the other blocks they'll match
other blocks a little bit better alright
let's go to the test area alright let's
have some fun with pistons shall we uh
actually the pistons look like I don't
like them as much as the way the mod
look the mod ones look they looked like
iron blocks these ones kind of look like
dispensers which I've never really been
fond of the texture for dispensers but
that's just the way it is and don't send
me a texture pack because I won't use it
but anyway pointing a fist ends they
move blocks I'm sure you know that once
you send power to them so the normal
Pistons move them the sticky pistons
retract the block with them as well so
this is the difference normal piston
over here
sticky one here looks the same right
well when they retract this is the
difference normal one the block stays
sticky one the block comes with it again
to harvest them you can just punch them
there relieves your harvest and you can
place pistons six directions put them
straight down like that every every
which way and they're lit I find they're
a little bit hard to place but they
probably just require a little practice
and directly down like that um powering
them is much like powering dispensers oh
yeah another new change with the 1.7 so
with the repeaters now you don't need to
run the redstone and extra block light
before you would have to do that forward
to work but now you can just have the
redstone wire adjacent to the repeater
which is very nice should save space on
wiring stuff okay let's have a little
bit fun with pistons shall we something
people are wondering they don't launch
you they just move you up one block they
do not launch sands just move it up one
block and drop it a Pistons to move up
to twelve blocks
so if I could have a stack of 12 sand
and it should move it no problem one
really neat thing about pistons is they
can move items upward like these item
blocks this is the first thing in
Minecraft that can do it so now there's
finally a possible way to transfer items
from below up to your base or whatever
so that's neat I might try to make a
nice design with that and I'm sure many
other people have already one thing I
was playing around with the sticky ones
is doing this and having repeaters every
second block do that set this one to one
one two two three and four now when you
apply power does that Pistons can move
other Pistons if they are not I know
what you call it extracted or if they're
like that they won't move if they're
like that so if I apply power can't move
it it's like that then it can move it so
that's kinda neat
but these won't reject each other you
need to they can only move one block at
a time
so when this one goes bad it's not going
to pull both of them it's only going to
pull one no they're pretty fun
these things are going to be very useful
for many things I also played around
using them as the water gates they do
work here's a crude example so when is
it extended like that the water won't
flow it's back it will and you can use
that for lava and stuff too so on their
own the arms or the plates of the piston
boxes they won't crush animals or mobs
they won't crush players but if you push
a block and make a cal sandwich or a mob
sandwich that does work so let's see it
in action
our cows very comfortably in a one by
two high area piece push in the bottom
one
now still fine a little tight in there
though um today's episode does contain
animal cruelty so parent little guidance
is advised so and you can kill mobs with
pistons if you crush them between blocks
so kinda neat so when I was playing
around with pistons today I came across
something very cool this is going to be
very fundamental to a lot of things I do
I'm sure what you do is you dig one hole
get your get your piston above like that
place the redstone wire below and a
lever next to it turn it on and this
what you have here this is a block
sensor piston
so as soon as you place a block in front
of it it pushes it which is very neat
let's see if you use a sticky piston
something kind of strange happens just
like a real pistol
you can flip it off and on
this is a really neat sensor very
compact here's something else playing
around with I made a loop of them that's
a sticky one so you can chain many of
these together and you can make self
building structures that way of of
whatever proportion you want without
needing any majorly complicated redstone
wiring so let's flip this on this is
four of them going around in them very
tiny loop
but you can make the loop as big as you
want really
maybe I'll set up another example
alright here's another example I just
set up three of the auto sensor piston
things so this is what happens oh I
don't look that one
if you can't move it will destroy the
lever so keep that in mind but pretty
cool you can make self building
structures doing that and mixing it with
cobblestone generators or stuff like
that
I'm sure haven't had much time to play
around with this day put on you're
pretty sure you can do some cool stuff
with distance maybe I'll make a sand
hour oh wait no that won't work like
that you have to do a less fancy way I
set up a repeater um your piston
like that block there and redstone wire
like that this is kind of a another way
of doing a sensor a little bit more
takes up more space and more resources
but there's no hole underneath so I'm
gonna shut this off we'll make a big
sand Tower ah then when you flip it on
fun stuff having a lot of fun with
pistons alright then the last thing is
playing around with today was this this
is kind of like an auto harvesting tree
farm idea I had so if you have a block
here it moves all five of those Pistons
this is the sensor it's running on a
loop to updates when a tree grows um and
there's this wire running up to all five
Pistons so when the tree grows guess
what happens automatically moves all the
logs I'm stuck here let's grow a few
trees so the loop the clock here updates
when the tree grows otherwise that it
won't detect that the tree has grown you
need that at excuse me you need a
adjacent block to update for this sensor
too
detect the tree is round oops
this kind of fun idea I might try make
it tree farm doing something similar to
this maybe a little bit more fancy
though but ya have a lot of fun with
pistons
those are our trees and then you would
just go harvest them really easily
because they're all in a line but anyway
that's all I figured out with pistons so
far a lot of fun like I said I do kind
of plan on making a new base I don't
know if I'm gonna do it right away but
sometime soon and I'll probably start
using pistons for a lot of things in the
new base all your new tree farms Reed
farms stuff like that maybe mob systems
yeah so
oh I hope these I hope this video is
useful for you and I will see you again
next time