is impossible II though your arrogance
will be your downfall my friend your
pride is now eating away like a worm on
your sanity it's impossible you can't
build a mob shorter oh how the tables
have turned that fiery tongue of yours
has gotten you into trouble za Bandito
because i do believe i have done it a
mostly automatic mob sorter and I
believe this is going to cost you a
diamond pickaxe alright let's check this
thing out this was such a pain to build
you have no idea and it's still not
perfect oh here they come
I is coming to get me No Oh what
happened there
isn't that interesting
yeah so uh
big props go to BD tetra for his
skeleton separator oh are you gonna go
over here
no he falls down there um yeah so
yourself skeleton separator made this
possible because I was trying to revise
it and I got it working pretty good and
then I noticed when I was standing in
this tunnel type thing and creepers go
to the left when they're about to
explode
kinda like skeletons go to the left when
they're shooting at you and I'm taking
advantage of X you can make a way to
separate keepers from zombies without
hurting anybody which is pretty awesome
um was a huge pain that they all talk
and it's still not perfect um I got a
shutdown switch here
the doors closing an opening here comes
more thought time that creeper will just
walk straight though and falling through
the zombie chamber seems to be random I
think there's maybe a five to ten
percent chance that they will do that
instead of trying to circle around you
and also there's issues if mobs are
coming together they might bump each
other incorrectly and change where they
they go above the creeper chamber
there's glass so if somehow a skeleton
or zombie gets in there they fry it
works pretty good though I think it's
about 95 percent accurate see even if
they bump each other they use one right
place the main problem is skeletons
Panda
in that spot for a while sometimes get
in the way of other marks the lotus-eyed
they jump here there's a diagonal stream
of water here that pushes them and the
left side which helps to make sure that
the creepers go in there
if the skeleton somehow makes it past
its spots they usually will go to the
creeper section so far it's working your
bill and I don't have this hooked up to
anything I just happened out of the
story neighbors and I think it would
work a lot better if you hooked up the
SOB Angie goes mob regulator that way
they won't come together but yeah it was
so hard to build this up and it's gonna
be hard to copy I'm gonna make a
tutorial for this I'll probably be in a
few let's place for a few days and make
tutorials instead
mind okay so I shut this off now and you
can see we have spiders here skeletons
here here and Tommy's here perfectly
separated and yeah so let's go back to
peaceful I'll take ya take you on take
you to the inside of it so this is my
mob elevator thing the one by one and it
takes you to a junction here I've
changed the junctions with my one to one
block space junctions with the door here
and a door here I found mobs that
sometimes get clumped together and then
get stuck in at the doors so I've made
this junction at two by two and it seems
to not clog up like my other design and
they go directly into water here so they
don't get stuck in the door place over
here and this one goes to nothing and so
I leave her down here oops controls the
door junction over there there's wire
all along the top and it goes down to
goes all along the top
we're here on to the nether rack comes
down here to this block to this torch
and to the two doors
and your positioning is very important
with this you'll notice I have ladders
on the side and the side that is to
create a very small gap from this wall
and this wall it's very important
because if you're against right against
this wall there's a good chance the
creepers are not going to start circling
around you in time and they'll just fall
straight down here and if you're not
against this wall there's a good chance
that every so often mobs
will get stuck in the skeleton place
because they'll be if there are brush
trade against as well sometimes they'll
get sent in the water stream yeah so the
door Junction takes you the water block
here comes up it's too high here so they
can't jump skeleton will see you and
then they'll start circling around they
get into the water and they fall down
the other mobs keep going they'll jump
around here and there's a diagonal
stream of water going going this
direction
and which drops them off around here and
that's a does two things it pushes them
against this wall again and like in case
that cases skeleton is is stuck here and
a creeper bumps against them the creeper
gets bumped to this this wall here a by
the time he gets here we won't be able
to make it to this water screen in time
they'll start circling but you'll fall
down the hole and yeah so pretty cool
try building yourself if you're too
close to this glass block the zombies
will be able to to hit you unfortunately
because it seems to work better if
you're closer but it works well with the
spacing with the ladders do and yeah so
that's the mostly automatic mobs order
it's not fully automatic because you
need to be there to make it work and
it's not perfect one other thing I
noticed I at first I tried building it
onto this door so that it would spread
out this way and the mobs behave
differently so the Sun is setting over
here that's West that's East
so you want the thing to run
I can't do the directions right now you
don't want it running west west to east
that's for sure
because when the mobs get to let's go
back in here if you run out west the
East when the mobs get here instead of
charging at you they're gonna freeze for
some reason they freeze when they see
you and they don't move
for some reason they behave differently
I don't know why so this is running and
I think either north to south or south
to north but yeah pretty cool I think
hope you like it and sorry it took so
long to figure that out I haven't had a
whole lot of time to play I did a little
bit more on the story when I got signs
up now and I think I decided on using
wood in between the chests and I'll
probably have like chandeliers hanging
from the ceiling to light up the room
area a bit more or pot lights or
something I don't
[Music]
and yeah oh yeah so I passed the 500,000
views which is pretty cool over half a
million views for my videos now thanks
to everyone that watches my videos and
keep on watching I don't know if you
guys know this but I don't really
advertise my channel it's mostly you
guys that tell people about it and then
when people find it they seem to
subscribe because they like it
so thanks for advertising for me and
keep on doing it if if people are
talking about on the forums for example
for good alfea's feel free to mention my
name or post links to my channel or post
links to my videos if people are looking
for ideas for things to build and help
me make my channel grow because I depend
on you guys and the more it grows to
more videos on the oops
he'll try to make better business
[Music]
I would definitely recommend you don't
go away you work when you're doing this
because there's a probably a slim chance
people might explode right in your face
it I've had it happen once a skeleton
like start shooting at me in it with a
creeper in it blew up
and another thing to do is whoa another
thing you can do with that thing is if
one of the mobs goes in the wrong place
you can hook up a lever or something to
automatically kill any that slip by
somehow the hook up a killing mechanism
through all three of the chambers it'll
work
well guys I guess we're about out of
time so I'm gonna wrap it up here
sorry if I rambled a bit this episode
but I was very excited to show this
thing off and I'll probably hook up
still haven't given up on the refuge
studio
I'll try hook it up to this thing I
might need to raise this higher and
rebuild it all I don't know yet but yeah
thanks for watching and I'll see you
next time