hello hello you're joining me Ethan as
we work on another minecraft adventure
together and Cays episode is going to be
a learning adventure because we're going
to be working on our mob system here
some more and we're going to turn the
volume down first I guess yeah so we're
going to be working on the second story
of this mob system which is going to
have the mobs order on it I know I said
we were going to build the first story
first with all the the chests and
everything I get that all done but I
feel like working on this today so
that's what we're going to be doing so
the first thing we need to do I've kind
of planned this all out already we need
to make a way to get up and down to the
second story easy so we're going to make
an elevator up here I March the spot
already and so I count one two three
four five and
six we are going to be making something
similar to my easy exits for the e
throat place glass blocks all around the
outside I'll load up the center and then
from up high we're going to place a boat
in the middle just like that and what
that does we can break up these dirt
blocks now oh I wonder why that didn't
work huh all right ended up taking like
ten minutes to figure this out so I just
scrap the video and I'll tell you how
how to do it
I guess he's what we needed a box on the
bottom only one block is needed but I
put eight around make it look better and
this bottom is one to three blocks off
the ground
I'm gonna place the boats at least one
block I break out the bottom and you go
to suspended boat right-click go up and
you can walk around on it without it
moving out of place and then from this
one you count to two blocks up one two
and this is where the bottom starts for
your next one and you don't need to
build it out of glass you can use
whatever you want okay and I'm sure
other people have feared how to make
this kind of elevator - it's not really
that complicated okay and then over here
I built a a break and what I'm going to
be doing is something similar to what
what's his name the mighty miner what he
did he used my minecart dates basically
there'll be a minecart gate here you can
check out my minecart Kade a video and
he sent a video response to it to see
what he did but basically he had a
minecart date with a button you stand on
top it and then press the button and you
fall down a floor
and the power save by a water break
that's kind of what I'm going to be
doing not quite as fancy shoes right
click right click easy to go up easy to
go down okay
I'll polish it up later
and add the minecart key okay so now we
got that set we're going to start
building the floor and I'm just going to
be using cobblestone oh yes and I might
change it later I don't really like
using cobblestone for floors
extend these higher this tube is for the
tall bobs and then this one is for these
spiders all right
so floor is going to be at this level
and okay what I'm going to do first I
think I'm going to go up to here and
going to put a door in here so that we
can access this to make sure the door is
facing this way is right now the only
way I can get inside this mob area is to
go down to the pads there and swim up
like the mobs do so now I got an easy
way to get in and add water stuff
so first thing I'm going to do going to
place the door here the reason for this
is if I want them to go up another level
I'm going to have a junction here so
that I'll have the option even though I
probably won't want them going up
another level but oh yeah um I need to
we're gonna have to go down and copy it
okay so diagonal stream this new level
is lowered talking and the door is
actually down one level so that means I
want to stay down one block maybe not
this other doors in the way down so
we'll keep it there and we're actually
going to make a three way Junction here
we're not going to deal with the spiders
yet okay we're going to want this door
to open the other way I think and so we
got a block there we're going to remove
this one so it has to attach to this
block okay that's good and so we want a
diagonal stream that comes to this
corner here and my game keeps getting
laggy I think I might have to switch
back to standard definition it's really
annoying me a lot of glass okay it will
be a sign here I thought it matters much
and if I want to go up another level
there will be water where this block is
okay I grabbed some more glass and going
to hook up some levers to our doors here
and I'm still lagging yeah that one's
good oh and the spider thing might be an
issue what to do with the spiders I just
just build over top it and we can route
them out lower we will need to capital
either here
all right I don't think my mom strap is
working as well more for some reason I
don't know something got changed and one
of the patches but there's just as many
guys now so I'll probably have to do
some maintenance on it soon figure out
what the problem is okay we can control
the doors now and get some water all
right so I built the water spring over
here just temporary I filled this tube
up of water and I brought some stairs
with me and we're going to place stairs
here not that way
like that the reason for that is because
sometimes mobs can stuck and get stuck
in this set to block space where the
door is
and they won't move because they can't
see outside of the space until another
mob comes up and pushes them up we're
going to have to do that over here too
okay all right
and so we need to make a diagonal stream
of water right over here and we're going
to do that so we place one block here Oh
actually forgot a source block here and
another one there so it creates a
diagnose stream of water that pushes
towards this corner and that is
important because the door hinge is on
this left side so we need them against
this right side otherwise we're going to
run it to this hinge and same with other
door it's pushing them to the left side
so they go under to the end on the right
side okay
of course the lever is going to be
reversed from each other though because
the doors are reversed and
from there I'm going to place I'm going
to place one water block here and then
another one like these uh those two
blocks are December in like that so now
we have a three-way junction they can
either go up if I continue to make this
higher if both doors are closed if that
door is open they will go this way if
that door is open then the world this
way and if they're both opens well then
it depends on whichever stream they
touch first okay and the reason we have
two streams one of these is going to go
to the mob sorter probably this one and
this one is going to be for if we don't
want to sort the mobs so two options
sort the lumps or don't sort the mops
okay
so this is the we're not going to work
on this one just yet actually we're
going to plug it up even we should maybe
test this up too so for right now the
unsorted mobs we're just going to die
alright let's test this out make sure
our Junction works so switching that
door so let's all go up now and my game
is getting laggy again yeah I think my
computer is overdue for a reboot it's
been on for like two weeks now without
rebooting ok so that one works close
that one oh crap
uh hate to be cheap but oh no no I was
on peaceful oh ok we're ending it here
I'm gonna rebuild this and I'll see you
next time