hey guys welcome back this is episode 16
and like I said in our last episode we
are going to go on a journey we need to
go find some slow sand so that we can
invent a timer a mechanical timer for
this device so we have a mission we are
going to the nether down our abandoned
mine here and we got our portal set up
from before and I'm already I think I
have tons of meats ready to go I even
made a bow and just the show I'm pulling
out the big stops I even made armor I'm
going to be like indestructible in there
got some flint and steel crafting table
put that there
torches okay so our objectives on our
mission are to one build a small basis
of operations to collect about 30 to
slow's hand and three returned alive
with it that's going to be a challenge
and we are playing on hard we're not
allowed to go off hard and I've spent
about a total of five minutes in the
nether not playing on peaceful so I'm
going to totally suck so let's hope for
the best
first time entering the nether in this
world that's dar Fetzer speaking gasps
to him where is he oh yeah we found slow
sand already okay
this was easier than I thought yeah
we're going to set up a base here
nothing fancy small nose no guests yet
so I don't think these guys attack you
unless you attack them all right this
holes are for Windows this is a lot
easier than I suspected oh man
and I brought some glass with us
and see I think door pretty nice place
to start off we're gonna build a chest
or two and we're actually going to also
build the furnace all right I'm gonna
put some stuff in here
all right so now we have been to harvest
some of the slow sand amazed there's no
chance I want to fight them but I'm
afraid okay this place is overrated this
is so easy
oh yeah bullseye oh this is kind of
boring that's it I gotta say I'm pretty
disappointed with this place
all right we're going back
maybe next time
mission accomplished
hmm they must not be spawned when you
leave oh yeah
well I thought we were going to spend
the whole episode in there but it was
pretty lame so I guess we'll start
trying to figure out how to build timer
so we're going to use the slow sand to
slow down the boat so that the timer can
be smaller and going to be a mechanical
timer using boats the first thing we got
to do is figure out how fast boats move
they're influenced by slow sand and I
don't know if I have any whip left this
is going to get a bit of wood so that
makes a base
and we'll just um do some testing over
here I guess make a few boats
all right so I think the first thing
we'll do is we'll dig out a three-wide
area maybe beep block song and then
we're going to place our water and we're
going to play slow sand all along
so when we place our boat here get
placed underneath the slow sand or not
right again yeah that's the thing about
working with boats you go through a lot
of wood really fast okay come on I
placed it right
last vote that's not good so I think
when the boat starts out it has to be
under any normal block instead of this
whole sand all right round two
mm why isn't that working
all right we're gonna get some pressure
plates and we're gonna build an ez
loader
I'm not sure why this isn't working
right it's definitely short now place it
in the middle
okay so we need to make a vote I think
take five minutes
going along slow sand like this roughly
five minutes four minutes is probably
good so I'm going to time how long this
takes and then I'll figure out how long
it needs to be and I'll probably build
it off-camera and then show you when I
get it all figured out
yes I just were about out of time here
sorry this episode was kind of boring I
was expecting the episode where we go to
the nether to people or anybody it was
like this world is more dangerous in the
daytime the nether was and so I'm going
to measure how long it takes the boats
to travel one block in when influenced
by slow sand and then I'll figure out
how long I need to make the boat go and
I also need to figure out how to so if I
pick up the items I need it to reset to
back to zero and start counting up to
four minutes again so I'll have to
figure out how to do that and I'll
probably expand our mob room down there
a little bit more to and hopefully start
structuring out the storage room a bit
but anyway thanks for watching and until
next time