hello everyone this is e Phil and this
is the 50th episode of the LP series and
this is also the 1 million view special
so it's pretty cool channel has grown
quite a bit lately so thanks to
everybody that watches my videos I
really appreciate it guys who's a good
boy
and I'm going to give a shout out to
coast on co-stars been mentioning me a
lot lately and I think that's helped my
subscriber count quite a bit and also my
viewers he tweeted about my death I
think yeah episode 48 he thought it was
really funny and I just saw his episode
where Nikko pushed him into the lava and
I thought that was pretty funny he lost
all of his diamond tools and his food
and his wood but it's pretty good so
that was a pretty epic death too so
thanks to CoStar he also mentioned that
I saw in the forums there's a topic for
people's favorite minecraft commentators
and co-star mentioned me and is number 3
along with the future so that's cool
because he's a he's at the top of my
list for favorite commentators too
and as well I like watching a m77 of
course these builds awesome stuff and
he's got a great accent knows how to
make things look good and he knows how
to build complicated stuff too and SC
joiner is also really good to watch he
likes to build technical stuff like I do
so it's always fun to see someone else
that does that and since this is a
special episode you know what's coming
you've seen it too many times before
we're gonna harvest the clay guys Oh get
excited
no don't harvest the clay so don't do it
no I'm gonna do it no oh just kidding
I'm not gonna do it oh I thought you
were really going to do it no I was just
kidding giggles yeah you guys know the
drill we're not going to do that anymore
because I think that jokes getting
pretty old so instead we're going to do
something that was suggested many times
and a long time ago as well and we're
going to put glass all around it because
that's something I wanted to do for a
while
I'm curious to see how much clay is
actually here and yeah I'm going to give
shoutouts to other people too Taikan and
watching some of his stuff lately and of
course saw Benji doe freak entertainer
although they haven't been making as
many videos lately
static he's been making some good stuff
CaptainSparklez he's one of my favorite
two commentators as well and you know
what I think we're just going to leave
it like that yeah
so quite a bit of clay actually and now
it will survive forever as abstract arts
so I might build a glass dome over it or
something
I don't know or I might just destroy it
I heard skeleton
I need to remove all the water and signs
and stuff to let my game won't - lake is
bad from the band chat was that a pink
sheep now I got to check the video later
I haven't seen a pink sheep yet
okay so one thing that'll do kill the
dogs
if you can't yeah I don't feel as bad
killing them anymore because they've
caused me quite a bit of trouble yes so
I think one of the most requested things
I've been getting is that I finish this
minecart system and I finally got around
to doing it today works pretty good so
I'm going to show you guys how it works
basically we got bled is it bla bla yeah
booster the door booster and it sends
this card around cart stops and momentum
gets reset the other cart hits that so
it's momentum gets reset so they want to
overload and then this car goes around
and the stack of mine carts goes over
here
the PEZ dispenser and this cart sends
one out they get boosted along here they
get boost it again here
and then they go to the hot and cold a
minecart extension which makes gives the
option of having flaming mine carts if
you want mmm so yeah let's get this
going that's probably enough so I was
kind of hesitant to actually make this
thing because apparently it has quite a
bit of flaws as you shall soon see I
think right now I'm just loading them up
here and yeah I killed those dogs
because they were getting in the way of
the mine carts which is causing them to
stall oh yeah these guys make way too
much noise in there so it was a real
challenge get them to make it all the
way around not an easy thing to do they
work pretty good like it's easy to get
around these corners are really tricky
though I don't like that let's get off
it's easy they go back down
cool and mmm
where to begin so yeah you can stop it
at any time by closing this door or if
you wanted you could hook up some
redstone clocks to it to regulate the
speed to slow it down if you want and it
just keeps going around and around I
don't know what the deal is with this
lever there were just cobblestone below
and I removed the cobblestone and now
the lever is here must be a new glitch
in the game and you'll notice these
minecarts make it back just in time as
the next minecart approaches there's a
little bit of gap there goes around so
try switch a hot cold yep
seems to work but the problems what are
the problems well if you leave the world
actually I'm going to leave the world
and this is proof that I don't go off in
other worlds to test things out they all
need to be converted still just the LP
world when I play in
and that is the flaw this is why I
wasn't excited to finish building this
because one of the guys I built it told
me that they freeze if you walk far away
from the minecarts and apparently they
also freeze if you leave the game so
kind of a major issue because the whole
point of this is to speed things up it's
supposed to be a convenience thing so I
can get around faster it's kind of
pointless if I have to get them going
every single time and also worry about
getting in their way if anything lands
on the track the minecarts are going to
stop if I have to destroy the minecarts
if they land in this stair area I can't
pick them up which is [ __ ] so I
actually have to destroy a log to pick
up the minecarts if I have to destroy
them
so just full of problems although it is
very cool I think
but yeah the negative kind of defeats
the pros so that's why I like eats Road
by the way because the eats road is
constantly boosted so even if you leave
the world they'll keep the boats will
keep going because they're always in a
booster minecarts they stop because they
only have boosted in the one spot or
whatever and then
then their velocity gets set to zero if
you leave the world or go out a range so
yeah but I'm not going to do a eats fro
thing either because I don't have a
space and it's probably going to be
complicated
also these mine carts are making my Dane
leg more so and it's not just because of
the fire so I probably will get rid of
it but I'm going to leave this all set
up here in case you guys want to play
around with it and instead I'm just
going to set up simple water trenches I
think and take out the logs and put
water streams all going in the same
direction and will be slightly faster
than walking still and a lot simpler
then hooking up one of these things and
yeah there's a creeper
so I decided against doing the tree farm
like I would said I was going to do it
well last episode instead I'm going to
set up something out here to the right
there's going to be hello
it's going to be a tree farm to the
right and then to the left there's going
to be a taxes farm an automated cactus
farm and then up there I might set up
the wheat farm with the eats road going
around or something I don't know we'll
see
but um it's time to go to the cannons
because this is a special episode and so
we're going to have a firework display
and here we are I love the way these
things look all the different colors
together pretty cool so I went ahead and
set them all up I think so all we got to
do is load them and then we're ready to
fire and so we're going to go through
them all and load them quickly and then
we'll we'll probably be nighttime about
towards the end of this and yeah again
if I made any mistakes just let me know
and I'll fix up and some of them have
lava in now and some don'ts the ones
that don't can't handle the lava because
they're made out of cloth or whatever
but it's going to be good this way
because we'll have a nice mixture of the
flashing white ones and the flaming ones
oh yeah and also I forgot to give a
shout-out to brainy beast that guys
helped me out a bit
and I'm sure I forgot to give shoutouts
to a few people so sorry about that and
what to talk about yeah I don't like the
new water the strong currents because I
don't know if they really make you go
any faster and they don't seem to
transport items any faster I don't think
it has any effect on the heats Road does
it make it any faster
so all it really is is a annoyance of no
no benefits that I can see so I hope
they change it back to the way it was
I'm not quite sure why they do some of
the things they do
I guess I know one other thing I could
talk about I guess many of you suggest
that I use mods and I don't really want
to use mods because I'm really happy
with the way the game is as is you know
I have a lot of fun playing the game the
way it is so I don't really want to
change that unless I get bored with the
game then I'll probably check out some
mods but on a totally unrelated note I
started programming my own mod this game
that I think might be pretty cool quite
get around to putting some time into it
it's actually not a mod it's going to be
a level generator minecraft has a really
cool level generation but at the same
time I find it if you know it's always
the same the levels are all generated
the same way and it gets a little bit
boring after a while because you know
all the rules so I think it might be fun
to make a level generator that's a
generates oddball level sets it still
look good
so that's I'm going to attempt to do
I've already started it I got to the
chunk saving and loading setup now now I
just need to start working on that
generating and if I make anything cool
with it
I'll release the program it's going to
be written in c-sharp and free the
download of course and yeah but it's not
going to affect anything with the LV
because I still plan on doing the LP mod
free it's just kind of a fun little side
project I want to try because I know you
guys think I'm a purist in video games
that's not true I actually pretty much
hacked every single game I've played
since I've was 13 so mine crafts the
first name I haven't made any programs
for and that's going to change now
probably I actually have a lot of
experience making editors and X and all
kinds of things for games
and if I do get it to the point where I
start making cool things I'll probably
show tech demos on my channel before I
release it so you guys can give me your
feedback on some of the things that you
want to point out about it almost done
yet almost done I don't want to skip any
of the names but yeah my commentaries
are pretty dry right about now oh so I'm
going to say it ahead of time thanks to
everyone that's donated very much
appreciated I say that a lot and I mean
it it definitely makes making videos
more fun at you hate pool and if you're
wondering how the I know that guy if
you're wondering how the Adsense is
working out for me I'm making about five
to ten bucks a day from having ads in my
videos which isn't a whole lot but it's
a nice little perk because it doesn't
really take any efforts
is this a pain to set up but now that
it's set up it's pretty easy to make
money that way
but yeah most of the money is coming
from donations so thank you guys we are
at 39 donors and 13 1884 awesome I think
we're almost out of a darkness here so
let's get the launch going here 1
million views guys I didn't think this
would ever happen
hehehe let's watch how the animals died
you
that's cool yes I asked you guys what
you liked better faster slow of course
you all made inappropriate jokes about
that but we went with a fast launch this
time I didn't change a pattern because
you didn't really have the time and
didn't have the redstone to mess around
with it still oh yeah so that's about it
guys I wanted to build the 360 cannon in
the nether this episode but this is a
running way too long I'm probably going
to have to dedicate at least one whole
episode to doing that and I'll have to
do some groundwork ahead of time to
speed things up but we'll probably will
try really hard to do that before the
next special okay so thank you everyone
and I'll see you later oh yeah I forgot
to mention this guy's but I'm going to
put up a new update for my world for you
to download in the video description so
if you want to check it out go ahead
it's got what I've done with the mobs
since the minutes but yeah once again
the mob systems not done I just haven't
gotten around to it and I'll finish it
up later okay
Oh spaz it's been so long since I've
last visited you
I think it's been 25 episodes now since
you've passed I would have came back
sooner but not all my viewers like tea
but you know what I think I think
everybody misses you a lot right now and
wishes you have hadn't left us you know
the world's just not the same without
you you've inspired so many people and
touch so many lives and I don't think
things will ever be the same without you
what the heck oh you sleep
you