hello everyone this is etho today is a
very good day for me in Minecraft and
I'm sure you know why if you've heard
the title today is my 20000 subscribers
special yeah unbelievable amazing thank
you guys thank you very much never
thought I'd come this far I wasn't going
to have a 20,000 subscriber special
originally because I didn't really know
how I didn't have any ideas of what I
could do with it
but I think I figured out how we can
celebrate it I'm going for a ride on the
eats Road yeah so very happy with you
guys thank you keep telling your friends
about my channel growing quickly I
actually gained 5,000 subscribers in
like a month which is crazy I just had
my other special but I actually have
something pretty cool plan for this
episode make sure you keep watching
yeah Mabel just right back I've kind of
decided what I'm doing with my new base
I found the location and I've started
figuring out some designs so I'm going
to show you those this episode it's
actually really cool I think you guys
are going to like this a lot
but don't worry I'm not going to abandon
this base here I will still use it the
new ones a little bit a little ways away
but it's not too far it's about a
thousand or so blocks away but yeah I
still plan on finishing this area it
would drive me crazy if I never did but
I will be working on the new base a bit
too so let's check out my new design
this thing is pretty cool in my opinion
what is it well this is just a prototype
that's why it's built on a soil but I'm
calling this what was it ethos mob
processor or EMP for short this thing
this is what I plan on using in my new
base basically when mobs enter here
they'll be separated like I might just
have pigs in here I'll have a big row of
these things and one will have chickens
one lot of pigs when you'll have squids
when will have creepers you know
something like that and what this thing
does is first of all it's a holding area
so the mobs will fall from above into
this thing here and they will keep
collecting again since they fall down
hundreds and fit in that to block space
no problem and if I wanted to say
release sheep but like say I had sheep
in here and I wanted to release them I
could open this up and they would be
free to come out and roam around I also
have this lever here
only one block goes down so say there
was sheep in there again I could hit
them but they wouldn't be able to walk
out and I could collect their wool doing
that also if there's say creepers or
whatever in there I could hit them and
they won't be able to see me because the
block is in their face that's cool I got
these last blocks here just so that you
can see what's in the chamber from an
angle like this from a distance and
these two are glass blocks as well so
you can see what's inside
right so let's get to the cool part if
this is closed you also have this lever
here which is a crusher it'll kill
whatever is in it whether it be chickens
or squid creepers you know that type of
thing
box will come in crush them I tried out
myself it worked
crushed me no problem and then when they
died the items will just be sitting here
so how can I demonstrate this let's
pretend this is closed mobs will die the
items will drop kind of like that when
you open this they'll pop out and then
you can pick up the items from the
individually separated mobs I'll be
separating them using what I've learned
from the space here so this lever here
opens up the floor and below is lava so
this is useful say I didn't want
chickens in my world if I want to get
rid of all the chickens
and I had this cloak no if I had this
clothes the chickens would just gently
float down fall in lava and die and that
would allow other mobs to take their
place so that's cool
say there's a bunch of items on here
that I didn't want I could just open
this up they fall in the lava and that's
all good umm yeah that seems this really
cool so also say I had chickens in here
actually let's let's just go look at the
back now maybe I'll skip the day just
because it's kind of dark we don't have
any nasty surprises
so in my new base I plan on separating
chickens and flour on separating pigs
sheep and cows will probably be together
because I don't know how to separate
them wolves will be there in their own
place and squids will have their own
place slimes I'll have a separate one
for creepers one for zombies one for
skeletons one for spiders and basically
every mob ah yeah around the back here
this is what it looks like I may make a
tutorial for this later but at the
moment it's untested I have no idea if
it even works but I'm pretty sure it
does in the back you also have master
controls so that activates the pressure
this lever here this one activates the
barrier to hold them in and this one
here is kind of cool it releases water
why would I want water you asked this
will actually do many things so say the
idea behind these master controls is if
I wanted to link a bunch of these units
together and have like a central
computer type then controlling all of
them I would say hook all the crusher
wires together all the barrier wires
together and all the water ones together
and have three different master wires
and if I was to have it automatically
kill all the mobs
in all the units i would activate well
first the barrier would be activated
the crusher will kill them barrier would
be deactivated and then the pressure
would be deactivated and then there'll
be a bunch of items here and then the
central computer or processor or
whatever will activate the water if I
want and that will cause items to flow
out through a main stream that all these
units are connected to and by doing this
I will be able to have a central
collection area which is kind of what I
which is what I have with my original
storage room so this is kind of the best
of all worlds because I will have the
mobs individually separated into all
these units so if I only want string
whatever I would just walk up to the
unit collect string and I can ignore all
the other drops and walk away but from a
distance I'll have a central computer or
whatever to activate it all the items
will merge together flow down a stream
towards me and I'll be able to collect
all the passive mob drops all the
hostile mobs and stuff like that what
else does the water do
I'll say we had the barrier closed water
was on mobs fall in from here and right
now we're stuck within the barrier so if
it was like this since the water is
flowing down the mobs wouldn't be able
to swim up I don't think again untested
I hope I'm right
and that will mean they will drown as
they fall in so I can automatically kill
them with this as well by drowning them
which is cool of course that doesn't
work for all them like squids that won't
work but for most moms it will I will
probably have to customize these EMP
units for certain moms like spiders for
example another thing if I wanted the
drops to automatically or the mops be
automatically killed by drowning and all
their items to automatically go to a
collection point I could just have that
one down so say there's a creeper in
there he won't be able to get out you'll
die but his drops will still be able to
flow to the mainstream
okay I just rewatched the some of the
video I've got record so far I realize I
said punch the sheep to get their wool
of course I'm thinking the past terms I
would use shears to get their wool now
also since I have a holding area I could
it was like this I could die the sheep
I could also milk cows in this holding
area wolves I could hold and then tame
if I want so yeah so many options with
this EMP unit and I'm really happy with
it I got chests here for storage so I
would just go pick up the items whether
I manually kill the mobs or if it's
automatically done using my master
controls it's up to me and then I can
pick them up quickly storm here that's
good
with my lava killing thing I have a sign
above so even if I have to beat the
water I don't have to worry about it
wrecking the lava it'll just flow on top
of the sign on there also looks kind of
cool having the water what else what
else I better check that I have that
closed well I had a good night checked
yeah so the mobs will come in from the
top
optionally I can have water here this X
is a water break if I choose
so if I have water there it's possible
to prevent moths from taking damage or
at least too much damage if I was if
this was for chickens oh I would just
have air because it'll just float down
on their own
another option is I could put lava here
and say a pig fell down he would get
cooked automatically and he would be
held in place by the barrier and then I
would have cooked pork chops sitting
here same with Bobby mobs say say I
wanted to automatically kill creepers
and get their gunpowder I could have
that down but what like I said one way I
can do it is with the downward water
stream another option would be to not
use water but instead have lava here the
mobs would fall through the lava be set
on fire the lab is high enough that they
won't be able to jump back into it so
they'll just burn in here and their
drops will fall here so that's another
way of automatically okay whole dad
never did that before I'm scared
we'll be back after these technical
difficulties whoo that was close don't
worry guys I'm all right yeah
so back to my rambling ah so I could
have water I could have lava I could use
Pistons again to switch between having
lava or water or air you know there's so
many so many different ways of doing
this I could also kill mobs using fall
damage yeah good stuff good stuff
one thing I played around when I was
building this one thing I played around
with it while building this is I also
had a lever here originally and that
would activate just the bottom one so
mat-based
both of them and this one activates just
the top one but I don't think I would
really need that for anything so I don't
really need that option unless you can
think of something that would be useful
for other cool things this will fit in
the wiring is five wide so you could
repeat these EMP units every six blocks
basically so one two three four five I
don't have another soil block here then
it would be glass pressure glass soil
soil glass pressure glass oil so I'll
make that six blocks so you can build
them pretty close together and it'll
kind of look like a wall when it's when
they're all next to each other which is
cool as well
I think that's everything I wanted to
say about this
like I said Toro will come later
once I actually test it unfortunately I
don't use single player commands or
anything like that so testing stuff like
this can be challenging for me until I
actually have it built in working
another nice thing these wires are
neatly spaced one block apart so it's
easy to connect to them and it looks
decent it'll look better if you use
different blocks and soil I plan on
having glowstone on this one and behind
these two glass ones I might make the
pressure out of glowstone and maybe the
rest of it sandstone or wood or
something but yeah let's go see my let's
go see location of where I've decided to
build my new base here we are guys I'm
at the location of my future base I
think you're going to be quite surprised
when you see what's around me I don't
think you would have expected I would
choose a location like this all right
you ready to see it here we go
yeah pretty much completely different
from my old base I'm there's a few
islands around here small islands low
islands and it's a huge frozen over
ocean all around me and I marked the
central location of my base this is it
why did I choose this area there's
actually quite a few reasons so maybe
I'll I'll say a few of them
first of all I've always wanted to make
a base or building or something in a
snowy biome because I've never
experienced that in Minecraft before
when we had snowy worlds before in alpha
version or whatever whenever I would
generate one I would quickly delete it
because I was new to the game and I
didn't really know how to deal with the
snow and I like green grass so this is
going to be new for me I'm looking
forward to it since this is a snowy
biome I have new block types that I've
always wanted to I can make ice anytime
I want by placing still water and having
it freeze so that's awesome that will be
very useful for making my item streams
because items flow very quickly on ice
and there's actually a few other tricks
you can do with ice another reason I
chose this location not a lot of people
build in snowy biomes so it'd be a
little bit different be bit unique I
actually plan on building using ice
blocks a little bit so be kind of like
an ice fortress but not entirely out ice
just because I don't think I could do
that
sensors islands around there's out also
grass nearby so I can get grass to my
passive mob spawning pads pretty quickly
and there's not much land around hostile
mobs don't spawn on ice neither do
passive ones so I don't have to place
many torches there's an ocean here so
I like having oceans around even though
it's covered by ice having the ocean
makes it so there's slightly less cave
systems I believe because the top you
know ow 1 to 16 blocks are going to be
ocean so there won't be any caves in
that area hmm what else what else
there's clay here guys look there's clay
I might harvest it though I don't know
one thing I'm going to have to do is
level these islands probably or at least
some of them won't take too long pretty
because they're pretty low um oh yeah
the main reason why I chose this
location if you look at the coordinates
it's kind of around a thousand 24x and
about 512 Zed so that means this block
here is in one region this one here is
in another region so it's on another one
and this is another one there's I'm
standing at the cross-section of four
different regions regions are 512 blocks
by 512 blocks so they're huge so to be
at the very cross-section of four of
them is a very rare there's not many of
them around you have to travel 512
blocks each one one problem I had with
my old passive and hostile mob systems
is there's I don't fits a glitch in the
game or just some built-in code to
prevent mobs from spawning if you kill
too many of them but every now and then
my passive mob farm which is shut down
completely same with my hostile one but
having my spawning pads in four
different regions will prevent that from
happening
I'm also far enough away from anything
I've built that it won't interfere with
my new base and yet I'm not so far away
that I can't return to them so that's
good and yeah it's going to be fun guys
the very first thing I plan on building
is those EMP units I'll probably I don't
know how many I'll need they'll probably
be at least ten of them arranged somehow
I'll build them before my spawning pads
and that's the plan guys
that's the future of ethos lab ah yeah
so many ideas I tried moving those ice
blocks with pistons it's kind of kind of
strange guess I'll be building using ice
but not completely I like I like tail
ice looks kind of like glass but kind of
unique and that's it for the special
guys I hope you enjoyed it the cool
thing I was talking about was the EMP
unit
there's no spaz thing today just because
I don't know I don't have any ideas for
that but hopefully you enjoyed this and
I will see you again next time thanks
for watching and for subscribing and
liking and all that other stuff for
being cool viewers leaving comments
keeping me entertained
I thank you