hey everyone welcome back to ethos lamp
they've got a great episode plan for you
today first thing we're gonna do is
we're gonna look at heart
EMP units a little closer because when
we finished the mob sorting last time we
didn't really get a time to look at them
we just ended the episode there so maybe
we'll look at some of the features again
quickly and also later we're gonna start
working on the spider spawning pads up
above if we can so let's begin first of
all they're working great I'm getting so
much stuff from them pretty much have
infinite food infinite leather making
tons of love there are more lately it's
good and my favorite thing is the wool
getting lots lots of wool so this is uh
turning up pretty good for me
can't complain I'm even getting a lot of
ground wool which otherwise would be
insanely hard to collect lots of black
wool even the hard time a pink sheep
will fall but it's very rare so that's
working great some of the features I've
added two more levers up here this one
controls water break
see water appears it over there
otherwise it just fall to their death so
one way of killing them is gravity just
having them fall to their death if you
want them to collect you need your water
break set there and then they'll end up
in here then you got your crusher
and gamma we need more we need more
people to help us with our demonstration
here Ariel get the floor and have them
straight fall into lava if you want you
leave that open and that way no items
collect if this is open so they want to
play your game that's a good feature of
course you got these openings can
totally free the animals if you have
them both open and the water break on
but I'd only do that
you got your drowners if you have that
on you don't really need the water break
on although it doesn't matter and you
can have the items fall over there or if
you want them to go to the main
collection stream then you just open the
bottom door here and the items will flow
out
just like that - this whole
automatically on their own let's go
check that out by the way I added
torches in here temporarily just to
improve the lighting conditions
apparently it doesn't seem to melt the
ice below just good but if I place like
a torch around here it would so I got to
be careful that's working good working
dude working great I should say yeah
that's interesting yeah you can combine
this stuff in lots of different ways and
then weird stuff will happen then she'll
probably rewire this so this floor
doesn't open if that door is closed
sound really like that
big stuff is much the same oh yeah I
forgot we got the lab so can have them
fall through lava like that if you have
the water break on the fall through
water first then lava but the water will
slow down their their fall so then they
will just burn here a little bit longer
if you want a show I guess or if you
enjoy that kind of thing torturing
animals and that works good for you umm
what else yeah the pigs the lava if we
have the lava above here then you get
the roasted pork chops because they fall
through the lava but they died from
gravity pretty much instantly but since
they're on fire they still drop roasted
pork chops cooked pork chops I should
say just like that if we get rid of this
now the lab is gone we get to uncooked
pork chops just like that that's good
because wolves need uncooked pork chops
you have to you can't feed them the
cooked ones so there is some point to
that and what else what else everything
else works much the same the pressure is
different for the pigs because their
border
seems to work perfectly though pretty
much Jeremy if I said this but this
lever here is hooked up to anything it's
just to bounce up the look and what else
what else I really liked how it looks in
here right now
it's pretty cool very technical looking
you might be wondering where the
chickens are what I'm doing right now is
I have my plan is to hook this lever up
to what go up to the top here to
something I have set up right now
because we don't need a water break for
chickens so I'm gonna have the wire go
up to this thing here which is killing
them a lot quicker than if they were to
follow the stream all the way here then
they slowly float down to the bottom
like that so having that chilling thing
up there for them just greatly speeds up
the time it takes to kill them and if
you do that then you get two sheep and
cows and pigs a lot faster oh yeah that
drowner for the pigs what I might do is
I might replace
this snow block here with the fence that
way when the water comes down items will
be able to flow with the water but the
pigs won't be able to fit between the
fence and the glass like they are right
now okay what else just eating up all my
episode of time today focusing on this
but it's important yeah okay yeah the
chickens if we want to collect chickens
in here then we have the pig set to
dying and the sheep and cows at dying
and eventually this will fill up with
chickens because they're the only ones
that aren't being killed and if you do
that then they'll lay eggs in here so
this doubles as an egg farm and if we
want well I'll show you the pressure
seems okay get all the same options you
got the lappa and you have the water and
you have opening blow doors open
if you want to free them for some reason
if you have the drowner sets the
chickens will float down and they'll
stay in the water like up at the top of
the water in the lay eggs eggs will fall
down into this water stream and then
they'll float to the main collection
area so you can have an auto egg farm as
well you can see there's a chicken stuck
there so he won't die there the lay eggs
eggs will fall down into the water go to
the main stream right okay
so I think I covered everything right
now it looks kind of ugly
I plan on covering this all up
everything directly above these levers
here so you won't see this weird stuff
and I'll try to make all this look a lot
better when it's done but first we want
to figure out exactly how we're gonna do
this unfortunately we don't have any
wolves I'm very disappointed about that
you know wolves
so that's too bad what happened is
before I even started building all this
stuff I that was one of the things I
checked for to make sure wolves would
spawn in this area it's just to day here
sleeping on the clay yeah I checked for
wolves originally and I did see them
what happened was I saw them let's see
opposite side over here that island we
blew up I saw them spawning on there ah
come on load you chunks load so directly
this is where the island started I saw
wolves spawning here right here so less
then Oh probably 20 blocks away or so 30
blocks so that's kind of a disappointing
excuse me I got to stop gonna cough
really bad here
yeah so if I ever seems like I'm
stumbling with my words part of it's
probably because I'm an idiot
and I don't know how to speak the other
part time probably got something in my
throat because I'm still getting over
that cold I had and it feels like I got
junk in my lungs still anyway yeah so
about 20 30 blocks away from here we
could have had wolf spawning if the
spawning pads just ended out that far
unfortunately they don't there are some
advantages to this so it's down here
so since wolves aren't spawning that
means we get more cows more sheep more
pigs more chickens a lot quicker because
we don't do that we don't have wolves to
deal with so we get other mobs instead
and this is good because wolves don't
drop anything so we don't necessarily
want them spawning if they're not
providing anything so that's kind of
good that they don't spawn here kind of
sucks though because you know I got this
all set up for them I wanted to show it
in action and it's not happening what we
could do you know that useless future we
have on our passive spawning pants this
shut to shut them down at all I don't
want to go up there again we can shut
off the passive spawning pads and we can
have a second passive spawning pad if we
want or a third or a fourth as long as
we're able to shut them off we can have
more so that useless feature is starting
to have some potential now in my eyes so
for example we could build
it doesn't even have to be spawning pads
it could just be a nice park area a
patch of grass over here that we can
flood with water to and we could switch
between having them spawn here or spawn
up there or spawn it both whatever you
know and that way we could get wolves
over here because I'm sue me this
building is gonna extend this far so
that's one possibility
oh I got a cough again oh yeah I'm gonna
pause here alright so I thought I'd show
the chicken farm egg farm in action here
we got about no probably twelve chickens
or so in there right now and they're
laying eggs chicken lays an egg every
five minutes and we have our Pig set to
dying and our cows and sheep set to
dying so if if they spawn on the
spawning pads they'll die and they'll
keep dying until eventually chickens
spawn and when chickens spawn they'll go
to this tube and slowly we keep getting
more and more chickens and fewer and
fewer of the other moms right now we
only have three mobs up on our spawning
pads so they're greatly slowed down
right now as we reach the passive mob
limit because we have all these chickens
here normally there's about ten to
fifteen mobs on our spawning pads
having a spawning pads that are 300
blocks in size seem to are not spawning
pets but spawning systems that are 300
blocks in size for passive mobs seems to
work really well it seems to keep up
pretty good at the rate I'm killing them
yeah so eventually we'll have all
chickens and no other mobs will be
spawning up there and we'll have about
15 chickens in here or so and that
averages out to an egg every 20 seconds
or so and they float on top of the water
if we have the stream running eggs show
up here at our main collection area just
got 9 eggs if we don't want them to show
up there we close this up we have to
have this top one up like that because
otherwise it's possible for the eggs to
get stuck on the piston there another
option would be to have the chickens oh
yeah we don't have a winery
nevermind or we can just have them down
here and having lay eggs down here that
works too yeah so that's how we hipped
and have an egg farm and there's no way
of auto killing the chickens to get
feathers I don't know if I really am
gonna add that feature I suppose it
would be good if I could but I don't
know Oh what because a chicken's stuck
there hmm work on fixing that
yeah I got some key thing to do with the
system yet anyway
alright so most of the time I'm gonna
have this set so let the chickens just
die up at the top there at that lab a
switch because we don't really need them
for anything they're kind of kind of
like wolves they're pretty much useless
for their drops anyway we don't need
feathers from them really because
feathers are one of the mostly useless
items in the game and also we're gonna
get tons of feathers from zombies when
we set up bar our hostile spawning
system on this side so the only thing we
really need from chickens is eggs
every once in a while maybe so we want
to get rid of them as quick as possible
at the top there
pigs probably have it this setting most
of time I'll have the floor open if I
don't want the extra leg those 30 or 40
pork chops will cause me and then we
have these guys most of time I'll just
have them falling to their death so I
can collect the wall on that but if we
want to we want to man it out we want to
die them
aerial except my shears got my I got the
sword
there's a few different ways we can that
die them this first way is pretty funny
and I think you guys are gonna like this
we open up our top and they just come
flying out and then we can shear them
kill them doesn't happen every time but
a lot of the times
that bunch will fly out which is kind of
nice you don't want them all flying out
probably
oops ah ding so you can deal with a few
at a time doing it that way
which is nice another way of doing it is
just to leave it open
oops and then try them through this
opening
well that's very hard to do you have to
hold down the right click and move your
mouse around and you'll get a few
another thing you can do is just let
them all free roam that's a kind of hard
to deal with them when they're all out
because they like to wander places they
shouldn't go like this guys doing
and then you might not catch them of
course this will be more closed off
later when I gets lab more finished
oh look there's one more J but the best
way I found of dealing with them and
simply get rid of these guys I have this
open have this thing empty just deal
with them one at a time if you can you
gotta be fast though and have your die
your shears and your sword equipped Jeep
here that's too slow there we go just
like that is the best way I found of
doing it quickly with the least amount
of stress of chasing them down and stuff
get some black this works pretty good
one more come on if you share them you
get more wool it's another nice thing
save only getting one gets between two
and four fatale Falls just kill it
um excuse me I was maybe thinking of
raising that water break so you can kill
them simply by punching them instead of
using a sword
I don't know fail if I do that it
probably won't work 100% anyway like
some you might have to punch twice or
three times
um you know I never tried milking them
maybe I'm gonna let I'm gonna let some
Morra show up here and then Mel tried
Mill Club
all right here we go we're gonna try see
if we can milk the cows when they're all
grouped together like this at the top
holding rights mostly seems to try every
so often the bucket goes like that it's
not very effective actually pressing the
button pressing right click doesn't seem
to work maybe you've tried in the water
on much more effective still not any
milk though
it's it's going a lot more often okay
oops sorry guys let's try with the
bottom open doesn't seem to be
activating from water it can't seem to
do it with the bottom glass block down
of course you can probably do it when
they're free-roaming that's much better
there's supposed to be a trick to it
come on
want some milk yes this is one part of
the game I've never really figured out
is how to get milk oh I had some I think
I just had some more yeah Ariel why am I
getting it now you got a milk the butter
are you kidding me
you have to milk the button why not why
it doesn't work if you click on the pink
thing you gotta milk the button it works
100% okay very strange
okay very interesting design choice by
knotch anyway I guess we're gonna end
the episode here
that's the MP units I didn't get to the
spider spawning in this episode but
we'll probably focus the whole next
episode on that and I'm gonna work out
some designs for it a little bit and
they'll be a little bit challenging
because if nobody's really built any
spider only spawning systems yet like
dedicated this only spider spawning I
know the one at chocolate island there
you have the option but it's not really
designed only for spiders so it's gonna
be difference this new system I'm
building here and I got nothing to
really work off of or nothing that's
caught my eye anyway so that's what
we'll be doing next time thank you for
watching today hope you found this
interesting even though we didn't really
do much
it's a talky anyway take care thanks for
watching bye bye yada yada yada