come on oh hello everyone this is
etho thank you for joining me once again
today as we play some minecraft and
today is a special episode as I'm sure
you're probably well aware already this
is my 30,000 subscribers special as well
as the 5 million view special and 1
million channel news special so three
landmarks all at once which is pretty
cool
and I want to say thank you to everybody
that watches my videos leaves likes and
comments and suggestions all that cool
stuff thank you everybody
you helped to make my channel grow and
you made it fun for me which is which is
really good so today why are we here for
all my new viewers what we used to do on
our specials is we come up here and we
would launch all these cannons and we'd
have like a little firework show to
celebrate the special but unfortunately
the 1.6 patch came along and now none of
these cannons worked the way they are
supposed to so we need to fix them I
keep saying I'm gonna fix them and it
just you know just hasn't happened yet
so today I think I should focus the
episode on reviving our special
celebration as one stubborn chicken so
hopefully we can get them working yeah
yeah cuz I missed that firework show
what it's that there's something over
there oh it's a creeper hello oh oh it's
spaz jr. hi spaz jr. how you doing buddy
this guy is the shyest creeper you'll
ever meet
you know most creepers when you see them
they'll you know they're shy but they
will try to attack you not spaz jr. he's
he won't come out at all it's okay buddy
I'm not gonna hurt you I'm not a
stranger I know your father I tell you
what Sebastian or if you come out I'll
give you candy you want some candy I
don't think it's gonna come out oh I
know what I can do there we go hey buddy
it's okay not gonna hurt you no no no no
no don't do that don't do that you know
it's bad Junior I think one way you'll
feel more comfortable around me
is if you tell me a little bit about
yourself okay how about you tell me what
you want to be when you grow up an
astronaut you want to be an astronaut
wow that is that's quite the dream spaz
jr. I bet you a lot of people made fun
of you when you said that because that
is a stupid idea very few people
actually become astronauts and they're
humans the ones that do you know you're
a creeper you have no arms you can't
perform the tasks you would need to in
space for the mission you know and at
the first sign of trouble you would
probably just explode and blow up the
spacecraft so I can understand why
people made fun of you when you told
them that
but don't you worry spaz jr. I can make
dreams come true would you like to
become an astronaut today I can make it
happen okay come with me
alright spaz you ready you're about to
become the first creeper astronaut here
not to worry I know you're probably a
little bit scared but you don't have to
worry this is all NASA proved so nothing
should go wrong should be perfectly safe
I'll give you a little rundown of how
this is gonna work our launch buttons
over here they'll switch the redstone
torch it will power the Redstone wiring
which will activate these two torches on
the side which should power the redstone
wire below now sure those aren't
necessary calm down making some
last-minute adjustments here but this
has all been tested before spaz jr.
there's nothing to worry about there we
go so we should be ready here engines
are ready you're ready I'm ready let's
do this so we'll do a t-minus countdown
t-minus three two one blast-off well
guys I don't think spaz jr. made it to
space after all he only flew about 10
blocks up so he wasn't even close he's a
trooper though he tried oh how he tried
so that's kind of a problem all my
vertical cannons are gonna have I sense
the 1.6 patch he just can't really get
much height out of the TNT blast
is the problem so even I played around
us that this is a vertical cannon design
I tried and it works pretty good all for
T and T in it end up where this water is
so it's got a lot of power packed into
one spot close to the missile and yet
you know you still don't get very much
height with it
so check it out those it's good it's
nice but really you know what guys we've
seen the cannons we need something
different because for one thing I don't
feel like fixing all of these so I'm not
going to and the other main problem I
had with these cannons besides them
taking a long time to build and then
being very repetitive I they used a lot
of redstone and I kind of want to save
my redstone for other projects so we're
gonna start a new project for our
specials and that's what we're gonna
focus on this episode we're gonna be
starting a Rube Goldberg machine I hope
I said that right a Rube Goldberg
machine in Minecraft is basically just a
big set of chain reactions that looks
very cool when it's all done so the plan
by the way I'll link the original Rube
Goldberg machine in the video
description as well I'm gonna link a
music video I really like with a
real-life example of one in the video
description as well it's really cool but
yeah the way this is gonna work
everybody that's donated I'm going to
dedicate a piece of the Rube Goldberg
machine to them I gotta find a short way
of saying that I hate saying that name
every time
RGB rude gold burg yeah I'm gonna call
it an RGB from now on just because it's
easy
so everybody that donates gonna get a
piece of the RGB more people that donate
the more epic it's gonna be when we set
it off and everybody's gonna enjoy it
all the viewers so that's the plan the
reason I'm doing this is because I'm
still getting donations every so often
from people and some of them are asking
you know but my foots Owens own name on
a cannon for me please and it's making
me feel bad because we're not doing the
cannon thing anymore so I want some
other new way of showing my thanks to
everybody that donated and I really
appreciate all the donations I've gotten
and continue to get keep in mind I am a
YouTube partner now so I am making money
from you guys either way now just by you
viewing my videos so while I still
appreciate donations they're not you
know they're not necessary unless you
really want to I'll be very happy if you
do of course but I am making a fair bit
of money doing Minecraft videos now so
I'm happy about that and it's because of
you guys so thank you anyway we are
going to look for a location for our RGB
machine and then we will start building
it today hopefully and maybe I doubt
we'll finish it today probably won't
even come close to finishing it but
we'll we'll start it that way I'll be
encouraged to work on it okay so I'm
gonna look for a location and we will be
back okay I think I found a pretty good
location over here are all right
vertical cannons are just over there you
can barely see them from here
and we have this big flat area over here
this was kind of a wasteland in my
opinion I wasn't gonna build anything
here but you know it's pretty good flat
land for projects like this and we have
lots of hills around to which we might
make use of so I think all this area
here is pretty
for this thing and our location is
pretty far away from chocolate islands
so should be a good spot and that's the
360 cannon just over there so yeah I
think I want to start a start up base
camp here and maybe start building it a
little bit and then I'll see you guys
again then so I've started to get
settled down here you've got a little
base camp set up here and I have been
working on the very first part of the
RGB machine this is one of the coolest
sand cannons I've ever built so whoever
gets this piece is going to be one lucky
bugger because I'm having a huge trouble
getting it to work well because the sand
keeps getting launched differently every
time so it's hard to it's hard to figure
out where the sands gonna end up after
you shoot it I tried to build a net up
there to catch it yeah ah I'm talking
but it's not working so well oh cool
alright that's the first time it worked
now if you do the same shot guess what
probably totally miss it so to build
this RGB machine I need to do a lot of
world backed ups and figure out exactly
how I want to build each piece and then
back up the work like loader back up and
actually put it into the world okay it's
working significantly better right now
first time I shot it totally missed the
net somehow and I have to have a net
because if I don't the sand gets blown
way up in the sky and it actually gets
destroyed in the sky because apparently
there's a time limit on how far or how
long sand can fly for and I once the
sand passes that time limit it just
turns into a block like this in midair
instead of being a moving in to D block
or whatever try it again okay so that
net may just worked after all
of course I don't have to use all that
TNT probably be easier to control if I
don't this is a very cool sand cannon
I'm very happy with this design it's set
at 40 ticks I killed you already get
lost and this is the sand block is
offset by one from the center of this
pool and it falls two blocks that's
exactly how I have it Dale one last try
this works all using that the plan is to
make this sand then fall on either a
pressure plate or have it block off a
water stream to start the next reaction
chain reaction whatever I need to figure
out exactly where the sands gonna land
to do that see that wasn't good hmmm
okay I'll play around with it a bit more
see you soon okay I think I got this
first chain reaction figure it out here
I'm gonna have water now over here
and I've been practicing and practicing
with that sand can and I think I finally
figured out something that's fairly
accurate something I can expect to work
every time pretty much so I'm only using
three TNT now loaded in the back and
what happens is light it is the sand
block to the water blocks of water
causes the water at an update and it
realizes it can go this way instead of
this way so when it does that I can
start a new chain reaction here make the
water hit something and we can make it
keep going alright so the first piece of
the RGB machine is done it's the sand
cannon it shoots the sand block to this
water stream here this is the second
piece
we've got built so far so the sand will
land about here water will switch to the
side and it will destroy this torch when
it does that the torch will flow in the
newly created water stream to this
pressure plate here which will activate
this piston which is going to start our
third piece basically everybody that has
donated will get will each get one of
these pieces they'll have their name on
it
I'll put signs on each piece for each
donor and I'll do it kind of randomly I
know some pieces will be better than
others but you know not playing
favorites or anything okay so this third
step what I'm gonna do is when the
pressure plates above here gets
activated it powers the piston below
oops well whatever same thing and it
pressure plate gets uprooted and ends up
top there oh I've got a pretty cool idea
of what I'm going to do for this third
piece I'm gonna have woodblock pressure
plate it's gonna spiral up it's gonna be
a piston under this one piston under
here and we're just gonna keep spiraling
up a few times anyway till I feel it's
enough okay try yeah try get this going
here so that will go up and we'll have
glass block here and there
now I'm building this the wrong way I
hate breaking glass but oh well
yes I want to glass block there don't
need it there you'll see this is going
to be cool glass there like this and
then we'll have a water stream in here
which will be held by that pressure
plate there J and then next step same
thing
nope did that wrong yeah I'll come back
to this in a second
cool I got the three pieces done now
although I might have to rip out this
one I just added because it doesn't seem
to be working quite like I want it to
doesn't seem to always work is the
problem another thing I found is I have
animals wandering around here so I need
to be careful that they don't wander
onto my pressure plates that I might
have around otherwise they could set off
the whole thing so I need to be careful
about that but anyway I got two pieces
done for sure probably have to change
this one I just added in coral there's
going to be about fifty to sixty pieces
so it'll be a huge project try to get as
much done as I can before our next
special probably do most of the work on
this project off camera but I just want
to dedicate this episode to it so this
is what we got so far
got our sand cannon and our water switch
there's a torch it's going to the
pressure plate it worked that time
that's cool
sometimes it works sometimes it doesn't
that's as far as we've gotten in this
episode so fun project I hope you guys
like it keep working on it
and once again I want to say thanks to
everybody for all your support I want to
give shout outs to everybody in my
channel box like dot gam SC Joyner
static Joker I want to give a shout out
to Joker and leach as well because they
were nice they let me play on their
server a while ago for free
nice nice thing for them to do although
I don't play SMP very much at all just
because I don't like all the bugs and
light issues in it but at school they
let me play on their server whenever I
want
so thanks guys and of course for any
Beast he's helped me a lot to figuring
out how stuff works in YouTube how to
set up ad sense that kind of stuff he's
been a big help for me so thanks brandy
and of course co-star he's been a huge
help for me he's added my channel to his
a subscription or his other channels
boxes and he's been giving me some
shoutouts in his LP which has helped me
get new for new subscribers so thanks
co-star yeah sent me a really nice PM
the other day he's a nice guy
but yeah I think we're gonna end it
today I really wanted her to bed right
now and I gotta edit this video yet
tonight so hopefully you don't mind the
rough ending so that's it for me today
thank you for watching and until next
time take care