[Music]
hey everyone this is etho
uh we're just hanging out with my
original base here
i've been working at laying the tnt
charges for
the destruction of the island like we
planned
i got all the tunnels dug now and i was
laying charges
but it turns out that i did not have
enough tnt
so that's why i'm over here i've just
been working on stuff around this base
mostly just collecting resources at the
moment
i've been working on doing colored wool
and stuff
and every now and then i just come over
here and pick up
whatever gunpowder there is so that we
can make some more tnt
because at the moment i am out pretty
much
so in order to blow up that island we
need a lot more tnt i've placed about
so far and in total i expect
i'll need to place at least a thousand
to blow up
that island i actually did a
a test explosion and it turned out
really nice it's actually very cool
i think you guys are gonna like the
thing when it's all set up
it's going to be very cool explosion but
i don't know how long it's going to take
before we can
do that because getting gunpowder is
taking
quite a while it turns out
i've been collecting
different dyes and wools
i've been harvesting trees and stuff
and i still have only made about one
stack of tnt since i got here and
[Applause]
it's going to take a while so maybe work
on
a project around here today
hmm well i know one simple project
i wanted to do is replace this black
wool
block with an actual coal block this is
what i have here
coal and now that we have pistons we can
actually do that so maybe
try to find a coal block somewhere
around here
and move it over
there's some
so this might take a little while but
we'll see
how this goes it's sticky piston
stick it there that won't work
stick it there
move to one block
um let's move it one more
get it out and open
and then we want it three up
i know
so one two three four five
ouch
oh too far
i should really be using a regular
piston for this
and where's my levers
okay moved it up one
and one more
sweet
okay now to get it that way
piston there and i'm going to stick a
block in
inch it over that way
and you get the idea so 10 hours later
i'll have it in place
five hours in it's almost in place
making record time here
sweet just gotta move it two more blocks
and it's
and it's done
greatest achievement ever
there we go that took some skill
so we have coal where the coal is
sweet um
should be some more drops here
and we have oh we actually got quite a
bit from that
so make another stack of tnt
yeah about four more and then we can
head back to the ice base
so i guess i need another project here
at least
okay so i thought of
something else i can build while i wait
for
gunpowder to show up there
which i'm getting quite a bit of now
this is an idea i've had a long time
i'm calling it quick kit
it's a something you're all probably
familiar with
uh maybe you've been
out exploring a cave far away from your
base deep underground
you come across a dungeon and you decide
to take it on like a man
and you die you lose all your precious
items
you restart at your base and you have
five minutes to get the back
now a lot of times when this happens to
me
guess what you spend oh i don't know
about
two minutes or so remaking an axe
and not an axe of pick shovels
getting a bow arrows food
you know collecting all these items you
need to get to take on the dungeon again
so that you can get your stuff back
so the idea with the quick kit is you
press one button
all that stuff gets given to you
pretty much instantly get your stuff you
go take down the dungeon
without wasting all the time and losing
your items because they despawn in five
minutes
so the quick kits i decided to build it
over here
and yeah so i'm gonna haul this out
try and match it with uh these other
booths i have here
i need a different spot apparently so
i'll be back in a sec when i find a new
spot
well after looking around a bit i
realized something that the eats road is
just down here
just over here so it would be nice if i
tied
this little section to this section
here somehow make it look nice
and i could put my
quick kit somewhere around here too that
way
and and maybe i'll raise this a bit
this section here
brought some half slabs with me
and yes i am so cheap that i won't just
cover up the wood blocks
i need to get them back
there nice gradual climb up
trying to make things look good is not
my specialty unfortunately so this is
going to be
tough for me
question is do i make this go slope down
straight or do i make it curved or how
should i do it
you guys are probably sick by all this
jerky camera
motion um
i guess there's pretty high roof here
so lots of space to work with
the other problem is this is wood here
and i'm using sandstone there so i need
to kind of
merge them together some way too
and choose
hmm i gotta figure out
i'll be back
i decided i'm gonna try have a gradual
straight slope from here
three wide one two
three
matches up with this and i'll probably
have like
railing on the side made out of fences
half slab
and more sandstone
i don't know
let's see how it looks
and half slab
hmm
so we got that
i wish they had sandstone stairs that
would be cool
and
i don't know maybe i'll try wood planks
and see how that looks
you guys are probably like oh don't do
the wood planks no
worst combination ever
i need some kind of transition to the
wood planking so if i have both
you know
i don't know
and of course lighting is always a
problem for me
yeah i think i'm okay with that i might
change the wood planking though
let me know what you guys think should i
use logs or something else
maybe i'll try blend these in
have a little transition here
that's not bad
yeah i can live with that for now anyway
uh if you guys got improvements let me
know
oh another idea is to use glowstone
where these wood planks are
for light possibly
or just have glowstone chandeliers or
something i don't know
okay so we got some way of getting down
here now
um i may put the quit
kit thing over here since we have a big
solid block to work with i believe
and
i'll clean this up more later
yeah so probably i'll probably build a
quick kit here
and i may do it out of sandstone
i decide i'm going to try place it here
after all so i got it kind of marked out
a little bit
there's going to be a wall here on the
outside
it's going to be an opening here this is
where the items are going to be
that i collect right where this torch is
and inside this area
doesn't really matter how you shape this
all it is
is just going to be a bunch of
dispensers down in here
that are going to deliver the items to
me
so you can shape it however you want and
you can make it however big you want
but i'll probably have at least
at least 20 to 30 dispensers so i need a
bit of space
the more space i have the easier this is
going to be to set up
and i can do fancier wiring too if i
have more space
so see how to do this
so i need at least
a one block space from the outside wall
to run wire on and then i'll have
dispensers
here and here for sure
and probably
here here here
copy it on the other side
like that and maybe like this
see how this works
so of course another issue is the water
actually i'm going to put a pressure
plate down where the items are going to
get delivered
right here so the water doesn't spill
everywhere
but if i place water here they're going
to create
still water so
can't have that
so we need to change this a bit
i might have to make it four wide
open still water get rid of this still
water
dead zone no good
um
oh it's raining i'll play around with
this water stream a bit
i might make it four or five wide we'll
see
actually you know what i should do
[Music]
oh
you know that a lot of people don't
really think that timers for anything
but it does
actually help that tune
because i know it's time to pick up my
items then
and the whole reason i'm building around
here today is just so i can get
gunpowder
so it's important i listen for that
timer
um yeah so i'm going to work on this a
bit off camera
and then we'll try get some more done
okay so it was pretty pretty easy to fix
i just
did the same thing on this side and now
we have a perfect
water stream that doesn't take up much
space
no dead zones of course i'd take a
dispenser out but that's not really a
problem because
now i can use this space here
so i don't really lose anything by doing
that
and same with over here
spencer okay
so how many do we have so far there's
going to be multiple layers probably
you got 5 11 down
so that's that's pretty good
try to get at least 22 or something
so then they'll be wiring all the way
around
um
doesn't matter that i'm using dirt here
you won't be able to
see this dirt that is a problem
put that there temporarily oh that's
going to be a problem too
darn
hmm
might have to move that uh five o'clock
over here
oof like
well anyway it goes around
uh i do have buttons good
and
i might have a button here
press it activates all the dispensers
assuming
i can connect this
the reason why i haven't changed this to
repeaters yet like a repeater
five o'clock or whatever is because they
glitch out so that's why i still like
using the old school
types of clocks
yeah i'll just do that for now
okay so that's one layer
now to build it up
play sandstone oh yeah one thing
i was going to mention see this glass
block here
for all my longtime viewers that is the
skylight i placed back in
i think episode 1 or something this
little glass block
got covered up buried underground and i
came across it digging this out
and i destroyed it so that was placed
over six months ago
that glass block
um
so we can go up a layer here
probably use sandstone here
run wiring up to a second level
getting some lag
and
hmm
more like can't remember if you have
a dispenser a block on top
oops
block on top and you power the block on
top does it activate the dispenser
i kind of think it does
let's try it out
[Music]
oh you gotta go get my hand on skin
yeah okay so i might use that method
for powering the second layer
i went ahead and started working on the
second layer here just because i'm
going over time kind of with this
episode so i want to
finish this up soon uh
decided to make a few changes here i'm
gonna get rid of
these edge dispensers
or corner dispensers i guess
and i'm going to have water there
so there'll be water here and here like
that
actually i should check the streams make
sure they are okay
yep so i'm gonna take those out
and i'm gonna have a piston
thing here to shut off the water so that
when i
have to restock these dispensers
i won't have water pushing me around in
here and i'll have a lever out here to
control
the water to turn it on and off
because with this quick kit thing i'll
basically be able to use it nine times
because like for individual items like
pork chops you can only put nine in so
once
once those nine are out you need to
restock it
so that
i'll wire these later
go down one further sticky piston there
and here
it'll be a block above um
it's pretty easy wiring these dispensers
gonna have to have water all or not
water redstone you're gonna have to have
redstone all along the top here
you won't be able to see any of this
wiring when it's done
this redstone will activate the second
row here
these ones will get activated because
the redstone's pointing at them
so that's good and we'll also have
some more dispensers
along the top here
maybe one here it's going to be a
glowstone in the center
in the ceiling to light this up a bit
too
like that um
you know i think i can actually
put some here too
i think they'll shoot the item into the
block but they'll fall
the item will fall through the dispenser
actually i should probably try that
put some cobble in there
yeah it fell through i don't know if you
saw that
all right it's cool and maybe
have two more at the top here
like this run the wire a little bit
further
oops just going to place a lever here
make sure the current runs all the way
it does not that's a problem
but nothing a repeater can't solve
i may put a repeater here i think that
would be safe
right okay so be one more dispenser
here and this will be covered
somehow put these here for now
something like this will be glowstone
above here for light
and we can restock every single one of
these
because there are none are hidden behind
blocks or anything
and we'll have pistons
just mark them here and here
turn the water on and off
okay so the idea is in some of these
dispensers i'll have
uh food i'll probably have one or two
well probably probably three of these
will be
dedicated to the cooked pork chops
i'll have one for a sword one for a boat
um one one or two for picks
one or two for shovels uh
i'll need torches too maybe
i'll have one for a bow for sure
and there'll probably be a chest out
here too because i won't be able to
dispense
arrows for example so i'll need to pick
up stuff from chess
too so maybe i'll have a chest full of
arrows and torches um
stuff you need a lot of because these
will only dispense one at a time at this
current setup or i may change the wiring
so that
maybe the top ones will dispense
like 4 8 or 16 of a certain block type
i don't know we'll see
but yeah this episode's getting long so
i
should really cut it here so that's what
i'm going to do
thank you for watching i'll finish this
up some other time
and i believe i'm at five stacks of tnt
now so
hopefully next episode will do
we'll see one of the coolest explosions
ever in minecraft
because i blew up i think 200 tnt just
to test out my
tnt chaining and it was very cool so i'm
very excited to see
a thousand of them blowing up the entire
island that'll be cool
well i gotta go gotta get my atoms so
thank you for watching
take care until next time
okay i forgot one last thing i just want
to quickly mention that i'm going to try
try to put my world up for download
again
in the video description uh the secret
project is not donna i
actually haven't worked on it in over a
month now just because i've been
busy and i'm barely getting episodes out
as it is so i can't really
do more than i'm doing right now but
soon i'll get to it again
what i'm going to do is i'm going to try
to delete the region that the secret
project is in
so that no one will see it and
if all goes well you'll be able to
download my world again an updated
version
in the video description and if i can't
figure it out
well that's why if i can't figure it out
it won't be in the video description so
hopefully i can get it for you