hello everyone this is another episode
of minecraft with your good buddy etho
here and it's been a while since we
watched the sunrise together so let's
take a moment so nice I've been working
hard on that renovating my base there's
been many changes well yeah that's
enough and okay so a few things light
doesn't pass through stairs anymore huge
issue for me as you all know I abused
that glitch like crazy and now it's gone
so I got a redesign a lot of my base I
changed the tracks we're no longer have
the stairs going inward I don't like how
this looks as much but you know at least
it gives light we have little torches
under all these glass blocks and that
goes all around if I ever get enough
glowstone I might switch the glass with
glowstone
Sammis here I would like to put one
glowstone here and one here at least
light this part up a little bit other
things the track is now mostly this what
do you call these power rails mostly I
didn't quite have enough to do the whole
thing I got I need like another 10 or 20
unfortunately I'm out of gold and no I'm
not going to harvest the cannons for
gold I'm not going to do that
yeah so like I was all excited about the
first thunderstorm I saw on this game
and it like changed like people said
that any light that goes through stairs
before it'll keep going through stairs
as long as you don't change the adjacent
blocks when the first thunderstorm came
by it liked made all my whole storage
room dark it updated all the lighting
and no no the light was going through
stairs anymore so yeah I had to change
it all and I still need to redo a lot of
stuff not happy about that change do you
have some very cool things to show you
though
feel like oh yeah I forgot to show you
one more thing I don't know if you
remember but you could see a bunch of
cobblestone over here now I have wood at
the ceiling it's a little bit curved and
try and make it nice I'm not quite happy
with above the creeper face yet it looks
a little strange
I'm not really sure what I'm gonna do
about that the reason I want the natural
sunlight is so it lights up all these
color blocks nicely and the creeper face
as well otherwise it'll be pretty dark
and I got crafting tables around the
place now just because I had like two
before and it was really annoying to
walk around the whole storage room
looking for a crafting table but yeah
the reason I changed well I'm not gonna
get ahead of myself I added half slabs
above the water controlled double doors
here just so I don't walk into the water
pit and I redid this room it's much
nicer now I think it's more symmetrical
now you can see through the glass or
still nothing below these glass things
will be eventually go down here
but the biggest change well there's I
got rid of the ladder in the ceiling I'm
gonna find some other way to go up
instead of going through here yeah but
the biggest change is this wall and this
wall you'll notice there are levers
light signs buttons redstone torches all
the things I like and this is for our
rail system it's finally set up it's
working pretty good now I might need to
change a few things on it I'll I'll show
you how it works and then we'll go down
look at it closer this lever here turns
the minecarts on and off in order to get
them going and you need to turn this on
they won't come just by flicking the
lever you need to make it a little
quieter you need to start it kinda like
starting a car usually you can start it
by pressing the button but sometimes you
need to pull this lever instead for like
two seconds
and here they come
pretty nice easy to hop off they keep
going hop on again and the reason why I
wanted these power rails all the way
around is so that when you're riding in
a carts
if you don't have these all the way
around you will slowly start catching up
to the empty cart in front of you
because empty carts lose momentum a lot
faster but if they're at maximum speed
the whole time from these power rails
and that doesn't happen so it prevents
you from bumping into an empty cart
ahead of you uh-huh so you can shut it
off flick this down and my carts will
start coming pretty soon yet they
stopped that's cool
the other ones keep going
now over here we have a variable delay
timer for the whole thing there's a to
second base delay so that's the minimum
spacing between the minecarts I just had
major like is that two seconds then we
have an additional two seconds we can
add an additional one so we can have our
minecart space both of these are down
it'll be two seconds this one's up it'll
be three seconds this one's up it'll be
four seconds and if these are both up
it's five seconds it's pretty cool I
could have made it shorter than two
seconds if I want to do like half a set
into a second but didn't really need it
to be I don't like I like not having to
worry about walking on this tracking and
I don't like I don't want to worry about
bumping into a minecart all the time
yeah so it's a few seconds now see
still get these things here they come
again
so now they're spaced a little bit
closer than they were I think I have it
three seconds before generally if you're
gonna switch it timing you need to shut
it off first
otherwise you might mess it up but let's
see what happens if you change it when
it's running still looks like two
seconds
that was five seconds you see the big
change in spacing now so they're five
seconds of parts pretty cool and then
finally we have the flaming minecarts on
and off so one feature I like oh we have
a jam here I could use detector rails to
stop that from happening I might end up
doing that because it does happen every
so often usually only if I'm on that
track will it do that if I bump one of
the money carts they're relatively easy
to get going you just have to give them
a little push
all right so let's start it now with
flaming minecarts turn that on its a
button you like turning the key on your
car pressing the button dope
oh you know why yeah it's that's another
thing if you have it off still if you
press the button it will only send one
out so now it'll keep going
so it took me about four or five hours
working on this to get it to this point
probably like three or four hours
yesterday and wondered one or two today
maybe it was six hours had a lot of fun
doing it
so yeah let's go check it out show you
what it looks like when it's running
holds ten mine carts in the PES stack
here and then they go here go by the hot
and cold thing go up and around in the
notes and there's a power rails all the
way up so it's so we can make it this
thing goes around and then it freezes on
the slope for however long the delay is
and then it gets powered again and goes
and it goes over this detector rail
every time it goes around and that's
what keeps the loop going
and with these PEZ dispenser systems
with the new boosters they're a little
bit finicky if you're going straight you
can do it if you're going straight I'm
pretty sure but you need to space the
power rails properly it's really easy to
do though if you just go have it sloped
up right where it meets your stack here
like I have here so that's the way I
ended up doing it
oh yeah there's um one issue I realized
after I had this all built Mayan carts
no longer get put out by water the
flames when they're flaming
I think that's new in the 1.5 patch or
else the one point five point one patch
just a brand new change I don't like
that at all
till the water and this hot and cold
thing does nothing now unfortunately so
the only way to put these flames out is
to actually destroy the minecarts and
replace them which is really
disappointing I doubt they did that
intentionally okay so I just stopped the
video for a bit so that I could rewatch
what I have recorded of the episode so
far I do that sometimes so that I can
see if I missed anything
no we just happened
what the heck man yeah I got that
detector rails great and I think I just
lost the minecart yeah I stopped to see
if I missed talking about anything and
this world's just full of distractions
let's go look at the Thunder don't know
why it keeps getting stuck there that
doesn't make sense
sweet okay I lost my train of thought
what was I talking about I yeah I
stopped to see if I I miss talking about
anything and you might self time to
think of course - and when Yuri watch
the video like when he actually watches
it but as an observer you notice things
that you don't notice when you're
actually playing the game and like
saying start instead of stop but one
thing I noticed is as my carts were
going by I said the minimum delay was
two seconds and I counted one two it's
not two seconds I can safely get out of
here I'll show you what why it's two
seconds like the torch delays two
seconds but I think and I'm really
scared now it's a guy right there
but it's two seconds plus the time it
takes this cart to go up here around and
hit this detector so it's probably more
like three four seconds yeah anyway yeah
I don't know if I'm going to attempt to
explain this even cable when this whale
receives power I have a button here it
goes up then it goes over the detector
goes to this and eight power is allowed
to pass through it goes to either AM
variable timer here I have videos on
this I did change this a bit though no I
don't even know if I should try to
explain this okay well with his timer it
splits the wire splits here one one of
these paths this one here is the
shortcuts and this one here is the long
the long way and then they meet again
and if power is allowed to go through
the shortcut will reach the end quicker
you guys I haven't seen two under yet or
like God come on the car outside already
we want to see it yeah I've seen that a
few times already I'm not I'm not too
excited by it yeah but there's an Andy
tear with the levers from up above the
plus one and plus two seconds they
control this and it's that determine
whether the power can take the shortcuts
if it can't take the shortcut it has to
go through this long way with these
repeater delays you can see it's two
four four that's ten which is a clone
into about one second so this is the one
second one then it goes to another and
eats this is the change I've made from
the variable timer system that I've
never done before this other end eat
here I wonder how many people have quit
the video already the other end date is
to prevent as a here it sends power this
way and this way if powers allowed to
pass through here it'll keep going down
here but the power from here also keeps
going normally and so the shortcut goes
through and then soon after the long I
can't explain this come on you guys can
download my world and check it out let's
let's leave it at that if you want to
figure it out yeah so the other thing
sometimes the car gets stuck here I
don't know what oh you know why it's
wrong I think I think I got wolves
running around and that's why it keeps
getting missed
because normally it's not this bad I'm
thinking about what building some kind
of nice wooden platform all around here
because I liked how it looks
looking down from here and I'll be doing
lots of renovating down here to make you
look nicer I bet you it's the Wolves I
can't think of it any other reason it's
before I had that closed off there's
probably no wolves here now there is a
few
[Music]
oh man I hate those guys another one
another one nope yeah okay one more
attempt to explain this one quick
attempt okay splits here if power can
pass through both of these wires the
short ones gonna go through and then
shortly after the delay one's gonna go
and instead of having like clean clean
power it's gonna be pulsing on off on
off and that on offs going to affect
this cart because the power needs to be
on for the right amount of time for it
to work the buttons usually give off one
second of power and same with these
pressure plates here these detector
rails it's about one second of power
which is it just enough time for this
cart to go up and get off these power
rails otherwise it gets stuck on the
power rail like up at the slope here
sometimes this happens to it like it's
stuck on both rails it's very rare
though
yeah so it needs about that solid one
second of power to make it all the way
up here if this after it goes through
the two timers the power ends it goes
down here that goes to here and then the
power rails just beyond this repeater
here so if this is if this wire is
flashing on off on off it's not going to
work it needs to be on for a solid one
second and it needs to be timed properly
and so by having an and each on each of
these split wires it prevents the
unwanted signal from going through and
messing things up basically I think
that's as clear as I can explain it and
so this is one lever here the one second
one it splits here gets inverted the
signal and it goes to one of the and
eats and the other one goes to the other
end dates so they're opposites little
strange not very interesting if you
don't like redstone so my apologies for
that
peekaboo
peekaboo are you tending them nice
normally this rail system works a lot
better this is the worst I've seen it
working since I've started recording I'm
pretty sure it's because of the wolves
that's the other way is starting it's
pulling the lever for two seconds yes so
about the wolves I need to stop them
from coming in here now which means we
need to work on the mob system again and
find a more permanent solution and so I
figured out what I want to do I think
instead of having the pigs the cows and
the sheep and all that instead of having
all their drops come to here I'm gonna
split them up after all
cows and sheep I'll probably make drop
over there the leather and wool and
bacon I'm gonna make fall out here and
I've decided actually episode's probably
getting a little bit long I'm gonna have
like a glass roof over here not too big
it's gonna be a little room above the
doors here glass yeah it will make it to
four by four glass and this is where the
pigs are gonna drop right above us
and they're gonna be set on fire so that
they'll produce cooked pork chops
instead of just raw ones so there's
gonna be a little room and somehow I'm
gonna have some stairs to go up to it's
probably out here and we can watch the
pigs burning above us
[Music]
it should be pretty cool I'm gonna check
the time if we have time I'll start
working on it actually yeah we're like
30 minutes and so probably can't do it
this episode I really wanted to go that
wasted wasted all my time talking about
the power rails and stuff so next
episode what we're gonna do is we are
going to rip this out and we're gonna
run a long tube all the way along here
to here and then it's gonna drop the
pigs onto a flame and then the pigs will
walk off the flame onto the glass and
they'll they'll roast above the glass I
guess you could say and all along like
we're gonna have a long tube here I'm
also gonna have a proper wolf separator
along the tube and it'll push the Wolves
out this way and the Wolves will go to
where the sheep and cows are going to go
over there somewhere we'll probably be
special building built for them at some
point okay so I'm gonna end it here we
saw the Sun Rise and now we can watch
the moon set together I really need to
finish up my cactus farm and my tree
farm to probably have some glass around
and then maybe a ring of lights and then
some kind of covering
I don't know okay thank you for watching
everybody I really appreciate it
hope you enjoyed it I'll see you next
time