I've done it
I have freakin done it yeah oh it took
me 34 episodes and like two months but I
finally done it I have built myself a
house yeah baby
that's right many of you rumored that I
didn't know how to build houses eat it
that's that's my first house isn't it
awesome
now we can hang out you can come over
hang out just chill if you want to crash
here you can crash here it'll be awesome
ahh
now but I'll in seriousness I have
started to put a roof over this thing
and hopefully we'll start to finish it
up um what do you guys think of it I
probably won't have all these lights
maybe just the ones in the middle I
might replace these logs with glowstone
and I've built this sort of wall thing
so the items in the dispensers are
represented above more or less they're a
little bit hard to see though but but
they're pretty good I might make this
track one block higher have like this
center part raised so that there's a
wooden stair on the side and this side
and this will be one block higher
as if you're on a block you can see them
quite a bit better but I'm not sure and
I put windows on the top of the outside
wall kind of cool got like a log pattern
in the roof and yeah not a lot has
changed in this world since uh what has
it been a week since my last episode
hooked up double doors and on the
outside of the place I'm gonna have to
put a layer of something all around the
building so that you don't see the
dispensers and stuff and yeah and I kind
of outlined these round parts not
entirely sure how I'm going to do them
yet aha
and I finished the colour wheel except
for brown because Brown doesn't exist
yet but I went on a journey there's a
bunch of snowy mountains over there and
I went to exploring a little bit looking
for the or is it lupus and yeah I found
some got about lapis got twenty-one of
it left and that's about the only
changes I think haven't done anything
with the mob system kind of waiting for
a patch I am having issues with my world
though docum 77s had the same problem is
my James didn't really lad you now frame
rate is dropping I think it might be
because of this wall here I'm not sure
which kind of sucks because I still got
a lot of things I want to build here I
might get rid of this lava place it with
torches and see if that helps over here
I got torches all along these are wooden
stairs and that allows light to pass
through them and I might try to destroy
this wall and see if it increases my
framerate because I think it's started
to drop after I built it so something I
just did now as I replaced my water
block at the top of ladder
and I've always been afraid to do that
because I thought it some of the drops
from the mobs get burnt but it seems to
be working 100% I haven't seen any of
them get run yet it's nice because I
don't have to listen to them screaming
in that for nearly as long so okay I'm
going to keep it there I'm probably
going to overhaul my whole mob system
over here because I've recently made
those mob tutorials and they have given
me lots of ideas
so I think I'd make a much better one
now my god um oh yeah
I'm gonna give a shout-out to Shai
cherry I hope I said your name right he
sent me a message on YouTube he asked me
if I could think of any way to make a
door stay open for two seconds or longer
when you press a button because normally
if you press a button on a door a lot of
times you'll try to walk through it and
it's closed by the time you get there
already and it's really annoying so yeah
this is what I came up with works pretty
good
it's an RS nor latch by fault
it sends no power to the door when you
press a button it switches the latch so
that it's powered and then it also sends
power to this delay here which you can
make is however long you want and
that'll just how long the door stays
open then it goes back to the RS nor
latch and sets it off again
thanks to shy Terry for that idea I was
really excited to show you guys this but
um yesterday someone sent me a video
response for how I could set up my this
loop thing with the minecart tracks and
in his video response I saw he built
pretty much the exact same thing as I
got over here so this is not a new
discovery at all I'm sure lots of people
have done this but in case you didn't
know how to do it that's how you do it
and I got a few things they want to talk
about I got to give some shoutouts to
people so I hope you guys don't mind I'm
going to make this three times speed
episode and I'm Anna do voiceover
commentary and you can listen to me
while you watch me builds my storage
room superfast so the first thing I
wanted to say is I just want to thank
everybody so much that donated that's
incredible of you guys it's awesome and
I appreciate it a lot so thank you very
much I'm gonna talk about that a little
bit more in a few minutes here another
thing I wanted to talk about was a last
video I mentioned about maybe becoming a
machinima partner yeah I kind of decided
not to do it after all after there was
really no chance you guys are gonna get
into mission about one one reason why I
might not have is because as many of you
know I don't really sound excited in my
videos and pretty much all I should the
directors are all hopped up on something
because you know it's like oh okay
the pigs looking at me let's write the
pig
and I'm I'm not like that at all I don't
know why but I just had such a hard time
being energetic when I'm playing
Minecraft um this doesn't come natural
but um some reasons why I don't want to
join machinima anymore are mainly that
sounds like there's going to be a few
guidelines I have to follow like they're
not bad or anything but like I have to
upload videos in 720p which I would like
to do actually but there's no way to set
your video resolution the Minecraft that
I know of so my only option is to record
in 1080p and then steal it now which is
a huge pain in the butt to do it takes
forever um another reason I kind of
originally wanted to become a mission a
my partner because I thought it was the
only way I could make money on YouTube
and I I just wanted to make a few bucks
you know for my videos nothing major and
well you guys have done that for me
already through the donation thing thank
you again
um I'm quite happy even if I don't make
another cent good yeah and also many of
you pointed out that I can become a
YouTube partner while I thought I
couldn't so there's a chance I might
make money from that too if my
application ever goes through also like
50 you guys thumbs up a comment in my
episode 33 and the guy said you thought
don't become a machinima your mom so I'm
trying to do what my viewers want to but
I am going to give a shout-out to the
fanatic glitchers he's the guy that was
going to help me become part of
machinima thanks for your time dude
sorry for wasting it I really appreciate
he's a cool guy
I actually want you guys to do me a huge
favor
I want you to go visit his channel I'm
going to put a link in the description
of this video I want you to visit his
channel and leave comments either on his
channel or in his videos saying
transformers rocks or transformers is
awesome something like that because I
was uh playing xbox other day and I was
talking to him on my xbox and as play my
favorite game which is transformers war
for Cybertron and he and his friend razz
me pretty bad about it they compared it
to some gay Power Rangers game they made
fun of me for a solid 5 or 10 minutes
about playing itself and that they
called it a gator our Rangers name
simply because of the title they have no
idea what the game is about and if you
do a search on YouTube for transformers
or for Cybertron deathmatch you can see
it's definitely not a game it's actually
really awesome so and that irony of the
whole thing is like the whole time I was
talking to him and his friend it sounded
like they were playing some game where
they were in like an enchanted forest
seeing if they could jump from treetop
to treetop while holding hands or
something I get their games sounded
pretty gay to me so make sure you visit
his channel leave a comment saying
transformers is awesome another person I
want to give a shout out to is brainy
beast and I'll put a link to his channel
in the description as well he's a cool
guy too
he also makes Minecraft videos and
tutorials which are definitely worth
looking at for any be sent me some
useful information about how to get my
youtube partnership accepted some tricks
I could use and
he gave me other information about
YouTube partnerships like how much he
makes from a thousand views on average
and things like that - so thanks brandy
for that information check out his
channel and I'm going to give a shout
out to my YouTube buddies za Vangie toh
freak entertainer am 77 and SC joiner a
Congrats to SC joiner for become a
YouTube partner that's awesome dude and
yeah so I guess so that's about all the
talking time I have we're going to do
one more thing this episode before we
end it I'm going to tell you guys how
we're going to do the 5000 subscriber
special ahead of time and I think you're
going to like this idea so yes I wanted
to do something nice for everyone that
donated something to show my
appreciation because that was a very
nice thing for you guys to do to donate
money to kind of a stranger and I
thought about making a wall a bunch of
signs on with everyone's name that
donated and it that would be a nice
thing to do but it's not really all that
original of an idea and I know you guys
watch my videos because I'm somewhat
original with my ideas so I kind of had
a fun idea here's what we're going to do
um
assuming I reach 5,000 subscribers which
I hope I do for the 5,000 subscribers
special
I've built this little area over here
around these awesome mountains what is
this thing why is there a button here
while I started underwater base
just started haven't got a lot done and
what I'm going to do for everyone that
donates I'm going to build each of you a
cannon and every time I have a special
like a 5000 subscriber special or a
million views special or anything like
that we're going to come down here look
at the cannons and then we're going to
fire them off and have like a firework
display hopefully and I'm going to put a
sign on everyone's cannon showing which
one is theirs I'm not going to show how
much they donated because I don't want
to make someone seem more important than
other but that's what I'm going to do
because I appreciated all your gifts no
matter the size and yeah I think it'll
be a fun idea so the more people that
donate the more impressive the firework
display is going to be and it's a fun
idea for me because I get to build
cannons which I love doing and it's a
fun idea for you guys because you got to
watch the cannon display and you get to
see the champions too and I was making
every one of them different but then
yeah
I thought this cannon was going to be
really awesome because it has a
compressor system which makes all the TV
boosters gather in the same place close
to the payload which should increase the
power of the cannon by a lot but I
overlooked the fact that the TNT blast
doesn't transfer with it and haven't
been back to your since that kind of
sucked
hey holy crap I did not even know this
was here
okay um yes I'm going to make I'm going
to put a sign on all the cannons with
you guys's names on for which one is
yours I won't be using your real name
because I doubt you guys want me sharing
your real name on the Internet some of
you I know your youtube name I'll
probably put that on the sign and for
those of you that I don't know your
youtube name I'm going to use your
initials and if you want a youtube name
or something instead of your initials
just send me a message on YouTube with
your real name and the name you would
like me to use instead and then that's
what I'll do so if you're wondering how
much was donated I don't like to keep
those things secret because that
information might be useful for someone
else so this is where we stand
not quite
let's see seventeen donors is donors the
right word or is it donators um what was
it 388 we are at 412
my math is really bad right now
438 oh I wish Ariel so thanks to
everyone that donated actually I said I
wasn't going to give anyone special
mention but I think two people I
probably should because the day after I
uploaded episode 33 like the first thing
I did that day is one of the first
things as I woke up and then I was
eating my mini wheats and I checked
YouTube to make sure everything was okay
and episode 33 was uploaded for not even
an hour yet then I checked my email and
somebody donated a hundred dollars right
off the bat a J or a G so thank you for
that donation that put me in a good mood
for the whole day and I'm still in a
good mood from it and then I checked the
donations later in the day and like 15
more people donated almost which was
awesome and then at the end of the day
Kotaro cos donated a hundred and fifty
dollars that's incredible so thank you
everybody
those two people I will probably put
some gold on their cannons just because
they pulled out the extra stops not that
I didn't appreciate everybody's and I do
appreciate the money but I also really
appreciate the gesture and it makes me
feel good because it shows you guys must
really like my videos so
I'm going to show you one of these
Tenon's being fired remember I'm using
real TNT here not to edit it in TNT so I
have to use it sparingly and I need to
make 17 cannons at the moment so
hopefully I'll get them done in time
before the 5000 subscriber special and I
think there was something else I
supposed to say - oh yes then talk about
the program
all first let's launches oh I guess it
the vote are you kidding me
oh I hope I didn't blow everything up oh
okay what are the chances of that I was
going to say expect that except 17 times
better but yeah let's hope it works next
time you get the idea though so I'm
going to go to build one more cannon now
I'm going to build all the cannons down
here and I look forward to our display
and those of you that inquired about the
program I'm going to make I probably
will um just set up a donation thing for
it instead of charging people money for
it if you're wondering what it is I
don't want to give too much information
about it because it's a unique idea and
I don't want anyone stealing it but it
has to do with emulating games on your
computer if you play Super Nintendo
games on your computer or Playstation or
anything
that Genesis you might be interested in
my program because it'll make your
experience much more enjoyable playing
retro games on your computer and that's
all the info I'm going to give about it
and later if it gets closer to
completion I'll probably post the video
on my youtube channel showing off the
program I would like to get input from
people on it but I don't want to give
out the idea just yet okay
so we're going to wrap up the episode
here move this boat next episode I think
we're going to start building the farm
animal collection system level 3 of the
storage room because I'm excited to do
that and I don't really want to wait
until level 2 is done or level 1 even so
see you next time