hey guys this is e so you're joining me
again for some minecraft fun I literally
just got Beaufort a few seconds ago so
what are we going to do today well we're
actually going to build something today
we're gonna start working on the storage
room and I kind of planned it all out
the best I could
[Music]
let's get crackin basically there's
gonna be a inner ring of dispensers and
there's gonna be an outer ring
dispensers the inner ring is gonna be
for items that don't really have a block
such as a better gunpowder or redstone
torches anything that's not a solid
block like cobblestone is and so I
figured I'm going to need to make
Oh going to need to make it 28 by 28 a
big square and I'm just gonna head up
here because I figured out where the
creepers keep telling them don't plug on
here
Mariel the odd time one will go up there
instead of being killed like it should
kind of a flaw not a dozen hot happen
too often only if a bunch of mobs going
on or spiders okay anyway let's get
started there's not gonna be any
dispensers here I'm gonna leave this
open so that we can look at the mob crap
leave one block buffer here I'm gonna
hook up these redstone torches to the
pressure plates down below to tap to
detect when that mob goes by I think and
from here my kid and for the quarter
that's seven I counted this is gonna be
12 plus 7 that's 14 oh that's weird
that's 2026 this kind of big this is
gonna be a big storage room
oh yeah I should count this we need 24
wood blocks here 1 2 3
23 24 holy this is huge
hmm maybe two huge 24 and then two for
the corner
and I don't know about this now that's
way too big I'm gonna redo this do-over
okay so I had it kind of figured out
mathematically on paper but when you
actually see it it doesn't look good so
the plan is to make it look good or
better at least
and so I'm gonna make the inside a lot
smaller got to fill in this hole I put
it towards here for now so that's one
side and I'm sure wish it was a baked
item
I kind of want this to end here 14 plus
4 is 18 as that compared to this side
[Music]
and when I say 18 so it's almost where
okay I got the inside base laid out and
I rebuilt kind of a ground here so now
it is button time
creeper check and yeah this much that's
gonna have to be wrong okay I got 48
things now 14 on two sides eight on this
one and 12 on opposite sides of this and
if you haven't figured out what I'm
doing yet you'll soon get an idea so I
decided to use wood because you can see
the buttons clearly on it I like the
look of wood and it's gonna be chests
around which also have the would look so
kinda match these buttons gets a
dispenser and each of these dispensers
is going to hold a unique item and the
dispenser is going to act as storage as
well as I can click a button yet one
item out and I got lots of dispensers
thanks to our mob system 128 more and I
will probably actually use them all
hello inside here's where the debts are
going to be and I'll try to clean it up
too and like very important life isn't I
might not do that after all very
unfortunate I don't get creepers
now because they don't want my storage
area blowing up the next thing there's
gonna be a layer of glass above each of
these
and behind the glass is going to be
they'll say for example this had a
sapling inside behind the glass is going
to be a sapling planted if it's an item
that you can't place down in any way
such as string I'm going to probably
place a sign on the glass that says
string so I can't physically represent
it with a block I'm going to use a sign
and I'm hoping it'll look cool Jannik
you guys have ideas let me know and I
might use them so this has Durden if I
press this on dirt shoots out or I can
pick it up pick them up directly from
the dispenser and the buttons do not
interfere with each other very simple
see think I'm gonna put furnaces in this
corner and all the corners and probably
a crafting bench
nah I'll clean it up
you know that probably keep this cobble
one rule of Kabul on these stairs
and okay so I kinda did one wall here
just to see what it would look like I
don't know if I quite like it I thought
it would look better than it does some
of these have the items behind in
summers with science records saddle sign
balls books sticks redstone wire
redstone torches torches fences ladders
signs paintings what do you guys think
of it
I think I'm gonna get you guys it so
pinion before I commit on anything it's
a little bit harder to see items and I
thought it was going to be because of
these glass blocks and there's not
really a balance because it's a mix of
signs and items one thing I could do is
put signs over top these
but then I don't know not really sure
I'll let you guys decide and I kind of
did this side to t get powder string
leather bone arrows feathers Flint so I
did the mob drops on the side since it's
close to this thing here be easier to
put them in the dispensers and there's
gonna be chess here as well I'll be on
the ground so oh yeah some time I need
to hook up the Zelda tune to this thing
I might do that off camera but anyway
give me your pants and I'll decide what
to do and there's going to be dispensers
on the other side so they'll probably be
a gap of five or six blocks maybe more
and then on the side there's going to be
dispensers with things like sand and
cobblestone the solid block items as
well as things like tools and yeah that
kind of stuff
so there's one more thing I was doing a
while ago I never showed you guys we're
gonna have to block this off for now
some of you suggested I should hook up
musical note blocks to the eats road and
I actually did do that and I forgot to
tell you guys there is a bit of an issue
with it though
see there's no boats here so I just
hooked up a few notes to check how it
would work so on three of these pressure
pads I have oats hooked up and so with
no delay it's one note block and then
with the two redstone delay for ticks
it hits the next one and so what I had
figured is I apparently boats move at
the same speed as mine carts boats on
that eats Road a lot of people said that
mine carts move at eight blocks per
second and so it would take about half a
second to move from this pressure plate
to
- this one so that would be half a
second so if we had a temple of one
second I'm not very good at musical
theory but let's say this counted as one
bar going from here to here going over
to pressure plates that's eight blocks
one second this in between one would be
half a second and a lot of people say
that there's 16 ticks per second in this
game so that's current passing through 8
torches would be 1 second current
passing through 4 torches will be half a
second or the time to go from here to
here if in fact minecarts moved at 8
blocks per second and going through two
torches would be 1/4 second so that's
why I have have it like this
[Music]
so like going to this first one would be
like if the note was on the bar at the
start of the bar this would be like a
quarter moving up a pressure plate would
be a half and then passing through two
two more torches would be a three
quarter if in fact all those numbers
were accurate but if you go over them
with a boat you can hear that they're
what's wrong here it's not working
what's wrong with our Road that time
four leg
[Music]
yeah so did you hear that it didn't
sound to me like the oops I accidentally
pressed right it didn't sound like the
temple was even there like it should be
[Music]
all those so six notes got played they
should all be evenly spaced from each
other if all those numbers were right
[Music]
he's breaking all the boats today so
yeah if there there was 16 picks in a
second and a minecart traveled eight
blocks per second those should have been
even but they're not so something is
wrong so I don't know how well you know
blocks would work with this road unless
you had notes that every one of these
pressure plates without using any
redstone torches if that makes sense but
anyway I'm gonna in the episode here
give me your ideas on this what should I
do
and I'll probably follow them because I
don't know what I want to be now and
thanks for watching