hey everyone this is etho and today we
are playing some more minecraft haven't
played minecraft much last few days and
busy finally you've been able to play a
little bit more today I've been working
on that tribute game I've recorded a few
clips of me building it which I might
put into making an episode out of I
don't know yet yeah I've been working on
the tribute game started working on
something over there
today's going to be a bit of a talky
episode but hopefully we'll start
building our hostile mob system to as
we're talking so I brought up the issue
about the spiders should I build the
spider only spawning system or not and
you mostly you guys seem to agree with
me that it's just not worth the bother
there's just not much benefit to it we
don't need string really we're getting
plenty of wool it would be nice to have
but well we got two pink wool two pink
sheep fell that's mega rare yeah it's
just not really worth the bother because
we would need to make a very large
spawning system to get a decent rate
going and it would be a giant floating
structure in the sky and you know just
it's a lot of work for such a simple
thing so we'll skip that we'll be
building a mob system very similar to
the one I usually build with the 6x6
spawning pads
I'll have a spider option to turn them
on or off tall mobs will always be
spawning
and I'd also this is what I got built so
far so this cobblestone square I have
built here is 20 by 20 in size so it's
divided into four quarters which are ten
by ten each and you can see we have four
spawning pads in the works here and
these are six by six like my normal
style and these spaces in between our
fertile water canals which we need to
add yet which will probably do today and
we're just going to go to sleep at night
you can see I cut away one of the
extensions on the passive mob farm it
was in the way so I just decided to get
rid of it completely because I want this
Center here to be closer to these E&P
units as close as possible though
causing any major problems so I cut away
that extension we lost fifty spawning
spaces for the passive mob system doing
that too to these diamond pads which we
will need to get back some other way
what I'm planning on doing eventually
most likely is to get rid of all these
extensions I added and instead have
several layers probably three layers up
with four of these diamond pads each
layer and that will help to increase the
efficiency of this thing at the expense
of it to being really tall and yeah it
should reduce the mob traveled the mob
travel time if I do that because if a
mob has to travel this extra distance
here it takes a lot longer than if they
only have to traveled this part here so
eventually I'll probably get around to
doing that
and with this new mob system I'm
building I'm going to be doing much the
same thing or
going to be stacking these layers I'm
thinking at least four layers with four
pads each one on top of each other is
the plan and we should maybe get to
building it so I decide to do another
one of these fast forward things you can
watch me fumble through building my mob
system here the first layer I'm just
going to build the first layer and then
we'll test it out if it works good will
I'll probably build the other three or
four layers off-camera if it works good
if it doesn't we'll have to figure
something else so but I think it should
be okay and as you watch me build this I
thought it might be cool to talk about
something that's on everybody's mind
that 1.8 patch that's coming out soon
that adventure update I saw notch
live-streaming it at PAX and it looks
very cool very incredible stuff lots of
new features are coming out and a lot of
people have expressed concern that maybe
it's going to break my LP series you
know it's going to cause me problems and
I thought it'd be good to address some
of that first thing I want to point out
a lot of people think patch is going to
be coming out in a day or two from what
I saw of the livestream I would be very
surprised if it does they have lots of
work to do on it yet lots of features
aren't complete such as villages I did
not see any NPCs or anything like that
and they were having other problems with
implementing villages so I wouldn't
expect anything soon actually it it
sounded like they were going to do two
patches instead of one big patch so
they'll probably release a few patch or
a few features soon like in a week or
two and then as they work on its more
they'll release a bunch of other stuff
and I'm guessing they'll put villages
off for later some other cool things
that came out are these new dungeons
there's like abandoned mine shafts
stuff like that there's new biomes
existing biomes can be bigger now so we
can have huge oceans huge deserts stuff
like that and of course there's an
experience system that was added which
at the moment isn't complete it doesn't
do anything I'm guessing they'll make it
like maybe you can mine faster as you
gain more experience input skills into
mining or farming or something like that
I don't know we'll see what happens I'm
just guessing and what else
big thing people keep pointing out to me
is the Enderman they're worried they're
gonna mess up my world here um Enderman
what should I say about them well in the
videos I saw they are three blocks high
this mob system I'm building here is
going to be cheap excuse me it's going
to be three blocks high so that they can
hopefully spawn in it we don't know the
exact details of how they'll work yet so
everything I'm doing here is kind of
guesswork if they are a problem like
they at the moment they can move random
blocks they become a problem I can
always put lower the ceiling in this mob
system so it's only to high and that way
they probably won't be able to spawn but
if they do spawn there their heads will
be in the ceiling and they'll suffocate
I'm hoping so if they're an issue that's
what I can do
I doubt notch will make them so that
they can destroy the world without you
know some kind of justification they do
look more powerful than other mobs more
difficult to kill you can't really run
away from them once you upset them so
they should be interesting it but they
are supposed to be pretty rare so in one
video I saw of people playing they
dropped diamonds when they died while
you zero to two diamonds so I'm very
interested in that that looks cool even
if they're rare if I have a mob system
like this
I should be rolling in diamonds in no
time
lots of blue shiny rocks for ether so
that should be that should be cool if it
works out like that but I wouldn't be
surprised if they made them not drop
diamonds when they release the official
patch some other stuff chickens they
drop chicken meat now and they also
still drop feathers zombies don't drop
feathers anymore
I saw the job drop some red thing that
I've never seen before some new item so
I'm interested to see what that is
almost like some kind of leather or I
know is red very strange
I think there's supposed to be a new
blue spider or something from what I've
heard that makes cobwebs and you can
click cobwebs now that should be cool
they're supposed to be rare too from
what I read on the wiki and yeah I'm not
worried about it not working with my LP
series the patch from what I understand
things like villages and that won't
appear in my game the new biomes won't
appear in my game and less I explore
further and if I explore further than I
believe those things will randomly
generate just like they normally do so I
will probably keep this LP world I don't
think I'll build a new one or start a
new LP world so shouldn't be a problem
I'm not too worried about it
yeah there's rivers and the rivers they
look pretty nice and some of them will
have like porches be deep in the ground
um of course the combat was improved we
have critical hits now mobs will take
more damage if you hit them when you're
jumping and we have the new bow which
can shoot short medium and far shots
I think the far shots do more damage but
they take longer
charge up that should be cool and of
course the one thing I'm really
interested in is the sprinting you can -
now by double-tapping forward and when
you're dashing and you hit a mob they'll
get knocked back further so that would
be pretty cool sound like not just going
to make it use up your hunger meter if
you're dashing so if you have lots of
meat like me you might be able to - for
long periods of time and that sounds
that you could be fun good way of
getting around quicker a new lighting
system looks very smooth now and yeah
lots of cool stuff look forward to the
patch can't wait for it all right looks
like the first layer is done here let's
go up here I'll show you what I did I
covered up all the holes just so that no
light would enter into spawning pads as
we do our tests here first thing while I
guess I should show you the inside how
do I get inside
whoo and I made a little walkway here so
you can see it's dark in there
pitch black I saw it all the ice all the
water all the water canals are fixed
here it's three high like I said and
yeah should be good so let's let's head
down to ground level and you will see it
in action there it is that's what it
looks like from below not the prettiest
thing but in time we'll try make it look
better function comes first though in my
LP so we shall see it working now let's
switch the easy three mom's up there now
for moms five
six seven eight not too impressive
spawning rates at the moment and see
their spiders they get through it fairly
decent oh nice try
yeah so your basic mob system it works
so the reason the spawning rates aren't
very good at the moment is one we only
have four pads they're not a whole lot
of spawning space as I make more layers
the rates will increase but the main
reason I haven't lit up a whole lot of
caves in this area
like what like might be able to see some
mobs through the ice here below I can
see I didn't see a few down there it's
another one they're far down deep so I
got a lot of teams to light up around
here and when I do that then the rates
will dramatically increase but I was
actually surprised they're as good as
they are right now and it does what I
wanted it to do so there's one thing I
want to test yet the spider spawning
option my plan for it so let's head back
up there and I will show you how that's
going to work right so you may have been
wondering what's the deal with all these
holes what are they for why did I put
them in all I'll tell you now they're my
idea for a spider spawning option to
turn the spider spawning on or off and
they're also part of a lighting system
idea I had so you can see I have four
water blocks in here in these holes
and down below it looks like this so the
idea is tall mobs should be able to
spawn on any of these blocks but spiders
they need a three by three space around
the block chosen for them to spawn so if
they spawn on this block here they'll
need they'll check a space like this and
where the water block is here and since
there's a water block here I'm hoping
it'll decide that they're not allowed to
spawn there and that'll disable them
from spawning is what I'm hoping in my
old system I use tap slabs to do this so
if water works we'll be able to just
have water and lava piston controlled at
the top of this tower and if we want to
shut off mob spawning will allow the lab
to flow down all these holes every
spawning pad will have these holes in
them that water alive we can flow down
freely lava flows down and light up the
area mob shouldn't be able to spawn then
if we have water flowing down now date
oops
water slowing down I'm hoping it'll
prevent spiders from spawning so I'm
going to fill all these up with water
and cover them and then we'll see if it
works or not and really hoping it does
otherwise I got to rethink everything
here I've been watching this thing for a
few minutes now I have not seen any
spiders spawn since I put the water in
which is great that means it's working
I'm pretty sure I should have seen a
spider by now if it wasn't so yeah
that'll work great as a spider option
takes very little space I don't have a
huge mass of wiring or anything like
that and it works with this vertical
style of spawning system this tower
style
yeah I'll be great I want to try out the
lighting now see how long it takes lava
to disappear and stuff like that
what happens if water flows down as the
lab is disappearing things like that we
should figure out so let's head back up
there
I believe I'm only going to need about
four or eight lava sources to light up
this whole system so that's very
efficient and probably four or eight
Pistons to control it so should be good
let's try put live in these holes cover
them just to make sure daylight's not
interfering with the lighting and head
down through our spot here let's see is
that enough
lava oops so that block there is light
level 15 this will be fourteen thirteen
twelve eleven ten
so each pad we can probably get away
with the just two lava columns like this
diagonally from each other we need more
than one because one two three four this
would be fourteen thirteen twelve eleven
ten nine eight seven mobs can spawn at
light level seven so it's just not quite
enough with only one lava stream so
that's how the lighting will work no
mobs will be able to spawn in here if
it's lit up like this that's how we can
shut it down should be good let's head
back up this is the same type of
lighting system I was planning on using
in my spider only spawning system that
is building a couple days ago that
failed
and in the comments I saw a lot of
people were concerned that the lab would
disappear too slowly in the style so we
should check it out
because you know when you're caving
sometimes and you destroy lab a source
block sometimes it takes 5-10 minutes
for the lava to disappear so I
understand why people brought that up
but with this vertical columns I don't
think it takes that long yeah look how
fast it goes away takes time yes but at
the longest I would say
can't remember how fast lava travels
looks like one block every three or four
seconds anyway so it won't take too long
the other thing I'm wondering about is
what happens if you were to switch it
quickly like if you who had the lighting
system on and then you shut it off and
turned on the spider option shut off
spider spawning so lab would disappear
and then you would dump water down the
hole so let's try that out and remove
this and quickly put water in and see if
it makes cobblestone
no no cobblestone that's interesting as
kind of expecting it to I guess it
doesn't when it's vertical like that now
I have never made a cobblestone
generator
yeah so that won't be a problem cool one
less thing to worry about so I'm pretty
happy with this design I think it turned
out okay I'm going to work you're
finishing it up add three or four more
layers to it it'll probably take me an
hour to to do that and that will
increase the spawning rates but the best
way of doing that of course is to light
up the Teves within this area and then
spawning rates will continue to increase
but it's working fairly decent I'm happy
actually now that I think of it I did
start building this slime farm not too
long ago you might have seen it if you
downloaded my world let's go check it
out I probably have slimes and it's
better decreasing rates as well for the
other mobs it's down here it's not done
it's just the open area for them to
spawn yeah so the Enderman some people
have said that they might take damage
from water look at this there's a lot
large slide others more above - yeah so
these guys are affecting my spawn rate
Swope yep and it's not lit up fully down
here we got other mobs spawning as well
yeah so Enderman they might take damage
from water I don't know filthy slow
damage buddy
I dare you to slime
I believe the slimes don't go for now
yeah anyway if Enderman take damage
sorry about the interruption
if Enderman take water damage if it's
slow damage from water they might be
able to make it through the water canals
before they die if it's instant death on
touching water then you know there's no
real way of making a mob system form no
good way that if they do fall in the
water that eight block stream I have and
they instantly die their items will fall
in the water and we'll be able to
collect their items from that so either
way we'll be able to collect their items
if they die instant I'm not too worried
about it we'll see what happens and the
batch hits released but yeah we will
call it an end for today thank you for
watching I will see you guys next time