hey hey hey this is evil welcome back to
Minecraft with me I've been struggling
to make videos recently guys I have
family visiting but every now and then I
find little moments in the day where I
can do some recording and this is one of
them and as you can see I finished
refurbishing my EMP wits at my new base
here I got rid of all the sandstone it's
snow now you guys seem to like the snow
which is good because I liked it too I
like the sandstone too but I think the
snow is slightly better since I'm in a
snowy biome and they all function like
the tutorial of the video down open so
we got lava below water I probably
should have done that oh it's fine
and then we have the friar above so
that's good
these were these didn't take too long to
make the first ones took a lot longer
the wiring for the new ones though is a
lot easier to do it's a lot simpler
smaller before the wiring extended right
to the edge here now I have all the
space but I don't have my master
controls set up yet and I'll probably
wait until I actually get these working
like with mobs and before I set up the
master controls just in case I need to
change things again I don't want make
extra work for myself
but yeah these these are working pretty
good a few of my viewers have found ways
to make these EMP units smaller one
suggestion was to change the wiring like
this have a repeater below I think
before I had I had the wiring extend out
one with the repeater and then another
wire like that but you can have the same
effect by having the repeater underneath
the block so let's save space so thanks
Deborah on that point at that out and
there's a few other changes people have
made to make it better but I'm gonna
stick with my clunkier model here works
pretty good some people didn't like the
plus sign for the glowstone I'm gonna
keep it though because I like it a few
people said just to have three vertical
little stone blocks but I'm gonna keep
the glowstone just because it's my
preference and most of you said to use
glass instead of fences and that's the
definitely a good idea to in this case I
think it looks better
just because it's easier to see through
the glass in this case Oh Dean I'm gonna
have to redo all this floor I think
though cuz right now it's just a mess
since I've changed how I'm gonna do this
I have to change the floor
so I'm guessing I'll rip this whole
floor out drop it down three blocks or
so and then fill it with ice and then
build it up from that instead of trying
to make ice baths again and I'll have a
covering over the top of these things
somehow to make it more uniform so you
can't see this junk this piston here and
that all I want to be able to see is the
glass tubes above in the end and I
haven't started the spider one yet I'm
gonna wait on doing that as well a lot
of people have shown how to do it and I
I have a good idea how to do it too but
I'm gonna wait until I know everything's
finalized before I attempt to tackle it
just because it'll take a little bit of
time to figure it out I think uh-huh
anyway this is going good people were
wondering if snow blocks melt - no they
don't
ice melts and snow like this where it's
just over top of a of a block that will
melt but solid snow blocks do not melt
and I know that doesn't make much sense
but that's just the way it is
so you guys have been great to helping
me pick out my color scheme so far it's
not something I'm very good at and your
suggestions help me out a lot so I'm
gonna rely on you some more here one
thing I know is I'm gonna be using snow
a lot probably glowstone a lot ice a lot
but we need to add some more colors
otherwise it's gonna look really plain
oh it's snowing beautiful snow it's
gonna look really plain if everything is
just white and now it's really dark so
we need to skip ahead today this is what
it looks like underneath here now it's
pretty messy sleep it is night go to
sleep sleep alright here we go come on
come on what a sleep or is it daytime
still maybe the snow just made it dark
that's probably what it was all right
well I'm gonna skip ahead then okay back
to the color schemes so colors I'm
thinking of using our possibly this blue
I think it kind of goes good with snow
there's this blue as well I kind of go
good together I think and with ice I'll
probably use some of that also I think
black hole will look pretty sharp with
snow oh yeah in case you didn't know
this using shears is a lot faster way of
picking up wool blocks so normally takes
that long with shears it's almost
instant just in case you didn't know
I may also like try greens reds I like
the purple you know pretty much anything
goes with white really but let me know
what you guys think I'm not entirely I'm
not entirely sure what I'm gonna do for
colors so give me your ideas and I will
probably follow them so when I started
this base here I was expecting it to
come together pretty quick but it's
taking a long time to build stuff as it
turns out there's a lot of work to it
really the next step in building my plan
here is to redo the flooring which I'll
hopefully get to this episode and then
after that we get to do some fun stuff
for you to build the passive mob
spawning pads and also the hostile mob
spawning pads the reason why I can't
start the hostile spawning pad yet is
because I have lots of cave systems to
explore yet before they will be
effective and the reason why I don't
have a ton of animals spawning on this
grass patch there is because of this
island here or this landmass so I left
up to a vote with you guys should I
clear the grass or should I blow it up
and surprise surprise you guys said to
blow it up so that's what we're gonna do
not this episode it will take a while to
set up I did not think I had enough TNT
to do it yet but apparently I do one of
my viewers kindly pointed out that I
have six stacks of TNT in my by my
nether cannon the 361 so we're good to
go yep
maybe I'll start working on this a
little bit today so I have this
cobblestone barrier drawing a line of
what I need to get rid of it goes all
the way along here so I think what I'm
gonna do is just dig down one block and
dig out one wide block marker for my
entire land mass here that's how I'll
know where to stop digging
when I'm underground I'll run into this
hollow hollow spots so I'm gonna do that
right now so the marker is dug now it's
just one wide so when I'm digging
tunnels underground to lay the TNT
charges I'm gonna come to this opening
and that's how I'm gonna know when to
stop digging otherwise I'll just keep
digging further and further in this
direction and wasting time so I'll come
to this opening a little to stop and
I'll stop and just digging this one wide
gap all through the islands or
landmass took between five and ten
minutes so we have to use TNT there's no
way I can dig out all this land it would
take way too long if one one block whit
takes that long so we're gonna use TNT
and it just goes all the way through so
I gotta get rid of everything to the
right and any low stuff I'll use a
shovel on like stuff like that I don't
need to blow up but anything thick like
this needs TNT
so maybe we'll start laying maybe we'll
start doing a little bit of tunneling
okay so I'm just quickly going to show
you the method I plan on using to your
to this island so what I'll do is I'll
just dig a tunnel like this
I'll dig it all the way through until I
reach that opening one wide gap that I
just dug and I'll AT&T charges and
that's then two blocks over there'll be
another tunnel that goes all the way to
the end anywhere there's a stone ground
like this I'm fine but if I run into
dirt like like this I might need to
replace it with cobblestone so that I
get a clean explosion otherwise it's
gonna make a deep hole so I do that and
then let's see what would it be I would
go two blocks up there would be another
tunnel here and I'll go all the way to
the opening and two blocks over same
thing so basically each hint TNT tunnel
I dig here is gonna blow out a three by
four high area so that's how it's gonna
work
so another tunnel will go here and then
I'd lay all the TNT and somehow try to
activate oh did I do that wrong yeah
this one's supposed to be one block
lower yeah made a mistake there anyway
that's the plant so I do that all the
way
cross the island place all the TNT
probably hundreds and hundreds of TNT
and then it'll all blow up somehow there
we go so I marked the position of all
the tunnels or at least a lot of the
tunnels I still need a few more marked
they don't go all the way through yet
I'll have to do that later sometime
they'll take a bit of time but that's
those are all the tunnels I need to dig
out to that one wide gap we made all
along here need to line them with TNT
and then I plan on detonating that's
from the top down hopefully I think will
work best and somehow I'll hook them all
together
maybe with fire I might make like a fire
a wick for the fire to follow or
something like that okay the other thing
I need to do is cut down these trees no
problem there nice and easy with yet so
high check that out there's a mushroom
on that tree pretty rare to see that
yeah so I'm not gonna make you watch me
cut down all these trees but that's what
I need to do and then I'll collect the
saplings and that's one less thing I
need to do before we can blow up this
island
okay I just finished there were a lot of
trees actually took a while but as you
can see this land is as barren as your
mom nothing left no more trees except
that our cobblestone barrier there this
is what I got one two three four five
about six stacks of wood and something
that's kind of confusing me is I blew
through about one and a half iron axes
cutting down all those trees I'm pretty
sure and like in my normal regular wood
tree farm I will collect about two and a
half stacks of wood with one iron axe so
assuming that's right something is wrong
here I'm have a theory that collecting
this dark wood doesn't use your axe up
as much as collecting regular wood but I
don't want to start any rumors about
that maybe someone will research it and
let us know in the comments and if
nobody does I'll probably do it myself
so I'm going to keep prepping that
Island for its destruction and maybe
hopefully next episode we'll blow it up
or maybe two episodes or something from
now whenever it gets done but let's
let's get back to this floor here so
originally I was gonna have the openings
set up like this there's Pistons one
piston underneath this half slab here
and I was gonna open the block something
like that so that when the water comes
out it'll flow to this hole spreading
everywhere but I have been shown a
cooler way of doing this now by Haan s
ihe I believe his name is pronounced
hand SIA possibly he came up with this
little design here which is very very
cool so we have three sticky pistons
here two going this way and one going up
and when this is activated this block
here goes over one and up one and when
you flip it back it retracts so that is
very very cool and you have to send
power to this block here it lights it
activates this repeater which is set to
two activates this block and this
redstone above so this is gonna work a
lot better for the floor hopefully
because for for example we're gonna make
this our pretend floor so when it's
closed the ground will be completely
flat and when it's open we'll have a
nice hole that the water and items will
flow down so should work out pretty nice
it's a lot better than having the half
slabs sticking out of the ground
so this is what I plan on using so
unfortunately to use that new design I
need to rip out this floor which kind of
sucks because I spent a bit of time on
our a bit of time on it already mostly
on setting up these canals these with
the ice underneath
I'm gonna have to make a new ice layer
three blocks below this one so yeah that
kind of sucks but it's worth it so I
gotta get rid of all these stuff
all these snow blocks all the water
broke I should probably have gotten rid
of the water first and when I do that
I'll be back so this is where we're at
now I got rid of all that junk under the
ice and I made a new molding filled it
with water so when this ice is gone this
water will freeze and we'll have a new
layer of ice underneath here so I got
that all done now the top layer of ice
is gone we have a newly formed lower
layer here and I play soil blocks
everywhere that I need the collection
point to be that's what these are
marking and now need to try make and
sighs I guess he didn't really give it a
name but his setup thing I need to try
get that working so I think this is how
he had it and then there's gonna be two
blocks and a repeater between so just
like this maybe get rid of ice
and let's see how to do this thing I
think there is that there and a repeater
- and I'm just going to use a lever for
now just to test this yeah that looks
good
okay
so we got that but we also need to set
up water streams to order this and the
problem with that is I can't just place
a water block here because when the
piston moves its gonna destroy that
water block so I'm gonna put a water
block here instead be something like
this see let's close this the water will
be here I'll make it flow out
so flow out and then maybe make it flow
a little bit more and have a wall here
it'll be like a sign here let's put our
lever back where it belongs so when this
is up that won't freeze this will be
covered while that froze fast
yeah and that's up the water block will
be like this when it's down it'll flow
out when the items fall the items will
be come to that point they're fall and
then they'll slide out here and then
I'll just have like one main water
stream here going this way all the way
to the end and so the items will flow
like this I'll go around and this will
shoot them out
yeah hope that makes sense all right so
I think I know what I'm gonna do here
the only thing I need to figure out is
how to run a wire to this block here
from from the second lever this one here
so maybe we'll say that for another day
this episodes being long beautiful
sunsets and so this floor is gonna be
replaced by something probably something
different than ice help figure out
pattern hopefully that looks cool
maybe with wool blocks of different
colors and hopefully it'll be good if
you have ideas let me know and I'm going
to say goodbye thank you for watching
until next time