hello everyone thank you for joining me
once again as I play Minecraft today
first I want to show you is the mob
system is up and running again just
great so I'll be able to collect
gunpowder again I pretty much ran out of
TNT so good that I can resupply in my
stash again been doing a little bit of
work over here
we finally have a door here before it
was just a dirt wall which was pretty
nasty looking now we had sliding doors
and it's unfinished out here still but
we have doors we were pretty cool they
seem to lag my game a bit though when I
asked to beat them you might have to
replace the glowstone with the some
other solid block that doesn't change
the lighting and I'll just quickly show
you the wiring for this it's pretty
simple so you have two Pistons two
sticky pistons on both sides that are
extended by default she's being powered
by this wire here so it goes it's
pointing at this one here and it's also
a block above this one so that's why
they're both game powered at the same
time hopefully I can do this without
wrecking all the wiring
so there's a torch directly below this
wire and the door the sliding doors
above here above these two sandstone
blocks are the wooden pressure plates
and above this wood block here is one of
the buttons above this one is the other
button and directly below them are these
wires which come down and join together
here and pressure plates above here also
power the same wire here move like and
these go to repeaters which are set at 3
right now and change it to whatever I
want and they go to the torches on both
sides here that's how that works if I
want pressure plates on the other side I
could just get rid of these blocks here
but wiring down get rid of these and
that would work if I didn't want to use
but you know so these are very simple to
wire
very simple okay so I'm gonna put that
back to normal and then we'll continue
on with the new changes okay I'll just
leave the buttons like that Steph having
them on the outside here the reason I
have those repeaters set to three torch
delays instead of just one is so that
usually when I push these buttons I'm a
few blocks away from this door and I
don't want it closing before I get to it
so I don't want it cutting me in half
basically that gives me time to walk
through without it shutting so that's
important and of course I'll dress this
up a little bit on the outside make it
look nice as I find the time and the
desire
now the other big change is I have a
piston elevator now to get up and down
I'll just get up from my mob system to
get down go down here water break and
you down pretty simple not too many mobs
in there right now let's see and to get
up you go down here you probably saw
this thank you to the top so it's pretty
nice you can actually make those go
faster if you hold shift when you're
riding it but you know I like like the
cleaner
feel of just walking it okay so what
else is new
well I've added these lights in to my
mob system here I had it figured out so
that everything behind this glass is
light level 7 or less and everything on
this side is above light level 7 light
level 7 is what mobs need hostile mobs
need to spawn so that would make it so
no mobs will spawn in here and mobs be
able to spawn out there the problem
though I was doing some tests actually
recording an episode that I deleted
because it was very long and boring and
I was just doing mob science tests the
whole time but what I figured out in
that episode I'll share with you first
of all it's always been my understanding
that's
as long as the ground is at light level
seven or less so from zero one two three
four five six seven all the way there
that mobs would have an equal chance of
say spawning on ground at light level
zero compared with flight level seven I
thought it was equal because I was under
the belief that not removed that check
in the code and one of the patches a few
months ago but apparently that isn't the
case I did a bunch of tests in the
little deleted episode basically I
covered one of these spawn pads this one
here I put a wall all around it got rid
of these lights so it was completely
dark in there and on this pad here I had
it set to about light level five so this
was light level zero that was light
level five both of them could spawn mobs
and what I did is I went over here and I
did a bunch of checks basically I would
go to peaceful and then I'd switch it to
easy and I would count how many times
mobs spawned in the completely dark room
compared to the how many times they
spawned in the partially dark room and
it was something like I did a bunch of
tests I think it was like twenty twenty
one mob sets a mob spawned in the dark
room compared to it was about five sets
of mobs spawned in the partially dark
room so if it was even then it would
make no difference the light level but
since so many more spawned in the
completely dark room that tells me that
light levels do matter
so it's very important to keep in mind
if you have a mob system I don't in my
tutorial I said you could put up
redstone torches if you did that get rid
of them because they're lowering your
spawn rate okay also with my thing here
I'm gonna have to revoke these lights
because they're the pads over here are
at light level 7 and it kind of feeds as
it goes back but ideally I want these at
light level 0 everything behind the
glass light level 0 so I'll have to rip
out these lights I'll probably put half
slabs on the ground here so mobs won't
spawn in here and yeah so keep those
changes in mind let's see what else what
else
one other test I did is I covered one
spawning pad completely with pressure
plates and mobs were still able to spawn
on it so yes mobs can spawn on pressure
plates I also tried redstone they can
spawn on redstone dust anyway that's
what I tried I did another test where I
had a spawning pad and closed one I
built basically it was closed like this
it wasn't a 2 by 2 pad it was this
enclosed 7 by 7 next to it I also had a
seven by seven enclosed spawning pad
except one of them was 2 blocks high and
the other one was 9 blocks I and I
wanted to see if the amount of air space
you had above a pad made a difference on
the spawning rates and what I found out
after about 20 tests 10 spawned in the
two high 110 10 sets of mobs and 10
spawned in the
9 I won so since those were equal it
makes no difference how much airspace
you have above your spawning Pat says
just as long as you have 2 blocks of air
for them to spawn is what you need
unless your spawning spiders roboticus
found out that if you have an airspace
and a glass block above or some other
translucent block like that then a
spider could spawn on that cobblestone
there and no other tall mobs will so
that's how you can make a spawning pad
that only spawns spiders and not hostile
mob not the I'm really rambling today
you can make a spider only spawner of
doing that so that's cool I might end up
doing that at the eye space some other
things that the switch is here that
one's for the lighting that's which is
pretty quick it's good this one's for
spider options I think I showed that
already maybe I will show you one thing
I got bed on the side at chess crafting
table furnace basic necessities yeah I
wanted to show for sure that spiders
will spawn in here when those half slabs
are down because I still have people
telling me that they won't and it's kind
of annoying me a few mobs in there
if you look at the e that's entities
actually nevermind I won't talk about
that right now
look I'll switch let's go out here like
men first thing we see is a spider and I
don't even have a world back up
that's how free so yes babies do spawn
letting up half slabs are down and when
the lights are on
no mobs seem to spawn in here which is
good
no mobs are spawning so the lighting is
working great yeah
e is for entities right now I have one
hundred and eighty-four eighty-five
eighty-six so I mobs count as entities
in the scheme as well as items see it
keeps going up as I throw these items
more entities you have the more legging
in your game will be unfortunately yeah
so even though I have pretty much all
the caves lit up around me look at the
entities we have a hundred and
seventy-three right now
174 if we switched the peaceful
automatically went down to I think one
will eat so there was still 70 hostile
mobs somewhere in my world in caves so
even though I have pretty much all the
tapes lit up there is still some places
for them to spawn oh I just was tonight
oh ok nevermind let's well it's same
piece they were spawning on the surface
price watches entities keep going up and
up as they find places for them to spawn
139 140 145 150 - it takes a long time
for it to find places for the mobs to go
but eventually it will fill all the mob
spots so the rate actually that's one
way you can figure out how many caves
you have left light up is by the speed
that your entities fill up during the
day
so for me it's pretty slow try it for
yourself
and if it takes if it doesn't take very
long that means you have lots of kids to
light up yet anyway
I think we should move on okay check
this out like right next to here I see
there's a mob so there's probably a
little tiny dark room just enough for
the mob to spawned you know it's not in
a main cave system probably just a
little tiny dirt room that you would
never find unless you heard a mob in it
or saw a mob using f3o
it was actually a place I've been before
but I didn't fully light it up so make
sure when you're lighting up your caves
do a good job I probably just missed
this little section here
I'd like to get rid of gravel when I see
it just cuz usually at the top of it
there's dark spots so if you get rid of
it the grounds flat here it's easy to
light up flat ground and I see if we
looked at again at our either it when it
says 0 / 182 any entities that it's
drying on our screen counts as a number
at the first start there right now I'm
looking at 14 mobs in the distance 13 1
dusty spawned 12 so I got a bunch of
mobs in front of me right now
a bunch of cave systems I need to light
up over there so that's another way of
finding mobs if you can't really see
them a few if you move your mouse around
it'll tell you if you're looking at any
even if you can't see the label that far
away right now I'm looking at 13 yeah I
see them down there
oh wow
what's going on here this is a really
dark area see I thought I lit all this
stuff up but there's still more to do
anyway moving on moving on you get the
point okay so after further
investigating yes we're still talking
about this seems a lot of those mobs I
saw were actually wild slimes so there's
a ton down here
so something to keep in mind these guys
are taking up possible spots for your
hostile mobs to spawn went in mob spots
I mean so if the tap is set any hostile
mobs I don't know if that's the Cabot's
it's around 70 though I know let's say
70 if the cap is 70 if I have 20 slimes
down here then only 50 like creepers in
that are going to be able to spawn on my
spawning pads at a time so you need to
get rid of these slimes unfortunately
slimes they spawn at any light levels so
the only way you can keep these wild
slimes responding is to use that slime
finder program and then lay down half
slabs
and the chunks where you don't have
slime farms around the area and that's
how you can keep wild slimes from
stealing your mob spots okay okay so I
did miss this the first time I saw it
but when I was rewatching the video I
noticed it as I'm sure you did too
you are now gonna believe this this is
crazy
such a crazy patch oh yeah ah that's
crazy oh my goodness
they've been multiplying for who knows
how long
Wow
yeah that's send very strange so it
seems like they can go anywhere
ask the light level 14 at the torch 13
here 12 or less is where they're
multiplying to just crazy on top of the
furnace on top of the drafting table mmm
I gotta get chest down there and there's
stuff in it no way that's been there for
a while more slimes yes I'm gonna use
that slime program to find all their
chunks and put half slabs down so that
they can't spawn where I don't want them
to and I'll link it in the description
if I remember hopefully I do if you want
to do it yourself in your world as well
and you only have to keep them from
spawning below level 16 for the
y-coordinate
that's not a slime that's something else
hey awesome guarding his precious
diamond nice try nice try that wasn't
born yesterday okay I'm out of arrows I
don't even use a sword anymore I find it
I find the axe works just as well oh
yeah there's a big dark cave here so I'm
gonna have to light this all up after we
get my diamonds and there's a creeper
around here I think so I got to be
careful
anyway I know you guys don't like
watching me spelunking so I will meet
you back at the surface that's a good
thing I stopped there this episode's
getting really long already so we're
gonna try wrap it up here this is what I
got by the way got about status slimes I
think I only got one stack of redstone
stack of iron and then some some gold
two diamonds so that was pretty good but
most importantly we lit up the caves
that were lowering the efficiency of my
mob system okay so quickly few other
things this minecart thing is done okay
I ripped out all the wiring because I
needed it and also on you know I'm I
never use it so why bother when it's
running it likes the game a lot so I
don't want I don't want that huge like
spikes so what I'm just gonna do is I'm
gonna loop this will have one minecart
going around all the time and I will
cover up these holes I'll finish ripping
out the tracks and that will be done and
we'll actually be able to use this
hopefully they'll just be going around a
loop I may try add a few see if they
merge together or not in here's we won't
need these controls anymore if I do that
so I plan on maybe putting like one of
these water column things you walk in
and you can swim up to the mob pads
maybe because right now I don't have any
good way of getting to the mob pads
another thing I want to say thank you to
Nana
1:31 he sent me some pictures showing me
how I can improve the item despawn timer
and actually a lot of people have
suggesting how I could improve it lately
so thank you everyone that did basically
I changed it before I had the five clock
running all the time
five clocks used to make the lights
flash and now it they're only flashing
five clocks only running when I need the
lights to be flashing so instead of it
being all the times just when I need
them flashing so that'll lower the leg
in my world a little bit which is always
good okay so my car tracks the spawn
timer
and I think that's it so thank you for
watching everybody and hopefully I got
stop saying and all the time hopefully
next episode we'll start working on the
ice space the the poof mob spawning pads
and stuff okay
hopefully if you guys are up for that or
if you want me to do something else let
me know if you guys are getting sick of
me working on mob stuff all the time I
will do something else for an episode or
so okay bye bye