I know what am i doing wasting all those
arrows well I can now because the mop
systems up and running so I've extended
it it's now four layers stacked on top
of each other each layer has four pads
each pad is 32 blocks of spawning space
that comes to a total of 32 times 4
times 4 512 spawning spots inside that
giant cube like box so how does it
perform ah so-so
if you look at your entity thing at the
top over here the first number tells you
how many entities you're looking at so a
mob counts as an entity and I am only
looking at 16 15 14 13 inside of this
cube so could be better but actually
this rate right now is probably better
than my old mob system so I'm looking
forward to maxing this thing out I think
it'll be pretty good so it on average
I'd say it does about 20 to 30 mobs
right now it's a little slower for some
reason probably have slimes down below
again so the mob limits is I believe 79
that means we can make this thing about
4 times faster at max capacity using
this design up in the sky so should be
pretty cool when I get master
yeah but lots and lots of resources to
build it that's kind of why I recommend
that original style just because it
requires so many resources to build it
in the sky like this I've used I think 2
or 2 but 2 double chests cobblestone I
think to build this thing four layers
only and I need to make it I think two
or three times larger yet I believe is
what I'm going to do so it's a lot
easier to build them underground it's
faster build them underground
and you gain resources building them
underground and they don't make giant
cubes in your sky if you build them
underground
so there's advantages to both methods
this one obviously more efficient though
yeah I just checked my slime farm here
and it looks like there's tons of guys
down here again and they were
interfering what the numbers I just
showed you normally I have I think
around 30 to 40 mobs spawning in that
giant Tower I just built but when I
showed you is only about 15 to 20 and so
these guys are taking on mob spots that
could be going to this skeletons
creepers zombies etc you need to get rid
of these guys the two mob systems kind
of work together the slime one and the
other hostile one if you want a really
good slime farm you need to constantly
be killing the other hostile mobs
because these guys have a slim chance of
spawning but if you're killing people
and that's quite often then ethic every
time a new mob spawns there's a slim
chance it will be a slime and you're
just increasing the number of times that
dice roll occurs so you will get more
slimes if you're killing other mobs
quickly that's why my slime firms
filling up so fast now but also if you
want a good hostile mob system you need
a slime farm that you can shut off so I
need some way of letting my slime pads
when I get this thing finished but
otherwise you're going to keep
interfering with my numbers like they
happen
hehehe
yeah there's a lot of slimes down there
I did a test and I uh after I killed
them I let that run for another minute
or two then I went back down and there's
about another ten slimes down there so
they're definitely spawning quickly with
that thing running but I just killed
them all again and now this thing should
be running little bit better course it
is slightly random 17 20 30 - so if
there's no mobs or no slimes I should
say then this thing will handle about 30
mobs at a time since the limit is 80 we
want it up to 80 so this will be 2 to 3
times faster than it is right now which
would be awesome but to get that we
neither we either need to make this
bigger I'm thinking either expanding it
or making 2 or 3 of them but before I
think of doing that I'm going to make a
strong effort to light up every single
cave in the area and those are pretty
easy to find if you use f3 like just
looking at the ground there's two mobs
below me somewhere in caves if you look
at the an identity thing at the top left
there 3 mom's 7 mom's 10 mom's so if you
wander around your perimeter here try to
even though you can't see the tags
necessarily on the mobs you the game
will pick them up at your entity thing
here so it's kind of like radar to moms
it's pretty good 3 4 so I would try to
find a high concentration of them and
then then dig down there
I think I saw some actually really close
to the surface here before let's check
if let's check if they're there again
ten eleven so this is a pretty bad spot
near here and right below here I saw
some four five don't really see any
right now but I know there was some so
let's go check it out
this is how we did you know shion's yeah
there's there's a bunch over there
digging down is cool
Wow there's a big cheat where they're
directly below my base let's go check it
out to see what's going on so I got to
find all these tubes that are hidden
light them up and then I will get many
more mobs in my mob system iron you can
hear them the tedious process though
lighting up all the caves but usually
when you do it to get tons of resources
so you know I never just over resource
hunting or anything like that there's
always I'm always doing two things at
once I'm I'm lighting up caves and
getting resources and having fun
exploring underground so kind of like
multitasking I know that's not really
what multitasking is whoa
of course I don't have any armor on me
or anything or food so might be
switching to peaceful here wasn't really
planning to go keep stuff creepy they're
just watching me oh yeah I'm going to do
it ah dang so yes is not a huge key but
you saw how many moms were in here in
such a small cave as you decrease the
number of spots where they can spawn
their concentrations will get higher in
smaller areas and we can hear there's
more Teebs near here so let's go check
it out this is a stuff I usually do
off-camera but try something a little
different today just for a brief little
while
another small cave nothing major
probably would never find it without
using f3 I'm worried that feature soon
be gone soon I use it a lot you so light
up the caves don't be stingy with the
torches or you'll regret it later make
sure you have it light enough run
through here at pretty small cave and I
can see there's four more mobs down
there very close and I think I saw some
more somewhere over there so I'll do a
little bit lighting here and I will meet
you back at the surface and just a
little sec a little while okay so we're
back up here I thought it'd be good to
take you up to the tower up close and
personal
I'll show you a little problem I have
now pretty big Tower yes here we are
this is the top this is how you can get
down so maybe I'll point out one thing
first a lot of people were concerned
that mobs are going to walk into these
water columns and then drown or get
stuck or something doesn't happen these
are considered drops so mobs don't walk
off these things unless they're pushed
and even if they are it happens very
rare and they drown if it does happen I
haven't really I think only saw it
happen once
it's very rare it's not a problem so
don't worry about that we're at the top
here we're at y-coordinate 124 basically
the top of the world and that presents
my next problem
this final layer I put on is pretty
close to the top we only have one two
three four can we place four blocks down
yet before we reach the top of the map
and I need to build my spider shut off
thing using water and also my lighting
system using lava so I got to get water
and labo down these oops these four
holes here and that's a real challenge
because we're at the top of the map and
we have pretty much no working room so
yeah I'm a little not really sure what
to do so if I dump water here it'll go
to three of the holes that's the thing I
kind of need to put another layer on the
top so light doesn't get down in and
interfere because if this isn't covered
directly above these holes light will
get down here and then they'll light up
the the pads and it will we won't be
able to shut we won't be able to make it
completely dark down there so kind of
kind of troubling the other thing is if
I pour lava in there I brought some lava
I have that problem where it won't
disappear takes forever
because it goes horizontally like that
and now if I remove it this this lava
pile here won't disappear for a long
time so it is a problem after all so I
need to figure something out here
the main annoyance I have with this
design is it's based off of even numbers
so I put water here it only flows to one
hole same here so there's no real good
trick to making it go to all four holes
since it's an even number but if it
would like this is a base for thing here
if it was base five I could just put in
the center and it would go to all four
holes no problem hmm so I don't know
what to do I've just been messing around
with a few ideas this one is a
possibility it's not perfect it is
within one to three blocks like I need
it to be if I flick the sleeper here
water will go to three of the holes and
then this one here would cause Labbit to
go to the other three like that the only
problem of course is lava takes oops
let's well there's two problems that's
another problem can't have them both
going at the same time or you'll produce
cobblestone the other problem is the
lava takes a while to disappear
so I don't know I'm trying to avoid
having to use two pistons for each hole
but it might not be possible at two
piston per whole idea would probably
work something like this have water and
lava piston fuel down water goes down
the hole switch it off
lap it goes down but again the problem
is there would be a lot of wiring there
would be a lot of Pistons kind of sucked
the build and you probably have the
issue where they both can't be on at the
same time lap is on and you got a
cobblestone generator so yeah not the
best idea
oh man I was just about to give up on
the idea of having a lighting system I
decided to give it one more shot and I
found something that works really well
and does everything I wanted to it's
still within the three block height
boundary I'm limited limited to here it
has a spider option and a lighting
option and uses only two Pistons per 4
holes so it's pretty good let's check it
out first of all water water is in there
and this is how it flows down goes to
that hole this one and this one and this
one so all four it's really good now
shuts off quick
see disappearing down there and we have
the lighting option there's labid
directly above so it flows down only one
hole it's a vertical column so it will
disappear quickly when we shut it off
and here's the real beauty since it's a
vertical thing it'll cut through water
so if we turn it on when the water is
still on doesn't matter
coming down pretty cool now there is one
slight problem with this still the very
slight problem if we have lava here then
it doesn't fully light up one of these
pads because this is light level 15
there 13 11 9 and 7 in the very corner
one mobs can spawn on light level 7 even
though it's not common the darker it is
the more likely there to spawn it is
possible though so I don't know I don't
think it's going to be a big enough
issue that it concerns me I think it'll
be ok even though it is possible for
them to spawn still it would be
extremely rare I hope because there's
only 4 blocks per layer four layers 16
16 blocks will be at light level 7 in
this whole thing and the water kind of
waits for the Labbit to disappear
kind of interesting how water does this
it doesn't spill out all over the place
it stays in a column that's kind of cool
so I think this is what I'm going to do
it's the best way but please if you have
a better idea send me a video response
or something and I will maybe use your
ID instead because this one's not
perfect it's the best one I found but
it's not perfect I just made one more
refinement to it too
I was using a regular piston before then
I realized that the lava the light from
lava above could reach down to the
spawning pads below so now I'm using a
sticky piston with a solid block under
the lava so it will be completely dark
in here
I will probably fill this room with half
slabs or something because otherwise
light would be able to go down this hole
onto the pads which would cause problems
so this should work and the wiring is
going to be super simple for this
because it's really close together here
and I don't think I showed you what the
lab is going any turn water on it still
tries to go to that hole that lab is
going down and it won't it won't flow
out this way it'll just kind of wait for
the lab ax to disappear and then when it
does it decides to go so
pretty cool but again if you have a
better idea let me know because I'm
always open for better ideas yep so
that's the plan this is how I'm going to
do it unless someone pitches me
something better and you can see it goes
down to every layer it's cool so now we
have one other thing to figure out I'm
pretty sure I have most of the caves lit
up like the majority of it and it's
still not going to be able to keep up at
this size so I might need to make two of
these possibly three and then hook them
together so let's not take up a lot of
space really and a lot of resources yep
anyway that's it for today thank you for
watching let me know any suggestions you
have and I will see you again next time
take care bye bye