Hey ladies thanks for joining me again
this is the ESL and we're going to get
right into it first new change I've
added a musical note blocks to our timer
here plays a nice Zelda theme when you
pick up the items or if the feather de
spawns
and let's go check it out I hate coming
down here because it's a real mess what
I did this is the wire from the pressure
plate cut the feather lands on so it
sends a signal here to the five o'clock
and stuff and I added this torch on the
other side can't really get to I don't
know if there's any way down actually
oh ouch
okay and that wire that's the torch over
there and wire down to these repeaters
and of these is the musical note blocks
I a button here to test it out but it's
on right now I got it
inverted the signal so that when the
feather disappears the these torches
come on and play the notes and there's
only eight notes so thanks to four schl
a b ACH i think it's a force club back
or something i don't know how to say his
name for posting a video response in
episode 19 on how to make this simple
little tune and thanks to everyone else
that these suggestions on tunes I went
with his because he made a video for he
told me exactly how to do it that's
pretty cool and it didn't take up too
much space which is nice alright next
thing when having trouble loading videos
to YouTube they keep failing
I got your inputs kind of on these what
I should do here I'll probably just make
these all signs and I'll probably get
rid of the glass I'm not sure yet
but we're not going to focus on that
this video instead we're going to be
working up here and so I came to a
realization I can't what I wanted to do
was make a mop sorter here sort the mobs
and mine carts and then if I wanted to
send them somewhere I would pull a lever
and it would send say 50 creepers
somewhere and then I would hop onto my
carts and head to that destination - the
problem is I don't know how I overlooked
this but as soon as the mobs go 144
blocks away from you they pretty much
instantly respawn so that is not going
to work at all I can be anywhere within
144 blocks of them and they'll be fine
I did a test before and they'll stay in
mine carts for a few minutes without the
spawning even if you're outside of the
32 block range but the only way to
actually send them somewhere is if I
escort them and send them all at the
exact same time so yeah kind of an issue
we're going to go the peaceful just so
that there's no issues here so the
reason I'm building this or was going to
build a mob sorter I still might just
for the kicks of it but at the moment
I'm not going to the reason I wanted to
do it was for two specific reasons one
of them was what we're going to build
here today I'll get into that asset and
another one was for I mentioned I was
going to do a big project soon and I
never said what that is and I'm still
not going to but it wasn't the storage
room that I was talking about there I
have another big project I want to do
that requires sorting mobs but we'll
worry about that another day today what
we're doing is we're trying to make Oh
trying to make an automatic record
producer so if a skeleton kills a
creeper he drops a record and we want to
automate that somehow so that's what
this thing is for I'm not sure how
exactly I'm going to build it yet but I
have a good idea and I wanted to sort
the mob so that only creepers would go
in one spot and skeletons in another but
I've realized that I don't really need
to sort them it actually be faster not
to them not to sort them that
I feel like I'm slurring my words today
so what we are going to do that's kind
of late the base here to make things
faster this is an item collection area
okay so I have a mob Junction here I've
hooked a lever up to this corner block
so that when you flick it it switches
both doors at once because one of the
doors is reversed from the other so we
have a junction there and there goes our
timer and there's going to be another
Junction here and through this path it's
going to send we're most concerned about
we mostly want creepers to come through
here
down this path here and through this
path where you're going to try get
skeletons okay so we have a five by five
area here I probably won't be able to
finish this this episode but hopefully
I'll get most of it done sometimes it
does that if a big jumps on the pressure
plate won't be an issue once I get
everything closed off
okay so we got four water sources in
every corner which is going to bring the
mops to the center okay this is where
the creepers are going to be then two
blocks away this is where the skeletons
are going to be and in between this is
where I'm going to be so Skelton will be
there he'll try shoot at me and he'll
hit the creeper and creepers will die
and drop records which will get fall
into this hole in the middle and get
sent out hopefully
but since the mobs aren't sorted there's
also going to be zombies in here which
is not an issue I'm mostly concerned
about having other skeletons in here
because skeletons over here are going to
get into fights with the skeletons in
the middle and skeletons in the middle
in the middle might also shoot creepers
by accident which will cause the
creepers to explode so might be a few
issues
okay
I've never made a junction quite like
this one in my and all my other mob
junctions the mobs come up from
underneath this one they're coming in
from the side so be a little bit more
tricky to make I'm also running very
little on glass so one of these episodes
we're going to have to go look for a
desert somewhere so we also need cactus
Jay please sign there
I'm going to build some of this off
camera because this is going to get
tricky then I'll show you after so I'll
be back in a sec okay you guys knit this
much I think I figured out a way of
doing it so I got a sign here and a sign
here and I'm going to put a sign here so
the issue is we have to make that
diagnosed stream of water
it's best if it's the same if it if it's
at this window part of the door so we're
going to make a hole here we're going to
put water in there to water there and I
think we have a dial screen now that
points towards the doors okay good then
put some ladders just for now and maybe
some torches around
okay so then whoops the other thing I
did get some more water
the mobs come into the junction like
this and most of them are going to go
this way we got our diagonal screen and
there's a sign above then there's the
door and there's a sign and a pressure
plate and I got a sign on a sign here so
if we place water here there's no the
apps for the mobs get stuck in and I'm
going to test it out like I'm oh oh wait
no I can't test it out like I'm a mob so
a mob will come to this point then
they'll jump
oh no I should stork jump without
touching the arrow jeez this is what
happens to me I get sent to this point
which is what we want okay so we can
cover this up the mobs are in water so
they're not going to get burnt by the
Sun and there's also going to be a third
story eventually probably okay so we
need a water stream that comes up to
this point I might make a gap game I put
the water here plate there we want the
water above the door
I'm going to make a few more signs here
I think I got to be careful not to go
over about 20 minutes in my videos now
because it says causing any issues with
uploading them because I have to use the
advanced the low uploader if my videos
are over 2 gigs which is what seems to
always fail
well that's a door
okay then we place water here
and fills up two blocks and lastly we're
going to put block underneath actually
we might put another side they're
running very low on time now
yeah okay so what's going to happen is
they're going to come up here and
pretend I'm a mob right now I'm swimming
up and not press any arrow keys water
takes me right through here when I get
to this point I'm going to jump and it
works awesome so I'm going to seal this
up and then I'll show some mobs going
through here okay we're ready for our
first test run of this new system didn't
take long to build at all
I added a so it's all closed up now it's
two blocks high so they can't jump which
gets them through a lot faster I added
this side entrance here in case I need
to do maintenance and there's nothing to
hold them so I'm going to be switching
to peaceful very quickly
looks perfect even if a creeper blows up
there shouldn't cause any damage because
he's in water so hopefully it won't be a
big issue the guys fighting each other
and that's the end of our episode thanks
for watching and I'll see you next time