hi everybody this is etho again firstly
I want to say thank you to everybody
that gave me ideas about the wolf and
sheep shearing issue that I've been
pondering about I got a lot of good
information from you guys one thing you
confirm that wolves can attack sheep
through doors when I tried it it didn't
work but I guess it was because the wolf
and the Sheep weren't held into place so
they were bumping each other apart which
was making it so the wolf couldn't reach
the sheep when I tried it but if you
hold them in place
it seems to work
you also confirm that the southwestt
trick works so you could for example
have a wolf here and the Sheep flowing
by and the wolf could attack the sheep
through the corner I think so that's
what this is this is a little mock-up my
idea is I haven't tested to see if this
works or not
but you would have your stream here with
the Wolves if this door is opened
won't forget pushed inside there might
be a dead zone here that's one issue I'm
dealing with at the moment but then the
idea is you would fall down here to a
pressure plate which would close the
store so no more wolves could enter and
as long as he's standing on this
pressure plate that door stays closed
and then this stream is where the cows
and sheep would be and
basically he'll attack the first sheep
that comes by because it's the first one
he should see there might be issues that
there's large clusters of sheep he might
not be able to keep up not really a
concern of mine and what you could do is
have a stream flowing over a sign that
the wool would fall down but the animals
would go over top and then further down
have a killing mechanism to kill the
cows that the leather would fall down
another assign thing and it would so the
wool and the leather would do two
separate paths and any extra sheep that
makes it by the wolf that aren't sheared
will also get killed by a lava things
similar to what I have up there so
that's kind of my current plan I think
that's the best way of doing it this
thing of them attacking through the
doors might work too I don't know
robot accost made a good video on this
I'll link it in the description it has
potential but it has a lot of problems
too
namely dealing with the cows is kind of
an issue but I'm not gonna set this up
yet you guys can go ahead if you want
and let me know if it works and if not I
will do it first about what we're gonna
do is we're gonna work on like I said
improving some of that in efficiencies
of that system so I get my tool belt on
and we're gonna do some demolition I
should probably point this out to
whether I so many of time of comments
but this is like I cut out look at what
I'm gonna do obviously this would be
covered up otherwise the wolf would just
jump out
and attack the sheet so I keep that in
mind okay so one of the things I said I
wanted to do is changes for my 2x2 area
this drop here to a 1x1 because I'm
having issues with mobs getting stuck in
this area here usually it's only two but
it's kind of annoying so I want to get
rid of that we will need to change a few
things here so let's get to work
ideally I want the mobs drop on this
block here so I think we need to build
here then move the door to here mmm it's
getting dark
yeah I'm gonna skip ahead today okay
we're back
I just watched a bunch of wolves die
right in front me like that one more ok
so gonna be ripping this in one
thank you on the street the chicken
separator is going to be moved actually
let's go up there first and map that out
how we want it so like I said before I
can't just have all the streams merge
together so that there's a one-by-one
opening because the mobs will just keep
bumping each other and they won't be
able to fall down it but I do know a
better way of doing it which I figured
out recently so we want it we want them
to fall down this block let's see how to
do this
okay I think we just need like a to drop
please glass there and I guess over over
there
here is some more of these signs
go all the way out there's another
exciting building episodes yeah oh yeah
okay I know what I'm doing here I'm
gonna have this covered this one too and
then we're gonna have a sign over over
here make an air gap my name is legging
and water and water yeah that's what I
wanted you
pretty sure that's all I want to do okay
so now we need to hold back the water
again somehow
what's the best way of doing this
alright time you need a second to think
you're okay so I think I figured it out
I'm gonna place a sign here yeah sign on
it and a sign on that bond over and
another one over here good
so now we have a three-block opening
here the way this works the mob should
not be able to interfere with each other
they kind of will take turns falling
down I'm pretty sure if I was ever to
redo this passive mob system instead of
having like an even number so that it's
a 2x2 area I would make it an odd number
so it's a one by one opening and I would
make like a plus sign like this so I
would add another another one of these
drops over here and another one over
here make a plus sign is how I would do
it and I might like if I ever go ahead
and build another base with another mob
system I might also make it so it's one
y canals instead of two to see how that
works
and I'd problem eight the spawning pads
even smaller okay so let's head back
down let's finish finish this up
chickens
we'll make a new path here I think and
close this one up probably and we'll
make this solid glass and then we can
break all this and I think I have to
leave that I don't want Ward water to
pour down rather Isis finna Rick Linea
Redstone wiring down below alright I
have water here good
so I'm just gonna close this off for now
so I know where it is
place the water for the chicken
separator place water here oh you know
what I need it's not a one by one it's a
to the two white ones so I'm gonna place
glass up here yet and get rid of this
side place glass here
there's just a one hide app there for
the chickens to fit through yeah okay
that should be it just have to fix this
chicken separator since it got moved
over one block it's really confusing to
see through all this glass oh you know
what I think it's actually set up here
yeah okay well that was easy it's glass
there
glass here and it should be about done
good alright that's fixed and it's night
time so we might be able to see it in
action so I'll skip ahead and hopefully
I'll have a big clump of mops here and
we'll see if they fall down okay so this
is gonna be proof that the mop spawning
is still broken in beta a 1.5 - 0 1 as
you can see there is no mobs down here
there's no grass nearby there's only 1
chicken left here that hasn't be spawned
yet because he was within range of me
and there is no passive mob spawning on
my spawning pads so that one chicken is
the only passive mob in my world right
now they're not spawning up here and
this happens with my hostile mob system
sometimes - and this is happening to a
lot of people actually just it almost
seems random but passive mobs will just
completely stop spawning or hostile mobs
will completely stop spawning and I've
had to happen with both of them at the
same time actually so I've been trying
to figure out how to fix it for me what
I found so far is I just need to leave
the area to leave the chunk if you look
at my coordinates
I have a point here I'm sure you see how
X is going down to zero once I hit zero
I'm gonna be in a new chunk and so all I
need to do I think is spend some time
away from that other chunk the chunks
are 512 by 512 so they're pretty big but
if you leave it and you get passive mobs
spawning away from that chunk and D
spawning then it seems to work again for
me that's how I fix the problem just a
nice casual stroll is the officially
dark forest night dodging skills are
very good
and we're just gonna go where there's
some passive mob spawning um some of you
guys know what the deal is with this I
did not trigger it it went off on its
own one day and I just came here and
there was a giant hole in the ground so
I have no idea when it happened but it
was sometime recently I think I left the
door open and I chickened got in and set
off all the TNT yes I'm just going to
spend some time here then we'll head
back and we'll see if acid mobs start
spawning again okay we spent a little
time here so let's head back and
probably five minutes a bunch of passive
mobs spawned once I changed chunks or
regions are called now I guess that 512
by 512 regions so now when I head back
those mobs should be spawn which somehow
seems to fix the problem when they D
spawn so when I head back to my other
chunk or other region here my passive
mob system should work again it might be
a little slow though because I didn't
let too many mobs despawn
and I haven't figured out exactly what
causes the problem but I know a lot of
people are suffering from this and
people just some people have a really
hard time getting mobs to spawn again so
I just suggest walking around away from
your area for a while
any mobs yeah we have mob spawning again
so it works I'll go up there to prove it
it's a really annoying problem I hope
not fixes it unless you did it
intentionally to make mob system stopped
working somehow but it seems like a
strange thing to do in tension
yeah we had mobs again like magic so I
just left the region when I crossed over
the zero boundary for X so I was saying
that chunk before when I should have
been saying region a region is 512 by
512 and you cross regions
every 512 blocks so if you were to walk
this way my Zed is decreasing at 0 it
would be a new region and negative 512
it would be another new region and a
negative a thousand and 24 and you would
cross a new region same if same with X
so that's how you can figure out
if you're in a new region and just need
like if you want hostile mobs to start
working in need to spawn some hostile
mobs and then when you walk away they'll
be spawn whence they are more than 128
blocks away from you little pretty much
instantly despawn and that seems to
somehow allow them to spawn again in the
region that is broken or at least for me
that's how I did it working hopefully it
works for you guys too if you have the
problem it happens to me if I stay in
that region for a long period of time
and killing lots of mobs or it might
because torches I don't know exactly
what causes it but I seem to know how to
fix it so that's good
alright so we're pretty much out of time
so we're gonna end the episode here I
didn't really get a good demonstration
of not working but it quite clearly does
work chickens have been separated and
see they're being losers stuck in the
door here these door junctions don't
work well for small mobs and they have
dead zones and I might work on fixing
this oh because I don't like how mobs
are getting stuck in the doors but yeah
you saw a large number of mobs went
through and they didn't get stuck
anywhere they'd get stuck up there or
down here so that was good
so it must be working but that's it for
today thank you for watching and I'll
see you again next time