some of the beach mom what the heck I'm
sure this was working yesterday I know I
didn't imagine that yeah so this doesn't
work anymore hey everybody check out my
new box or derp it works awesome for one
day cutting-edge technology for one day
and now we're at 1.3 and mob behaviors
got changed and now it doesn't know
anyone but not to fear I think I'll be
able to rebuild it all right so this is
kind of strange mob behavior changed and
remember I told you not to build it this
way what is this don't build it I said
don't build it east west and now North
the South doesn't work or whatever and
now East the West does so I built this
little tunnel thing as a test and before
the mobs used to freeze when they would
see you when you were in this tunnel
alright here's a zombie so before they
used to freeze this is MCU and now
they'll come after you so kind of
interesting
oh and so I thought if I built at East
the West it would work again so that's
exactly what I did
built an exact copy and it doesn't work
either because they freeze when they get
to the first pad there they don't charge
after you and I think the reason is
because it's high off the ground this is
my theory
I think the mobs freeze because they're
pathfinding senses that they're high
above the ground or something and so
they freeze instead of charging so I
think if I place a fake ground under the
sing it'll work but I'll have to try
that later
so I'm a little bummed out this doesn't
work anymore but I'm confident it'll
I'll be able to get it working or
someone else will
the mob still behave the same way
skeletons still the left and creepers
still the left so there's no reason it
won't be possible to get it working
again might have to change a few things
but I'm sure it's possible but other
than that I am actually really psyched
about this new 1.3 patch I think it's
it's probably my favorite patch yet it's
awesome um you guys know I don't use any
mods or anything or embed it or anything
like that but I have been so tempted to
download that better light mod forever
and I was actually going to do it after
the 1.3 patch and then I saw it's
actually included in the 1.3 patch so
that is totally awesome I'm really happy
with that I think it looks great and not
only that we got all these new gadgets
to play around with and yeah I've been
playing around with them a bit and we
should spend some time doing that let's
see let's get out our torches get some
of our redstone repeaters if you guys
don't already know how to make one of
these repeaters it's pretty simple wait
yeah I forgot for a second and I think
that yeah that's how you make a repeater
very interesting little things um let's
see let's get this started
this is one thing I made the light kind
of just flashes on for a brief second
and then it's out not really useful so
one thing I found very useful with these
is you can now make different clocks
that are a lot smaller like before if
you wanted to make a five o'clock you
had to do something like this and it was
huge and I'm building this because we're
going to do a test
so yeah that's about as small as you can
make I'm sure you can make a little bit
smaller but that's about the size I have
a 5 o'clock it's 3 by 5 by 2 um
wait I'm supposed to be on hard and so I
was playing around with this the
smallest 5 o'clock I was able to make
was place your repeater place block in
front torch get to that room
yeah I did reversed and torch behind
burns out at that setting go one more it
also burns out go one more and it works
so I think that's actually one thing I
wanted to check I think yeah so this is
a 2 by 3 way smaller and it's adjustable
too
it's a little bit slower now I think
each of these uh it's got four settings
this repeater thing 1 2 3 4 I think the
1 2 3 4 represents torches and not ticks
so 2 ticks for ticks 6 sticks and a
ticks so I think right now it's actually
a 4 o'clock at the setting
it should be blinking slightly faster
than the five o'clock here yeah it is
so yeah each of these represents a torch
so now it would be a five o'clock that's
four plus the one so now they should be
blinking at the same exact yeah no
difference and so if you want to make it
another if you want to make a slower
clock you'll have to make it a little
bit bigger you can add one their torch
on the back there so now it's a two by
four but we have three of these things
and so that allows us to make up to a
fork a fork lock up to a what is that
four eight twelve thirteen we can make
up to a 13 o'clock and we can make it
bigger if we want to even slower
that's pretty compact I saw on the forum
someone made a gives a one o'clock the
way that works is and sorry if this
doesn't interest you it kind of it
interests me yeah so these are set at
one you place a torch and then remove it
and I think that's one o'clock maybe
it's a two o'clock and that won't burn
out but if you leave the world and come
back it's not it's going to be stopped
so the only way to get it going again I
think is to place a torch and remove it
if you hook up button up to as a reset
it won't work it just gets stuck on
but pretty cool i liking these new
things they're going to make things a
lot simpler for me I want to redesign
the either amps variable timer using
those I'm sure we made a lot smaller now
and let's see I did this I learned
something new to when I was playing
around with these things so if you place
my games get an all-lady here place a
dispenser does nothing if you place a
torch near it starts ticking so if
there's power near it so I didn't notice
but if the dispenser is facing a solid
block and you put something in it it
actually shoots it through the ground
upwards which is interesting I didn't
know that and if you place the block
above that one it like places items into
the ground actually I guess you can pick
them up
and then if you destroy the block they
all kind of pop up like that but yeah
pretty cool stuff so one other thing I
wanted to talk about kind of a delicate
subject money I wanted to talk about
money that green stuff or if you live in
Canada like I do we have as my American
friends call it the funny colored
monopoly money here um so yeah how about
money some of my viewers have wondered
why I am NOT a YouTube partner yet and I
would like to be I actually applied make
two or three weeks ago and my it's still
being processed so I pretty much got
ignored don't think anything's going to
happen there and actually I think I
don't think it's legal for them to
accept me as a partner for the type of
videos I make I think it violates some
kind of copyright because I'm posting
videos of a game I didn't make correct
me if I'm wrong on that
so yeah nothing's happening there and I
think the only way you can actually have
paid for making videos like this on
youtube is from machinima realms and
someone actually contacted me from
machinima realms that's affiliated with
them not actually from Mission of um
realms I think they are a director and
they offered they offered to sponsor me
which is like the first step he said to
becoming affiliated with machinima
realms and then later he said he
contacted his team and they agreed that
I could become a paid sponsor that that
I could become a paid sponsor so there's
a chance I might make some money that
way I don't exactly know all that's
involved or if I'm going to be accepted
yet or anything like that still in the
works
why is my game lagging yes I actually
watched the movie The Social Network the
other day so that movie were about the
youngest billionaire in the world who
made Facebook and it's got to be
thinking about different ways I could
maybe make money from the internet not
that
I love playing Minecraft and I love
making videos for it and I love the
response you guys give me with my videos
but you know if I could find some way to
make money from playing Minecraft too
that would be like the icing on the cake
that would really make my day um so yeah
I think it was yesterday I was watching
one of co-stars videos from his LP
series he's one of my favorite LPS for
this game and I noticed he had a link in
his description for donations like
people that watch his videos sometimes
donate money to him for making his
videos which I thought was kind of
interesting
I usually don't pay any attention to
those things but I noticed his link to
his websites and I really didn't think
anybody actually donated but when I went
to his website he had like a list of 50
names of people that have donated just
for making minecraft videos which made
my jaw drop and one guy even said he
donated $100 which is quite amazing
um I know I'm not co-star but I thought
hey I might try to so I'm going to start
putting donation links in my videos in
the video descriptions - it's really
hard to talk and build it at the same
time but I'm going to put down a link to
donate to me in my video descriptions
from now on and don't feel compelled
like you don't have to I'm not going to
start making minecraft videos if you
don't do it
I love making Minecraft videos but you
know if you want to show your
appreciation that way I would absolutely
love you for it
and you would really make my day what am
I doing here just at brain Lake and yes
I don't feel compelled to do it just do
it if you want to I'm kind of doing an
experiment too because I'm actually
working on a computer program right now
that I think it is a really good idea
it's a unique program nobody's ever made
anything like it before and I would like
to earn money from it somehow um but I
don't think I can really I don't think
it'll work if I charge people for it
because people are just going to pirate
it anyways and it's this going to be
just going to annoy people if I charge
money for it so I'm curious to see if
anyone will donate to my minecraft
videos to see if that's actually a good
way of making money because I think
about making a website for my program
and then setting up a donation link and
making money off the program that way
all right she's almost done here um I
forgot I wanted to point something else
out with these other Peters too there's
a weird quirk with them
let's see setup up a lock and a repeater
here it doesn't change the state of this
torch and there's even one wire here
which is kind of weird you have it right
next to it it doesn't work either okay
it does work
never mind if you make it too long
though then I think it works the wire
yeah well if it works if it's right next
to it I might have changes
now that I have my foot in my mouth
beautiful so yeah this is my mini
vertical cannon design um got the button
here goes to the boosters wraps all
around the boosters and this is a very
cheap way of doing a variable timer
system I'm still going to try do the
binary method like in either amps timer
this torch is off and I haven't tested
it out yet so this would be ten torches
plus two twelve torches
come on cow I dare you to hop into the
center and hopefully this isn't blowing
the TNT goes there the torch lights the
TNT and it shoots up hopefully and
that's the first cannon I've made in
this LP I guess you should expect to see
a lot more of those in the future a and
yeah this is a mini cannon it doesn't
have a whole lot of power this might
actually make it blow up so I've added
an extra nine torches or 18 ticks - yep
still in one piece until I fell into it
anyway I'm going to wrap the episode up
here um donate if you want no pressure
and hopefully I made the donation link
properly I had to take the HTML code for
the donation button and I manually
converted it into a hyperlink so
hopefully it works
I had to manually pieces together and
hopefully I got it all right
and
yeah I'm going to work on our world some
more and then oh yeah I'm and I'm going
to keep making those mob system
tutorials and then we'll probably do
another LP episode so thanks for
watching and I'll see you next time