hello minecrafters this is etho again
and we got another good episode here for
you as you can see I've redone the
passive mob spawning pads don't really
know how well they work yet because I
just recently did it and I don't know
how well you can see it but a little bit
complicated kind of similar to the
hostile spawning pads and then in the
center I just got a whole load of signs
to prevent the water from spilling over
but I think it works good I'll probably
release a new download to my world then
if you guys want a closer look check it
out by downloading my world and I think
the chicken separator works perfect I
haven't seen any mobs it's stuck in the
water kind of think that cow got stuck
because it landed on that chicken last
night because I haven't seen that happen
again
since look at that brief cow what are
you doing over here
of course I leg every time I come here
chickens are up there but so the first
thing we're going to do is we're going
to try get a pick separator going here
and we've got to route all the items to
this point here this is a collection
tube we're not going to build a minecart
gate up here we're going to build it
down lower to save space because it's a
little bit cramped on this level so
let's get going here
so information on the Wikipedia isn't
quite accurate for the sizes of the
animals but basically they get pigs
separated they are one block tall well
sheep and cows are larger than that so
you basically just need to force them
through one buckle one block high hole
and the best way of doing that I think
is to use a diagnosed stream of water so
now and I haven't practiced building
this or anything so it's I'm just trying
to make it up on the fly here
let's see here
actually let's move this block in one
we gotta want a sharp angle okay we're
going to have that part covered and so
it's going to be one block high here and
that's where the pigs should get pushed
through hopefully and the rest of the
mobs are going to just continue down the
line you got to be careful not to cover
this up
so I think I'm going to try it like this
I'm gonna have to test this off-camera
though because it's going to take a
while for the pigs to spawn so I'll see
you guys in a bit
I'm going to watch it for a while and
then we might make some changes okay
this is a pretty promising you'll notice
there's only pigs outside here and
there's cows and sheep Center perky I
don't know exactly what happened I went
away for a while and when I came back
this is how it how it was pigs
everywhere so I think it's working
already
I made a couple slight changes so these
guys were made so they can't get up
while the pigs could get out alright
clear their best part of my job okay so
I made a couple slight changes I should
pretty much only one
why Kenneth escrito yes I looks like
it's working pretty good
basically I got rid of that second water
source because I guess the water
transfer clashing with each other so I
just have the one right in the corner
here and starting from this point that
way starting from here the pixels
started going under and it's diagonal
stream all the way up to here
so once the pigs get in this area here
then we collect them together to another
one white tube and they will be separate
from the system okay I'm going to go
ahead and build this out of glass now
because I'm pretty happy with it I think
there's something wrong with my mouse or
else it's a glitch in the game every
time like I try to pick up stuff and
still gets placed down on you
okay that didn't take long
oh yeah and I don't claim credit for any
of the stuff like it's not really my
invention or anything like that
a lot of people have given me tips about
how I could do this one guy in
particular made a video of how to
separate the mobs and it was very nicely
done
unfortunately I don't I can't find the
video otherwise I would post it I think
the guy's name started and if I remember
right and people have been making
passive mob separators for a long time
now but at the same time I'm not
directly copying anything just going off
the concepts that can separate chickens
using gravity and water and separate
pigs using a one block high opening with
a diagnose cream okay
yeah there's something wrong with my
mouth hmm
how should do this okay give me a sec
yeah I'm gonna think about this little
bit okay so what I was thinking about is
you know normally and my systems I don't
like to have any dead zones but I don't
think it's really avoidable with the
pigs because like hostile mobs tall mobs
or two blocks high spiders therefore
blocks two by two you know but pigs they
are one by one
basically so to have no dead zones you I
think you pretty much need to have a mob
that is at least two blocks in size
unless like right where this cobblestone
is here if I was to drop it down one
layer and then place water there would
be no dead zones because the water is
running the full length but I don't
really want to do that just because
it'll make things
hmm have like a lessons on that stuff
it'll make things a little bit more
difficult I kind of want it all level so
I'm just going to place a pressure plate
here that's the dead zone and hopefully
everything will be okay still so this is
where the two rips off and we're just
going to make it small just to make sure
it works first I'm pretty sure the pigs
will have no problem walking that one
block space and then there'll be another
water screen you know right next to it
all right so only pigs should be able to
make it to this point and it'll be easy
to deal with them from here on because
it's a 1:1 wide by one high next thing
we should probably figure out we're
gonna do with the chickens here
I think just for now I'm going to remove
this water oh maybe I can't so running
at this the water the full length helps
to make sure that the pigs actually go
through this gap because in the one
video I saw that was a problem he was
having that sometimes the pigs would
just go past the diagonal stream and end
up with the cows and the Sheep
okay so what we do here I kind of want
to bring the chickens over to the
flexion points Oh
oh he didn't go through one on it's
working perfectly if you have any more
pigs something
okay one day I'm going to try here I
don't know if that chicken sance whim up
I can't place anything on these placing
pressure plates here replace the water
Springs back and then I'm just going to
have a little upwards water section here
and this is just to see if the chickens
will swim up because I'm not sure if
they do they probably do so I'm going to
watch that and all that you guys know oh
it's madness I'm still waiting for
chickens at this decaying pigs
I think I'm dead
oh we got chickens you got chickens see
what's going around here
oh they're stuck on the pressure plates
that's not good
oh man see we have that problem with
chickens too we can't really prevent
dead zones because they're only one by
one as well the thing is though with
mobs once they do this like where they
get stuck on a pressure plate I don't
think they'll ever move they'll just
keep jumping up and down forever so
that's kind of a big issue I don't know
what that happened
oh man oh man see again that's why I
don't like dead zones because it gets
stuck and it's not just cuz it's a
pressure plate they do that if it's a
sign and other things do because they
can't see through the block okay I'm
going to do some more thinking I guess
okay okay so not a whole lot of progress
the whole thinking thing but I do think
that know how I'm going to do the
chicken set up so you can see in there
I removed the two water source blocks
there's only one in there now in that
corner she's in diagonally towards this
one why - and the water is going to flow
all the way up to this door here and
he's just suspended by a sign okay
this is all going to be covered and
let's see if this works
lay there move this quickly in place of
blocks and loser that's terrible
okay so this is like our chicken storage
so they're going to lay eggs when
they're like that then the eggs are
going to drop through this water into a
screen below and then that stream is
going to run towards this point here and
drop eggs down and then the option is
going to be controlled by this door if
this door is open the chickens are going
to go to a killing chamber which will
harvest their feathers and then the
feathers will get routed to the
collection point and it's kind of going
off to the left here so it's out of the
way I got the pigs going to the right
and then the other guys are probably
going to go over here someplace
not we got our four steak
I just probably make the screen also go
down at least one yeah just gonna place
the sign here to prove and please water
that should move the eggs to wherever we
want them to go so we're going to try
open the door here to make sure the
chickens can get through letting stuck
on the door hinge there's gonna be
another pipe here let's see the work
opinions and sorry if it's hard to see
what's going on I don't using all glass
and I hurt to see me exactly what I'm
doing
apart for me too
there's one place soil here temporarily
this will be the source of our next
water stream and they'll probably be a
pipe that goes above and then to the
left this will be covered I can't cover
above you know cover it there here and
here oh and here oh how much and yeah
we're on peaceful again because of the
hostile mobs making noise Oh why'd I do
that I can't open the door
oh never
so hopefully when they go through
they'll go through the door and into
this water here that's the goal oh come
on
ah darn stuck in the door and this guy's
not going
at least the eggworks big system okay so
that's not going to work so instead I'm
probably going to have to hook up a mic
heartbeat somehow I think that's only
way of doing this properly and then make
the chickens drop through the minor key
somehow and the pigs I don't know what
I'm going to do with them so I'll
probably just tweak around with this
guy's and then I'll show you what I
figure out because I have a feeling it's
going to take a while as there's lots of
minor issues showing up everywhere okay
got a little bit of progress done this
episode but I'll have to figure some
things out and I'm going to end it here
and thank you for watching and hopefully
I'll get this working better next time I
make an episode and if not we'll go do
something else like another trip or
something okay all right thanks for
watching
see ya