[Music]
hey guys this is evil and this is a very
important moment for me right now that I
wanted to share with you guys by now
you've probably seen my cannon but this
is my first test launch of it it's
finally at the point where I can try to
see if it actually works
which is kind of significant cannons not
fully done yet but it should should
launch I think all the wiring is done
the timer's done I just have to make
some polishing touches to it yet and as
you can see the lava down there is not
igniting the TNT up here like many of
you were concerned about for some reason
I don't think that's a problem because
the embers can't fly that high things I
am concerned about is if the TNT from
the Boosters here is going to destroy my
base I doubt it will but it might you
never know and another thing I'm worried
about is if I built my base low enough
because if it's not low enough when the
tnt goes off down there I'm gonna
receive damage up on the platform here
and I might have to lower the base
anyway it's fully loaded and hopefully
there will be no problems and I can
finish it up then so here's to the first
launch guys
[Music]
right on that's what I wanted to see
couldn't have asked for it better this
is a back up by the way this isn't TNT
for my stache sweet
all right on with the episode alright
here we are again back in the real world
and we're probably done with another for
at least a few days now start doing some
stuff in the real world again here at
some point this week I'll probably build
another 360 cannon a normal-type and
I'll use this timer here so I'm not
gonna remove this until I do that and
then I'll make the tutorial as I built
that cannon as well for you guys so
that's something I'm gonna do one
question you guys had was how to handle
miss loaded TNT in the nether cannon
that's a pretty good question something
I never really thought about while I was
building it but definitely became an
issue once I had it all done I don't
know if this still works but in the past
there was a really cool trick you could
do I think it might have been fixed
though
before if you had a soil block and say a
TNT above it I'll just use a cobblestone
for this test and this cobblestone is
TNT you were able to use your mum on the
soil and then plant a seed if you aimed
like right here on top of the soil block
I guess it doesn't work anymore but that
used to destroy the block above it even
if it was bedrock any block they would
destroy but I guess that's fixed now so
some other ideas I had for let's say
let's pretend this torch here is
redstone and you miss loaded by placing
the TNT above the redstone what do you
do you remove the redstone near it and I
think use place slabs all around it
top I think that will absorb most of the
blow okay I have four torches here let's
see how many get destroyed yeah just the
one so I think it blows out like a three
by three by three area so that's a
pretty safe way of getting rid of TNT I
want to see what happens if you do solid
see if it makes any difference
I just I need some way to detonate it
there okay and then I'm gonna play soil
around it so we can visualize what
happens better they'll probably work the
same I'm guessing but it's always nice
to try things out damage me oh okay well
that didn't work nearly as well actually
blew up part of my timer here so stick
with the half slabs I guess darn it now
I need to fix that okay I'll do that
I'll clean this up later okay so this
might be a little bit confusing but if
you divert your attention to the top
left of the screen you will see I am now
in 1.5 underscore 0-1 the first five
minutes or so the video was from one
point four and I've already recorded an
episode in 1.5 so what happened is I
recorded those five minutes from first
five minutes of this episode from the
one point four patch still I record a
whole episode and then I scrapped
most of it because I had an issue with
something and before I could finish up
the episode with more footage the 1.5
patch came out and I wanted to cover a
whole episode on it and I did and so I
still have some footage from before that
and what happened is I was working on
this road thing here I'm about to show
you as a possible concept for SMP
servers instead of having the regular
paths that interconnect all the houses
with each other and direct people around
the server you know how you have those
paths they're usually five four or five
five blocks wide and I thought hey why
not put water on one side going one way
and water on the other side going other
way and you can get around a lot faster
right that was the idea and you can make
it go up till you can make it go down
hill and do all kinds of stuff with it
right yeah so I did a test and I found
out walking with the water is actually
slower than walking just normally I
figured that out at the end of the
episode so this whole idea was stupid so
it's a waste of an episode I found out
that walking in water you travel roughly
3 and 3/4 blocks per second
and walking normally you travel a four
and a quarter blocks per second so
walking is slightly faster than walking
with the water currents which is very it
doesn't make sense but that's not logic
for you right and I also found out that
if you just sit in the water like this
and have it pull you you go about 1.8
blocks per second but yeah I decide not
to spend the whole episode on this since
it didn't work so that's what I figured
out I'm gonna show you what I've been
doing with the minecarts all right this
is something I was messing around with
today I still have I have a whole lot of
time at the place and sip a CH came out
but last episode I was messing around
with the door booster because I some
reason I think I've read it or I either
watched a video on it but someone said
that you can't have these power rails on
slopes or on curves and silly me I
didn't even try to see if that was true
so I've got a lot of feedback on this
thank you everybody
yes it is possible and that's a good way
to launch karts makes things a lot
simpler I won't bother to show you this
I was working on making like a buffer
kind of like a PEZ dispenser except the
spread out horizontally that
doesn't require the old boosting style
to get going because you can hook up you
can't mix these new booster rails with
the Pez dispensers which is cool but it
requires both the boosting styles to
work so I wanted to make one that holds
each of the carts individually spread
out horizontally each one of these is
four blocks apart so it's it's not super
compact but it's it's nice and they look
really cool when they go I like that
what is going on here is there's a
there's a detector here okay well the
button first powers this power power
rail here the cart goes it's the
detector this detector is connected with
it to torch delay - oops - this power
rail here at this cart song and then
this cart triggers this detector and on
the opposite side same thing goes here
to the next power rail and so so on and
so forth so you can keep doing this
basically infinitely for as many carts
as you want I thought this was a good
idea but it has some serious flaws that
I overlooked if you send out due cards
at once
you got problems
because this is off so that messes it up
and it starts going the wrong way just a
total disaster
same thing if you add carts like if I
have four cars phone in here and then
have problems so ideally what I want
just to be doing just to set here is how
you load it ideally what I would like
this to be doing if there was no cart
here okay let's let's say there's no
cart here this should be powered no it's
only one cart here no carts here ideally
this one should be powered on and this
one should be off because this one
should detect that there's no cart here
and Beyond and when the cart moves to
here it would go off that's what I would
like it to do but there is no way I've
messed around with this there's no way
to have a minecart on one of these power
rails and one of these detectors at the
same time without getting launched off
and there's no wave even to have it's my
cart on them power rail and a regular
pressure plate at the same time either I
tried lots of different ways and I just
couldn't get it to work so the only way
to do this properly is to use RS nor
latch --is for each of these and it
would just take up so much wiring and
become so complicated that it's I'm just
gonna use a Pez dispensers for the
storage room
here's what I figured out I'm gonna show
you this next thing it turned out a
little bit better let's go to day though
seems like everything I try to make with
mine carts doesn't turn out for some
reason and like everything I make with
boats always works no matter how
ridiculous it is but this turned out
kind of it's a little bigger than I
hoping it would be this is actually one
of the most complicated redstone
circuits made fairly simple with
minecarts this is it right now it's a
base three memory unit so just going to
start it here right now it's this torch
is on it's a counter is what it is and
so when you press the button it's going
to advance forward one now when we check
here it set the second one press it
again it'll be at the third one and you
can keep chaining them for as many as
you want and ideally you would have it
loop back and start over this would be
very useful for making 7-segment
displays the Xbox nut actually made
something very similar to this out of my
boat memory thing I gave them the
suggestion to to make a base 10 counter
memory unit and it turned out pretty
good it's a little bit bigger than this
would be if you use Maya carts now I'll
I'll link it in the description in this
video so I might make a tutorial on this
I'll try to explain this the best I can
so so one application for this is to
represent numbers if you set up ten of
these pressure plates unit things
they're four blocks each apart so if you
made ten of them it would be ideally you
would have five on one side of this
inside track and five on the other side
and you would make a goal loop around
inside track and you would move this
holding thing to the side or something
yeah you could represent a number from 0
to 9 like this would be 0 so be 1/2 all
the way to 9 when it gets to 9 it would
loop back to 0 again and if you had 2 of
these base 10 units you could represent
a number from 0 to 99 3 you could
represent a number from 0 to 999 and so
forth and so on so it's pretty cool it's
it's not an easy thing to do in
Minecraft so what happens is I don't
know why this is powered right now it's
not supposed to be the power rails are
still pretty glitched but yeah so the
cart would go around once and it would
push the cart from this pressure plate
when the carts on this pressure plate
that lights this up and then it would
fall down to here
and get stuck on this slope and then
when the cart goes around to this
detector it sends a signal to all if you
had 10 of them it would send it to all
10 of the power rails down here on the
slope
and then it shoots the minecart up to
the next pressure plate and stops and
it'll go again the next time the cart
goes around so a pretty cool counter I
will also be using this in my secret
project which will I'll hopefully get to
soon I'm not going to tell you what it
is but it's going to be very complicated
and very cool hopefully if it turns out
maybe a collection of so many
complicated things mine carts boats
redstone music TNT it's gonna be crazy
I'm gonna check the time and we might do
some other stuff yet mmm I think it's
about 20 minutes in but it's late here
so I think I'm gonna pretty much end it
here so that I can get the episode up
today we're just gonna do something
really simple
you guys have commented that the stairs
do not let light pass through anymore
and let's say we're there before the
patch not too happy about that
what do you want but like like a lot of
things I should probably test it myself
just so let's see if it's true or not
mmm that doesn't look good
darn it yeah it's true that sucks
actually you know what happened I was
like standing right here and I was
looking at my inventory and I heard
these doors open I thought it was one of
these wolves I go off the inventory and
I look and there's a creeper right here
I was walking towards me but the door
was shut before before he made it out to
me otherwise
so I'm guessing somewhere in my storage
room here now it's dark enough for them
to spawn which I'm not happy about it at
all yeah anyway thank you for watching
everyone and I will see you next time
I'll probably do one of those challenge
videos again soon and a bunch of
tutorials and then I'll do another LP
episode I think and there's something
wrong with the trees there what is that
about it's still light there
that's new for me anyway the lighting
seems to be pretty slow okay I see you
guys
you