how's it going everybody this is Ethan
this is my 5000 subscribers special and
before we get into things first I think
we should talk about a storage room some
more because last episode got the most
comments out of all my videos over I
think is like 350 so you guys had a lot
to say about it so we should talk about
it a little bit more this is the pot
light idea I only made four so that's
one option I don't know looks okay yes
looks better than the torches for sure
the other option I don't have enough
wood to demonstrate it but is to raise
the tracks one block have stairs facing
this way towards the tracks and stairs
facing this way towards the track so
it's a nice gentle soap that you can
just walk up and down and then have
torches or something underneath the
stairs to light up the area through the
stairs that's another option what do you
think I should do if I do raise it I'll
probably still have this part here
lowered where the sandstone is
but I'll raise it on these uh long
hearts here um I added iron doors here
just for the heck of it kind of
pointless but kind of fun to place water
here nothing happens place water there
nothing happens
ah but if you place two waters they open
up so that's kind of cool
and how does that work I think I got it
opened up still we have two of rabbits
water sensors my compact versions of
them - two of them separate from each
other the double doors are above these
redstone torches and there's just the
wire that attaches to this wire they
merge one wire goes to one door here
with the one torch delay so that they
open and close at the exact same time
the other wire goes around to the other
torch very simple for such a complicated
thing that's actually pretty simple
um other issue I wanted to talk about
was I asked you guys his opinion on the
torches versus torches on the ceiling
versus the chandelier type things I'm
about 50/50 on them I could go either
way I think they both look good so I
left it with you guys and you guys
pretty much won 50/50 - I think a few
more of you preferred the chandeliers
but it was pretty close and so since it
was so close rather than making a choice
that some people might not be happy with
we are going to leave it up to chance
and I'm giving chandeliers odds so
because I think more people prefer them
so five out of nine chances we're going
with chandeliers here four out of nine
that we're going with the torches here
we go torches win we're going with
torches and that's all there is to that
thanks for your input everybody I
probably shouldn't leave it up to chance
but oh well I think it's getting dark
now I'm going to take a nap in this game
so that you can see things better and
we'll be back
oh yeah uh oh yeah so we had something
planned for this episode and we what was
it again oh yeah the cannons we're going
to go to the cannons I thought I killed
this - do you think okay all right we
got a boat here - things are going our
way so for those of you that are new to
my channel I said I was going to make a
cannon for every single person that
donated and on our 5000 subscriber
special we were going to shoot off the
cannons and we were going to have an
awesome firework display hopefully and
that was the plan that's what I wanted
to do um now you guys see it was a big
project that's all I can say so here we
are at our underwater base
all right I'm sorry guys I know
nothing's changed you know I did the
math and it's just crazy the idea of
making I had 36 donors to make 36
Kamen's is just too much there's no way
so I'm very sorry it wasn't able to do
it I thought I could but realistically
it's just not something I'm able to do
so to make it up to you guys I think I
came up with a good idea we are going to
finally harvest the clay no fuli's this
time this is it we're going to harvest
the clay because I feel bad that I let
you guys down now we're not going to
harvest the clay are you kidding me that
would be so lame oh I did it I made the
cannons 36 of them and it was insane how
much work it was I started when I was at
4,700 subscribers and I finished when I
was at like over 5100 that's how long it
took I started on Sunday today is
Tuesday wait where am I going oh man I'm
lost
[Music]
okay yeah we go this way I think not
that I play Minecraft much maybe an hour
to day but still it was crazy amount of
work floating islands um I always forget
how to get to them oh oh I left torches
answering I think we're going to go up
should be achieve around here somewhere
[Music]
is that it
do to do I think this is the Cape this
is not the cave okay alright that's the
cavers going to go the lamely plus I
find the key
here they are guys
[Music]
37 cannons it's actually supposed to be
a 36 though but I accidentally made one
too many because some of the repeated
donation that I didn't know so I made an
extra one and so thank you to all my to
all the people that donated all 36 of
you um very appreciative of it that's
why I did this to show my appreciation
in my own weird way and also this is
going to be fun for everyone it's fun
for me it's fun for you guys a ring that
donated gets a cannon and it's fun for
my viewers and it shows appreciation to
my viewers too even though not everyone
donated I still appreciate everyone that
leaves comments and stuff and likes and
favorites and yada yada yada all that
stuff and so some of you were wondering
about this we're at one thousand ninety
eight dollars and 84 cents that is
canadian funds and that's before paypal
takes its cut too so I think PayPal has
like a six percent deduction on that and
alright let's get to the cannons at the
moments
they're not really set up yet I have to
actually pause and set them up but here
are some fun facts about the project
each cannon has 14 plus 18 32
redstone 32 times 37 cannons is 1184
redstone that's just on the surface
that's not counting all the wiring
underneath the cannons which is close to
another thousand so altogether this was
about 2,000 redstone it's my biggest
redstone project yet this is all made
legitimately now embed it or mcedit or
anything like that took several hours
takes 185 tnt to load all the cannons
five each let's go check the mounts
actually what I'm going to set them up
first finish setting them up and then
we'll check them out and all alright
guys we are back and ready to roll here
if you're wondering what I was doing I
was doing a couple things I'm going to
show you something with these cannons so
every cannon has four boosters and a
projectile which goes in the middle here
I am gonna demonstrate one
this is like the most efficient design I
could come up with and it's not really
my design I'm sure this has been done
before but yeah you load it like this
those are the boosters then you post put
the projectile here and it's ready to
roll every cannon has its own button
they can each one to be individually
fired because each one has its own
timing system as well over here six
repeaters every cannon sends its this
wire here which transfers power through
this block to the TNT when I originally
made these I had four glass blocks all
around and I found out that to power
doesn't transmit through glass blocks to
the TNT so I had to change every single
cannon but yeah so what I was doing is I
was randomizing all these times here I
tried to give each one kind of a random
time and also as randomizing the timer's
below the cannons which you will see
soon this is what it can does pretty
cool so we're going to walk through the
cannons
I've also I was also backing up the
world because as soon as we're done here
I'm going to reload it so that I get all
the TNT back and you might say that's
cheating but I don't think it is because
we're doing this for fun if I was for
example using TNT to haul out a big
cavern to save time on the ground
if I backed up my world after doing that
I would get the TNT back but none of the
work none of the work would be done so
if the TNT is actually being used for
something useful I can't go back but
this is just for fun it's we're not
doing anything useful so I don't think
there's anything wrong with reverting
back so we're just going to load up all
the cannons and then I'll go through and
I didn't want to reveal your names
because I'm sure not everybody wants
their name posted on the internet so
I've just put your initials your first
name last name so you know what you can
then is yours and I tried to make all
the cannons because someone asked that I
make them a wool cannon and I thought
that was kind of a funny idea so I'd
wait I tried to make every single one
unique
and originally I wanted to make every
candidate a different design but that
would have been way too hard because
just doing every single one the same was
pretty hard and I didn't have enough
redstone to be messing around I actually
only have I have less than 2 stacks the
redstone left I use my whole supply on
this project
and yes some people have fancier cannons
some people donated quite a bit of money
so I think it was the right thing to do
but every single one every single
donation was appreciated greatly I have
been able to buy so many bottles of Jack
Daniels lately you have no idea it's
been great oh and that'd be terrible now
I don't have any bad habits so your
money is definitely going for useful
things not to not to support a drinking
addiction or gambling or anything like
that
alright that's not even half of them yet
I add some of you like I said if you
wanted your name or your youtube name
displayed just send me a message and I
would use that as your display but I
wasn't really organized when I said that
and so a lot of you that sent me a
private message on YouTube I didn't
actually didn't really put your name on
the side because I didn't write it down
anywhere and I got well over a thousand
private messages in my inbox so they
kind of got lost in my inbox so I am
organized now so if you want your name
change send me a message now and it will
definitely get done the flames are
because you like to start playing Wars
aha
so sorry about that so I've used
initials from what PayPal set the
contributor stainless have so many
cannons I haven't fired the mid either
so I don't know how it's going to look
hopefully it's cool we're going to have
to delay the secret project even longer
I think because I'm not a redstone and
fortunately
but this was a lot of fun too this is
the guy that asked for the wool cannon
so if you that's why you guys all have
special box for your cannons because of
this guy some of you have the same
initials as each other so I've added a
little bit extra to your name both at
Jes so yeah this cannon got destroyed
the most out of all the other cannons
because this cannon over here used to be
made out of TP and a tip self-detonating
so unfortunately si you no longer have a
tnt cannon because it blew up over five
times and blew up that cannon and tip
blowing up that cannon and that one and
that one so eventually I had to switch
it if you've ever tried to place a sign
on T&T you're in for a surprise
[Music]
I think you know what the light stone is
for many thanks thanks to everyone again
can't say it enough snow cannon I hope
you're Canadian
[Music]
glass cannon hi so if any of your
initials are duplicated let me know poor
guy
I have a friend with those initials yeah
if any of your initials are duplicated
let me know and I'll add a little extra
to your name or give me a secondary name
you want me to use
oh yeah and the reason why abandon the
underwater base there's actually a few
reasons would have taken a lot longer to
make the cannons because I would have
had to clear out the area I made myself
a cannon this is the extra one why not
it yeah I would had to clear out the
area which we were taking forever the
other thing is it was 20 blocks or so
below sea level so most of the height
was lost it was only shooting like ten
blocks out of the water at best I think
you know why you get the redstone so
that was one reason another reason was
uh since there's like 2,000 redstone in
this project I didn't want that quite
that close to my base because probably
with the light my base even more here we
are pretty far away we're close to 300
or so blocks away from base I'm not sure
if we should do a nighttime launch or
daytime launch oh let's do both I'm
going to make another backup and I'll be
your back all right we are set ready to
go backups are made I think all the
timers are set there's a slim chance
some of the cannons might blow up or
something terrible might happen let's
hope for the best
it's never been tested yet
um another thing ideally I would like
you to go one blowing up here here there
they're kind of like a random order
fortunately that is extremely hard to do
so it's going to be more like a snake
pattern but I tried to make it so it
want to be just like did you know like a
sequence that's very lame I tried to
make it as random as I could uh I don't
really have the redstone to do anything
else
also um we're going to shoot this off
again when we hit a million subscribers
and not not a no no no a million views
we're going to shoot this off again so
as we get more donors the number of
cannons is going to increase
eventually I want to make some cannons
shooting horizontally and a few other
crazy things might be set up as I get
more time but I've been working on this
forever so I didn't really want to do
anything or fancy than what I have here
this time anyway
next time might be better thank you
everyone
here we go this is launcher very excited
Oh
hey oh it's cool now I want them all to
have flames that was awesome
alright let's do a daytime launch now I
think I want to speed up the timing a
bit too I'll see you guys in a bit and K
I think we're about ready here
so I sped up all the cannons by about 4
torches so or about like 1.6 seconds so
it should be quite a bit different now
be much faster so I want you guys to
tell me if you prefer it slow or fast
this is the fast one and man this
episode seemed long there's a lot of
things I wanted to do in it but this has
been pretty fun also let me know what
you think about putting flames on all
the cannons or if that's a bad idea
I'd have to have redstone on top of all
of them them or not redstone netherrack
or whatever you want to call it okay
here we go
daytime watch first time high-speed
still random let's go down low
I knew I was gonna do that too sorry
guys
my bad okay so this is a storage room
again oh let's go walk back and we're
back so well that's not it that's weird
right in EXO off
that would up oh it's still blast I
don't know why it doesn't transfer
through glass that's weird your cannon
gets to blow up again don't worry this
is a backup let's check if any of them
if any more like that I think they
pretty much all launched probably just
that one because I redid it at the last
minute
yeah all is good so I'll fix that for
next time and I wanted to show you how
the underground wiring works the other
thousand redstone or whatever so this is
a sandstone block that the buttons
connect to on the other side wire runs
down here repeater another repeater this
is a little tunneling I made underground
and let's just follow the wire so every
cannon has these two redstone torches
the vertical wiring and that's how the
signal gets from down here to up to the
cannon and every cannon has at least two
repeaters some have three and so it
always branches off to the cannon and
then either goes this way this way this
way or this way and I planned it out on
paper the pattern I wanted to take
otherwise I would have just got lost
down here
because I tried to do it random and it's
pretty random ran into like a couple
underwater pools so I had to do some
terraforming around here so much wiring
also some of the cannons are higher than
others so I have to adjust the height
with blocks or whatever to make it work
because the ground is not completely
flat above us that's it that's the whole
path so pretty crazy pretty long lots of
work lots of fun hope you guys liked it
I did leave your ideas and are supposed
to be one more thing
well I forgot what it is so thank you
everyone and I'll see you next time
thanks for watching and subscribing and
for being awesome fans