hello everyone this is Ethel and you can
call yourself whatever you want to this
episode we're going to work on something
I haven't in a long time the hostile mob
system so if you're unfamiliar with my
world I'll try to explain this to you
below me is a storage room then over
here is the hostile mob system that
layer up there is the passive mob system
and at the very top is a passive mob
spawning system and below the storage
room is kind of a wire room the e throat
is there further down is the hostile mob
spawning pads and deep deep deep down is
the fake nether room it's the way I have
this laid out at the moment but yeah
we're gonna we're gonna be redoing this
I'm not gonna be able to get the way I
wanted to just because I would have to
redo the storage room and everything and
I'm not gonna do that this will be kind
of my test system and ideally I would
like to separate all the items now
instead of having them all collect to
one point but we're gonna redo this so
that they all collect to one point
anyway controlled by levers and stuff
like that planned and then I think when
the piston mod comes out I'm gonna start
a new base far away from this one so
that we can so that I can make a new mom
system the way I want it but we will not
be abandoning abandoning the space
either we'll be using both of them if I
do that and my game's lighting slow one
sec
okay I think that's better now I never
really did finish this as it is and now
since a 1.6 patch a lot of this stuff
can be done a lot simpler than I have it
here you can see that's still soil I
never finished that part even that was
just supposed to be temporary but with
trapdoors these door system things are
overly complicated more than they need
to be I don't need to use minecart
cheats anymore
the spider killer thing up there doesn't
work anymore and they still drown but
the lava does nothing and I've always
had this problem with mob scene stuck in
this burger separator so we're gonna do
a different kind as well so off-camera I
am going to demolish this and I might
reenable spider spawning on my spawning
pads and I gotta cook a bunch of glass
and then we'll be back alright so I got
that all done spiders are spawning again
I believe it's all ripped out Scott's
probably laughing his head off that I
had to destroy all that glass but you
know sometimes you need to take a step
back to take two steps forward so this
is where the mob evader is and I just
kind of want to play around with this
first before I build anything major I
want to do a few test things one thing I
want to see is if spiders will fit
through the trapdoors if they're like
that so just give me a sec I'll get them
spawning and then we'll see alright I
think we have some spiders coming here
and they are stuck I think by the mob so
not by the doors
well that was dangerous
oh so it is by the doors yet they don't
seems to be able to fit a little kind of
hard to tell us all these guys but I put
them around and they haven't gone yet
oh okay so they don't as far as I can
tell I had it cleared there for a second
and we store enjoying so I'm assuming
it's not possible oh that guy got out
after a scalp and shot him through and
now he can't see me through the doors
time to go oh maybe it's this it's later
oh yeah he's after
holy crap okey yeah I'm only on easy
guys just really playing along sir got a
pressure plate
what's my sounded got a pressure plate
here on one side and they can get out
from that but it only well only seems to
be when the door is up like that they
don't seem to fit when it's down okay
I'm running the same test except for
tall mobs this time it's only two hi
there with the trap doors down I'm this
is the first one coming up I'm guessing
he can get through that yeah because
he's the same height as us and we can
get through that okay alright - Jen much
the same test just want to make sure
they can fit through that I'm pretty
sure they can because we can't as far as
I can tell tall mobs are exactly the
same as us yeah okay
so I need a way to separate the spiders
out I want to do that as soon as I can
here and I also want like a holding
system so for the purpose that if if I
don't want items to drop for my mobs
because items cause lag in your world if
I ever want to shut them off I want like
a holding system that will hold them all
in a clustered space where they won't
drown or die and then when I flip a
lever I want them to be free to go to
their killing chambers and so this is
kind of an experiment to make a spider
separator and a holding mechanism all in
one here this is the holding mechanism
believer in the back so I'm gonna have a
water source block here it'll push the
mobs diagonally to this point here and
I'm just gonna cause the water to flow
all the way here so the tall mobs will
follow this path and they should get
stuck at this door here and then if it's
flipped open I'm not going to press any
arrows they'll continue on their way and
same with the spiders after that test we
did they shouldn't be able to fit in
this spot here assuming of course it's
only one high it'll be a water source
block here which should suck the spiders
in and the stair should hopefully cause
them to go up a block Oh actually you
don't want to block there we want one
here
so that the tall mobs can't get on that
stair because it's only one high space
so this should work I think and then at
this point here I'm gonna make spiders
swim up and drown and their items will
fall here diagonal stream pushes them to
this point and then I can do whatever I
want with them of course this is just a
test that's why I'm building it with
soil right now now this will be covered
of course that will be covered so I'm
just gonna set up a drowning thing here
and then I'll let some mobs in here to
see what happens
under a heavy load actually I kind of
messed up the spider thing here so I
made two holes instead with two signs
holding the water back still the
diagonal stream and then I place the
water above and there's two more signs
over here and I just need to put four
source blocks on top and that should
drown the spiders and cause their items
to get collected properly I hope
spiders are always the hardest to deal
with okay so just cover this and this is
just a test of course I maybe hold these
guys back okay all right so I'm gonna
let some up and see what happens here
comes the first set of mobs first test
I'm a little hole for the tall mobs to
fallen and they might drown though
that's one concern the spider seems fine
he's not drowning felt never mind let's
try flip this up see what happens
why is it this stuck there we go
the spiders jamming these guys - that's
not good I hate spiders string came out
here now we're gonna let this get free
hopefully as it stands ill this does not
work can they actually move through the
corner Wow okay so I'm gonna rethink
this I might just do a spider separator
like doc damn did that seems to be the
best one I've seen so far the simplest
one oh there's another spider
okay I'm gonna watch this for a bit -
now one thing I do want to check out
though is how well this trap door whoops
the whole unit all mobs
this thing is loaded up really heavy so
I want to see if they can make it
through that I know the spiders are
gonna be in the way though but let's see
if some of them get through
what's
that's pretty good ain't get jammed
those guys are jammed at the moment just
watch this a Fiat free though on their
own
ah it doesn't look like it's that's not
good so as a holding system that
trapdoor set up with the stream going
around a bend doesn't seem to work very
well if you have lots of mobs like this
because they will get stuck like that
okay there's something else I want to
test with trapdoors
I really doubt this will work but if it
does not or Jeb get a high-five for me
I'm wondering first of all I have like a
dark room here okay they let light in
okay that was a quick test I guess it
makes sense because they have holes in
the trapdoor I was thinking though it
would be cool if if it was dark in here
when it was closed and if they let light
in when it was open that would be a very
awesome feature especially for building
the cook house another thing I want to
figure out is under what conditions do
the mobs drown underneath trap doors so
I have solid water source blocks
underneath these directly below I'm
assuming they will drown
hee-hee-hee-hee-hee centers
yeah okay I'm gonna try space the water
further I'm gonna try space of water
further apart and see what happens so
now I space the water one block so it
should be one level shower I think I'm
speaking English today so I'm guessing
they will still drown with this I think
it has to go one more but we'll see all
right we got a bunch of creepers let's
see what happens yeah they're still
drowning so I'm going to space it one
more and then I think it will work I'm
pretty sure so I figured out the answer
to my question here turns out I have to
move the water two more blocks yet and
so there's a water stream directly below
these trapdoors here and the mobs are
not suffocating being in the water so
water basically has eight depths at at
the source block here is level eight
seven over here six and then five
so if mobs are in water level five or
less four three two one they will not
drown if there is a block directly above
them
is what I figured out from this so
that's good to know
if you're wondering why I'm doing tests
like this I never used trapdoors in a
mob system yet and I plan on doing so in
the future so I just kind of want to
figure out how mobs react to the
trapdoors I did similar tests like this
when I was trying to figure out regular
doors and I just watched how they
reacted with them and by doing that I
was able to build mob junctions and
stuff like that so you can learn a lot
just by doing little tests like this I
think the last test we're going to do
this video is I just want to see how
this works this is a spider separator
like Doc M built in his world I think
you did mention who you got the design
from but I don't recall it offhand but
it looks like a really cool way of doing
it so they come up there and there's
basically just a little gap for the tall
mobs to fall down and since it's only
too high they can't jump over it
so I want to see how this works
hey there comes a bunch of moms oh man
they're getting a fight Wow
help the door switch back my bad oh
don't do that
well they hit a creeper okay well it
does seem to work my setup here is very
dangerous though because they keep
attacking each other and me but it seems
to work pretty good so I might end up
doing this style but I'm gonna play
around with a few other ideas yet I
think and yeah so that's it for this
episode guys it's been a while since
I've worked on this mob system you can
probably tell this already but I'm not a
very focused person I'm kind of all over
the place I have a hard time starting a
project and finishing it but that adds
to the variety of what I do in my LP
episodes but it also makes stuff take
forever to get done so kind of a good
and bad thing oh well but yeah thank you
for watching and I'll see you next time