hello everyone we're back again and this
is episode 13 and a lot of changes have
taken place since our last episode there
was a patch that a lot of new things who
made your leg there I'm also starting to
record in 720p which should make things
better I think
and also I am now running on a ram disk
so everything should load a lot faster
now so I didn't get a chance to show you
this last episode but I wanted I built
this wall here out of water I wanted to
see how the mobs would react to it and I
also built a a double door trap system
I'm not sure if that works or not I
haven't tested that yet so I just want
to show you what this does first if I
can find some creepers yes come on come
on get these idiots to chase me
this way low okay come on let's go keep
going this water wall is kind of
interesting for one thing it kills
creepers if they try to walk through it
if you dig in it deep enough and it
kills cows and I think it kills sheep
and pigs and chickens too spiders will
walk through it though and zombies and
skeletons will walk up to it and then
get stuck and they won't move anymore so
I thought that was kind of interesting
let's try find another creeper real
quick and see if we can get them in our
double door trap
to close whoa that was cool I don't know
if they'll go through this okay so they
still get stuck on it
I think or they won't drown at least
how's it going in there
oh yeah this is negligent work very well
anyway this episode I think we should
work on the road I keep saying I'm going
to show you guys how to wire it and I
still haven't done it and now we have
wire so there's really no excuse not to
do it oh yeah first thing we should do
is fix this water pattern down here
doing it that way
isn't a good idea
I've come up with a better way of doing
it
that that will need one sign
like I said before problem with this the
way we had it there is if a boat lands
on another boat it's going to get stuck
permanently and all your boats are going
to get wrecked so we're going to place a
sign right here and place blocks above
here to stop this from happening and
torch here and so we've got a hollow
spot here we can place water there now
and then what we're going to try to do
is make the water bottom out here do
that we need to run it the full eight
blocks length so one two three four five
six seven eight
there and then we can cover this up so
now if a boat comes down and lands on
here and another boat lands on it it'll
keep working still and also doing it
this way allows us to load boats down
there let's see here a little bit
disorganized here
okay oh yeah we are missing one
important thing on a road still and
someone was asking me about this they
were having problems with their Road and
it's because you need to have a ladder
here and a ladder here so that boats
when you hop in the boat it doesn't push
out this way the ladders stop it from
pushing out this way okay so yeah we can
load a boat by placing it right in this
square
and it works just fine and I left the
door oh okay okay so to wire this thing
it's not too tricky we need to attach
this pressure plate to this door so
let's dig a hole for that I'm going to
place a ladder here so I can get out of
here still
play some torches so we're going to dig
a hole here and then we're just going to
join them together like so and we need
to run the wire to the bottom of the
door so right here just like that so
that's one wire done already and we have
three wires to do so we can seal this
back up next wire we're going to do is
we have to connect this pressure plate
to this door which is a little bit more
tricky because they're close together so
to do that let's dig a hole around here
and we want all our wires hidden so it
looks good some iron
and also I don't suggest building this
in multiplayer servers just yet because
boats are still very glitchy and
hopefully notch will fix them eventually
but for right now you're going to have a
lot of problems trying to get this
working as I've discovered because the
boats don't work consistently and they
behave differently than they do in
single-player with even though they
shouldn't okay so it's two blocks over
I'm just going to take this away from
them now all right how did I do this
before doors over there
pressure plate is over here oh I don't
want to use that I think pressure plate
is here yeah the water is lighting up so
I think to the way I did it before is
make some torches here I add a torch
here a block here and a torch underneath
the door and then you just run a wire
like this the pressure plate activates
it here goes through the torch next this
block lights up this which opens the
door so pretty simple you could probably
also do this without using any torches
but doesn't really matter so that's
another wire done just one left oh yeah
clean this up again
hop in the boat door opens and go okay
so the next thing to do is this pressure
plate needs to open these two doors on
its press our weight needs to close
these two doors when it's pressed and
I'm gonna have to take a hole here for
right now I had a lot of trouble with
this one because I found out you can't
use any redstone torches on it because
it will create too long with delay
okay oops wait it's a lot easier doing
this if you have a lot of space around
so it goes one and then one over
hmmm how did I have this before I think
this is where the doors are yeah
alright okay so I think think we got to
do it this way place the wire inside
what was that noise I have company down
here place the wire beside the pressure
plate and make it go down one I read it
my sword Oh
so yeah just like this that connects to
one door just connects to the other door
and then you can seal this back up so
now when we these doors are open by a
default now let me step on it
they both closed oh okay there's some
school works that one still works
now stories so it's all wired and that's
how you do a neat throat and then for
the other end just copy the exact same
thing as we have over here and we're
going to experiment with the elevation
changes and also hopefully with making
right and left turns with the road and
other things like that but probably not
this episode yet let's go for a ride oh
yeah someone suggested I should hook up
music boxes to the pressure place I
actually kind of like that idea
I think I'm going to try that eventually
because you go over them pretty quickly
and I think you could make music out of
it
all right what now so I guess we pretty
much used up all our time for this
episode already it's time flies when
you're disorganized so we're going to
end it here next episode I'm hopefully
going to start building a storage room
it will be the start of my house using
the new dispenser blocks and I think
they'll work good for a storage room
also a creeper just blew up my stairs
here I'm pretty upset about that but
anyway thanks for watching now I'll see
you next time