hello everyone this is ESO and this is
Minecraft and this is episode 25 25
episodes 2500 subscribers I am stunned
2500 subscribers what can I say about
that that is amazing why you guys keep
subscribing to me I have no idea
are you that hard up for entertainment
well either way I'm not going to
complain I love every one of you guys
thanks for subscribing and please keep
on doing it then please keep on
commenting and stuff I love reading your
comments and since this is our 2,500
subscriber episode we're going to do
something special like I promised and I
figured we should do something else
ordinary and so we are going to
exploring today I would really like to
find a desert and some cactuses and also
I wanted to explore this island here
because I plan on building stuff here
sometime soon this is where the big
project is going to go so
I was kind of trying to think times I
was trying to think of something fun we
could do this episode and I don't know
I'm just not feeling very creative today
trying to think of something fun and
stupid we could do but I just I don't
know did not think of anything which is
too bad I get a lot of comments with
people telling me I'm a genius and
everything and while that does wonders
to my self-esteem you guys giving away
too much credit ah this is where this is
that symbol I made I haven't been here
since episode 7 I think it was I
remember the symbols so I want to get
lost and I actually did get lost it
didn't help me at all so I'm going to
make it point home I think the prop I
liked died around here and I think I
went to the left and died and then when
I came back here to look for my stuff I
went to the right by mistake and never
found anything so I want to see what's
at the left here pretty sure this is a
spot as is thinking that maybe later
this episode I should crap the cake to
celebrate the 2500 subscribers I think
that would be a good way to celebrate it
what song is it dude that's the house
how the heck did a house get out here
that's not my house I didn't build that
general spazzes residence what the heck
man Bull Run is a creeper in here oh
there is a creeper in that house oh my
goodness eyes closed is that a new
feature in creepers build houses now
I've not heard about that
yeah I see you in there Oh what are you
gonna do what are you gonna do what you
just want to talk to me all right you
want to talk about peace treaty yeah all
right I'll listen to you what do you got
to say uh okay guys I'm going to talk to
this guy for a while and I'll tell you
what he has to say all right guys so
this is general spaz and basically he's
in charge of what did you say yeah so
basically all the creepers in my area
and he's heard about the recent
experiments I've been doing on mobs
lately and how I've been tormenting and
killing his friends and his troops and
basically he wants me to stop so we've
been talking about a peace treaty here
for a few days now and the deal is
basically if I stop killing his friends
they will stop killing me and blowing up
my base and everything and at first I
wasn't really going to accept this deal
but then he brought to my attention a
misunderstanding I've had um I thought
the creepers were attacking me because
they didn't want me on their land
and I thought they were trying to get
rid of me but that's not the case at all
he has told me as many of you know
creepers are very quiet and shy
individuals they like their privacy and
they haven't actually been trying to
attack me
rather they've been trying to attack my
camera equipment that's you know my
cameras that are following me around
this world they don't like to be
recorded on camera and whenever they see
a camera they just get ticked off and
try to blow it up so they're fine with
me living here as long as I stop killing
them and if I do that they're going to
stop killing me so I have agreed to this
peace treaty it sounds good to me
it does have one other issue though I'm
going to have to stop making minecraft
videos because I'm not going to be able
to use cameras in my world anymore to
record the videos because that violates
the treaty so unfortunately for you guys
this is going to mean this is going to
be my last a Minecraft video that I'm
going to post so yeah that kind of sucks
but I think it's for the best
it's for peace after all and I've even
told spaz here about to my 2500
subscribers and he's really happy for me
he even baked me a cake to celebrate I
think it's I think it's done now yep
it's done baking so we're going to have
some cake and celebrate our last episode
and our 2500 subscribers this is my
first take I've made with spazzes help
of course so let's let's all have a
piece I think you just left click on it
peace for me peace for spaz peace for my
subscribers
I guess I I guess I saw we can eat so
I'm going to leave the rest here for
spaz and spaz I am going to destroy all
my mob equipment I'm going to stop
killing your friends and we hopefully
will live together peacefully from now
on so nice to meet you spaz I'm going to
get going here and yeah so we're just
going to head home here and since this
is my last episode I thought it would be
good if we harvested the clay finally
and also I'm probably going to blow up
all my mob tubes and stuff with TNT so
we're going to head back to our base now
to do that but before we do that there's
one thing I actually wanted to try a new
invention a new idea this is going to be
like on-the-fly portal so to build a
portal you need about 14 obsidian or 14
lava and flint and steel to light it but
that is not easy to find or to carry
with you
so this is kind of like on-the-fly easy
to build portal I think is going to work
I'm about 77 percent sure it's going to
work and what we're going to do is we're
going to build it out of cobblestone and
wood instead of obsidian like this and
we're going to light it like you would a
normal portal make sure trees don't
catch on fire
but obviously this is not a portal if I
walk through here I'm just going to
burns so what I'm going to do I brought
along with me a button and this is I'm
pretty sure this is going to work I
haven't tested it yet we're going to put
a button on this tree
run some redstone wire to our low
quality portal here and I think when I
press the button it's going to convert
this to an obsidian portal and then I
can just take it to get home really
simple and so if I'm on the go that's
all I have to do but that regular button
is not going to work
we need an epic button and if you don't
know what an epic button is it's
basically it makes awesome and
unexpected things happen so to make sure
this is an epic button we need a do not
press sign
all right you guys ready just kind of
make an obsidian portal to take this
home I'm 77 percent sure here we go I
didn't work holy crap man spaz are you
okay how the heck did that blow up your
house I am so sorry dude seriously
you're not you're not going to forgive
me aah
oh I'm in big trouble now big trouble I
just killed the general Oh
and blew up his house oh my guess I'm
gonna be trouble now how did this happen
things were going so well
we made peace uh
Wow well I guess that changes everything
because I'm pretty sure the peace treaty
is no more because I just killed the
troopers leaders and I think they're
going to be angrier than ever at me so
the good news is I guess I don't have to
stop making Minecraft videos we can
continue our adventure together still so
some good team out of this I guess oh
but I miss poor spaz he was the coolest
creeper I ever met and I guess we should
honor him properly
rest in peace
general spaz um what's the date today
born fit
9:11 died Feb 9 I'm going to miss you
spaz
we had some good times together told me
some good jokes shared some laughs
add some cake together life's not gonna
be the same without you
getting all weepy-eyed here this is all
I could find of him just his ashes he's
gonna have a cool coffin the kind with
the window and spaz was a good creeper
but it's time had come good knowing your
buddy and to my subscribers thanks for
watching and there's going to be more
let's play videos