hey everyone we are back back to the
real world
no more nether for a while and we are at
the storage room and I apologize for
last episode the speed-up one there's a
little bit messy due to technical issues
and my commentary kind of got messed up
also away while there was no commentary
because it got messed up so I was going
to scrap it but I had no other videos to
post so I posted it anyway and all in
all we only got 27 glowstone so yeah
definitely not enough to do the checker
pattern for the whole storage room
because I figured we'd probably need at
least 100 to 200 glowstone um fell great
I just got creepers on a little bit
disorganized oh boy and I never switched
back to peaceful oh I know there's
funnily in there I will get to that in a
second um yeah so this is your storage
room a little bit scared I may get
killed here and it's pretty big got clay
blocks brick coal which is really black
wool iron gold and my huge diamond
supply crafting bench Jess furnish
Spencer jukebox and block and then we
have our different colors of bowl here
still missing all the blue colored ones
and also brown buddy how's it going oh
okay we're just going to switch to
peaceful because I never fixed an issue
um yeah so cloth goes below dye goes
above and I don't really have a lot of
anything you get one out at a time using
the buttons or you can just enter them
and get as many out as you want like
normal like a normal chest and then we
have chests for extra supply here and
yeah so about the lighting issue with
the glowstone I've kind of solved it
here that fire in the background sound
of fire basically I kind of came up with
a solution this is easy to read right it
is for me it might be different on
YouTube but as some of you probably know
light can pass through stairs so this
looks like a solid wood plank but it's
actually a stair and there's fire on the
other side of it and so this lights up
the signs really bright I was using
torches before but fire lava glowstone
and the jack-o'-lanterns are a little
bit brighter than torches so fire is
actually a better choice I'll probably
replace it with lava just to get rid of
a that's stupid fire noise all the time
but I got to back up my world first to
make sure it doesn't burn everything
down and yeah so we got to let's see I
blew away this hillside a little bit
more using TNT and there's a minecart
track in our storage room it's kind of
busted because of an accident at the
moment but the track loops around the
storage room comes to this point here
I have to set up a minecart system PEZ
dispenser style and the goal is every I
want to get to the other end of the
storage room quickly I need to have mine
carts going around a loop constantly
like within three to five seconds of
each other and so that's what I'm trying
to set up here so they're going to go
around this way and they're going to
return to a stack carts here I've never
built as dispenser minecart system
before so it's a little bit challenging
for me but they fall on a half-block and
then there's going to be a booster track
next to this that's going to be
constantly going around with some
overload protection on it and it's going
to send the carts up up here and they're
going to go around they'll need to have
enough force to make it all the way
around and it's just going to keep
looping around and around and this is a
as dispenser is important because it's a
buffer and it's also a regulator to keep
the carts in equal spacing because
otherwise if you ride in a minecart it's
going to change the distance between an
empty line cards they're the spacing
will change if you ride in mine carts if
you don't have a regulator so this is
the fire system ideally I would like to
use glowstone if I have enough but I'm
just going to replace it with lava yes
so this is an experiment I was doing
just just now um so BD tetra made an
invention for sorting skeletons a lot of
people suggested that since skeletons
move counterclockwise from you that you
could make some sort of method to
separate them and that's what to DD
tetra figured out I'm going to post a
link to his invention and this is a
refinement I'm trying to make to it and
it seems to be working well
all right so we got some activity going
on here you just saw the skeleton one to
the left there and another one and so I
found out the best way to make them go
counterclockwise is to make sure that
they are on dry land so I don't know if
you can see it but there's a pressure
plate right where my cursor is and in
that one block space they go on dry land
and the distance you are from them is
very important and so there's just a
hole here where the zombies and creepers
will fall and I don't really have this
doing anything right now just be dropped
into this room yeah so creepers up here
and this lava started to flow out and
that's what destroyed my car tracks
there man
but yeah this seems to work very well
I'm gonna work on polishing it up a bit
yet and so a little bit hard to see but
especially since I made out of the dirt
this is where elevator is I would like
to show you guys this I have to destroy
these and so
the tall mob elevator is right over here
so it travels two blocks which is
important because if you let them free
roam over here they'll probably not move
so the water stream gets the movie at
the exit point and they see you and this
stream is going this way the skeleton
sees you he always moved this way and he
falls down into this little special
chamber the other mob just keep going
straight over here and then the half
blocks prevent them from coming to you
because can't fit through this space and
you need to be three blocks back from
the half block so all together it is
five eleven blocks total so the elevator
is ten blocks away from me and yeah that
it is that um I'm going to check how
much time we have and then we might do
something special so we'll be right back
okay so we still got a few minutes so
let's go do something fun um thanks to
everyone that sends me their videos and
ideas and comments and everything we are
going to go visit one of my viewers
worlds that he sent me one of his
inventions which is very cool he calls
it boat warp speed version 1.0 design
inspired by etho thank you more boats
can be added I just don't want to lay
these shoes currently loaded 64 boats
give or take four not yet tested on S&P
funding made possible
by embedded and up at perch ooh aperture
I'm not very good at pronouncing things
and aperture labs we do what we must
because we can load by placing boats on
above lapis is a lapis block so up there
I'm not supposed to say who invented
this because he said he didn't want to
people messaging them I think um but I'm
going to say anyway because I think he
was just being modest the guy that came
up with this is nanometer seven eight
nine but be warned if you send a
messages he might not respond but I
think he deserves credit for this
because this is cool so I'm going to
load I think it was 55 bolts I had I
don't use in vedat
so just using what he's left behind here
so now there is a hundred and give or
take a few 120 maybe and if you saw my
previous LP videos um I basically
discovered something that I called warp
speed I brushed up against about a bunch
of mobs it would send you flying and
this is what this guy figured out only
using boats and is very reliable
so you just enter the minecart there the
boats then a 3x3 area here which is
important and all you do is point down
and right-click oh I'll get sent flying
I did a bit of testing and playing
around with this which is very cool it
sends you flying I think about 50 blocks
the way he has it set up right now and
it's only blocks off the ground so you
fly 50 blocks while only dropping 3 if
you fall further you'll go a lot farther
and if you use more boats you'll go even
farther oh and I hit the tree issues
with this and these are serious issues
reason why I wouldn't actually ends this
thing um it legs your game the more
boats use the more it's going to let
your game unfortunately because it is a
very reliable system you always go the
same distance and I hit this tree now oh
yeah it goes about 50 blocks and 5 10 15
20 25 30 this is about 30 pretty cool
thanks battle meter thanks for showing
us that I'm not sure how you position
the minecarts I don't know if you had a
method for doing it or if you just
brushed against it and somehow got it
perfect
maybe maybe he'll reply and tell us how
he did that because it's kind of a weird
spacing away from the block
and yeah so if you place the boats from
underneath here the boat gets placed on
top of this block that's how it's doing
that and inside the other boats pretty
cool um I think we have some time so I'm
going to show you my older world some of
you have seen this before
it's my old storage room and I mentioned
that I was making a fire river system in
my ceiling before and I'm actually a
fail work system because it didn't work
very well while it worked perfectly but
I overlooked one little thing and this
is a temporary wire I set up tested so
what I when I originally was making this
I used soil blocks and they look a
hundred times better than cactus blocks
because tactus blocks are a lot bigger
and they're green which is kind of ugly
but the bigger block blocks most of the
fire animation so it doesn't look nearly
as cool
there's one more thing I could show you
guys I'm going to cut it here hey
actually there's a few things I can show
you this is the gigantic cactus farm for
the fail work system it was supposed to
be few layers and for fireworks setups
never got finished and they all funnel
into these drop dates the original drop
gate and they fall down the minecart
date has replaced this and let's go take
a walk down memory lane I haven't played
in this world since I started the LP and
this is where I did a lot of testing 8
on this hill here so I invented the ez
loader and ribbits compact the water
sensor don't remember oh I know what
this is these were both memory cells
never got finish old wood generator
which got patch
the random cactus logic thing which has
been destroyed then you did a redstone
don't ask I remember and this is another
important test actually well so this
stuff is half destroyed because I ran
out of resources we are going to go
check out one invention real quick yeah
so I have a few inventions I've never
shown anyone before this is one of them
I made this about two months ago but as
you know it's impossible to jump across
the three wide canal
um you can use boats as platforms oops
that was an accident
let's try this again add a button here
that I never hooked up
here comes the boat and I just jumped
across an impossible jump and yeah so
we're out of time so I'm going to end
the episode here thanks for watching