hey guys I was just doing some
spelunking came across something coolant
that show it to you start off the
episode for today least I think it's
cool
I had one of those like wow moments in
Minecraft as soon as I saw this that
epic cave music played too and it was
just perfect alright guys we're back in
her lab here I had a pretty good haul I
think I got about 15 more diamonds and I
mean it was close to 10 stacks of
redstone I was really happy about that
three stacks
I earned a bunch of gold bunch of lapis
lapis yeah and yeah so our mission for
today is to start working on our spider
system spider spawning system so if
you're unfamiliar with the concept I'll
run it down for you basically you need a
solid block with an airspace above then
above that airspace you need a glass
block this is a robotic oz figured out
and now Derek Lee will blow this glass
if it was dark a spider would be able to
spawn there but nolde call mobs would be
able to because it's glass is in the way
so it's a pretty cool trick and with
that we can make a spider only spawning
system and that's what we're gonna be
doing today and so I've looked around
I've seen a lot of people's spider
systems they've been making like docum
for example has made a pretty cool thing
everybody seems to be making a spider
switching options which are really cool
they allow you to have only spiders or
have spiders and tall mobs mixed
together I think some have even made it
so they can have only tall mobs so you
have like three options there
and they're cool and everything but I
really just want a spider only system
because we're gonna have to spawning
systems we're gonna have one dedicated
for the spiders only and we're gonna
design it specifically for them and
their unique shape and climbing ability
and all that annoying stuff about them
to make it work efficiently and then
we're gonna have a second spawning
system for the tall mobs
only so we're gonna keep them separate
and design each one specifically for the
shape and that of the mob because that's
to me that's a real benefit of being
able to make a spider only system or to
make you know that whole trick with a
glass block and that is so that you can
make specific spawning systems for that
mom now what was I gonna say I lost my
thought now we're all my cows and sheep
there's nothing spawning what's going on
oh man I'm worried about this never
happened before and me have messed
something up the chickens stuck there
that's from before I know still waiting
for him to be spawned dead no they're
not on
no I think I'm being affected by the
mobs not spawning glitch for the first
time for some reason that was unexpected
yeah I don't know I was weird but
they're they're back to normal now I
just walked towards that Island that
blew up or that piece of land I blew up
and came back and is working again so
don't know anyway back to work here so
originally I think you're making a giant
spawning pad for the spiders like just
one huge pad with water canals in it to
push them the direction the general
direction I want them to go as even
experimenting with the lighting for the
floor that I could use and I've actually
recorded an episode of me building the
spawning pad that I have now deleted
because I changed my life yeah so I came
up with a pretty good idea that we're
gonna do instead so I loaded my back up
and we're redoing everything here
although it looks like I'm starting
fresh and in the episode I deleted I
decided I was gonna build with smooth
stone mostly the pad because one thing I
don't have enough sandstone to do it's
another thing
cobblestone would be the easiest but I
don't really like how it looks
and also I don't want to use dirt so
smooth stone I have an abundant source
of it as long as I have enough fuel to
to smelt it and it looks pretty good too
this is gonna actually gonna be the
first thing I've ever really built with
smooth stone which it's kind of hard to
leave because I've been playing this
game how long I always use cobblestone
instead just because it's easier but
we're gonna use some with stone and we
are going to go up there and get started
so the main problem I'm having here is
the passive mob farm is in the way like
really in the way with this new idea I
have we may end up half having to cut
off this wing here from the passive mob
farm and maybe adjusting things to it
later but for right now what we're gonna
do we're just gonna cut a hole through
it from this tube and I'm gonna mark
mark clear this whole belongs
I have to be quick otherwise the water
will spill out ah
there you'll see
um yeah let's go up there find that spot
the spider spawning system I'm making
now instead being one large pad it's
gonna be mostly vertical and several
layers as many layers as we can get with
all this stuff in the way I figured out
I can only get six layers unfortunately
for a total of fleming calculate here
about 800 now it'd be less it's maybe
about 700 spawning spaces for spiders
with six layers kind of small
so yeah hours gonna cut a hole through
here right now probably leave this one
here run our two braids through the
passive spawning system I will need to
adjust this a little bit because the
water currents are really messed up
right now but I'll do that in a little
bit later
it may be off-camera then we need to go
through here oh yeah we have that
stinking piston switch above us - all
right I'll deal with that and then I
will be back all right so that's done
I hate crippling the passive mob
spawning system but I think you man it's
gonna work out better this way and it
shouldn't affect it too much so our next
step here is to start building and I
think I'm gonna try do one of those
super speed things with voiceover
commentary so you can watch them deal
the whole thing and hopefully I don't
mess up in editing and it actually turns
out so here we go here we go
so the first thing I'm doing here is I'm
counting out ten blocks on each of the
sides I got to make a giant square here
it's gonna be a 20 by 20 square to start
out with and I'm just outlining the
borders of it now holding shifts so I
don't fall off
yeah this is this layer here is 20 by 20
but this is not where the spiders are
actually I'm spawning on we gotta go up
one more layer yet which the next layer
will be 22 by 22 so keep that in mind
yeah this is this is how I like to fill
things in I'll put down these cross
sections with the two or three wide
airspace between and then it's really
easy to fill in the square hole down
right right click sounds really cool in
3 times speed I love that noise and of
course I fell down there I was trying
very careful not to do that and I still
did it anyway done here yeah so that's
that's 20 by 20 I'm just counting here
to make sure I I measured right because
this is the base measurement for my
whole thing here it would suck if I got
this wrong and now I'm just adding
outside border for the second layer so
it's gonna be 22 by 22 the layer below
is just the bold water in place
basically because I'll be drilling some
holes in the second layer and the first
layer I put down is to catch the water
from spilling everywhere
alright get the borders done I want to
make sure I don't fall down again fill
it in
it's been a long time since I've done
anything fancy with editing so I thought
I'd give it a shot this this time last
time I tried to do the three time speed
thing was I think for that nether trip
disaster and I ended up recording the
whole thing with voice over commentary
and after about 30 minutes I realized
that my mic plugged in yeah I got pretty
upset with that and I just ended up
releasing the episode sense and they're
pretty crummy episodes so I haven't been
too excited to try anything fancy in a
long time and now I'm just adding
another outside wall this will be to
hold the water and stuff in place all
right to work in the clouds though
they're pretty annoying
so I thought for this part of the
building we do it at regular speed cuz
it's gonna get a little bit more
difficult here and I have my graphic set
to fast now just so the clouds will be
less irritating we're gonna be doing the
water canals now I know it looks like
I've built this before but I haven't I'm
just going off of something night
doodled on paper this whole design so
it's a little bit challenging for me
it's still too but for the center's
we're gonna have I do need an infinite
pool somewhere for the Centers we'll
have the water like this I think this
will work good because it'll kind of
suck the spiders into the center and
they won't be able to go out of this
stream by going left or right I hope
that ends up short how did I figure this
I think I have to afford two blocks
that tells me I made this too big I
think I'm going to afford one more block
yet right make some pressure plates oh
wait how did I do that I was gonna have
two blocks behind there and then a
pressure plate don't understand why I
have all this space I'm sure I built
this too big anyway so the trick here is
going to be deep down going to be too
big down two blocks here this is why we
have that layer below and then date down
I think around here just work okay don't
work we got this issue we should place
box over top actually just so that our
water doesn't freeze while we're working
all right speaking ice there we go look
went through another diamond pick all
right so now it should be safe or
Newsies just like magic
water stays where we want it to and now
definitely messed up somewhere here yeah
well we'll try building another one on
this side how did we do this and then
next one here and we had the pressure
plates three from the wall there I'm not
sure why it's so big don't know why I
put those there
okay put those there and then two behind
gets more water
place it torch that cover them again
look how fast that froze okay and then
we'll punch hurt our holes there and add
this one to away from the end trying to
do this without using signs just because
I think it's a lot better if you can
make something without signs so it ends
right at the hole that's perfect but I
figured something out wrong here I'm
sure
let me count this one two three four one
two three four yep definitely counted
wrong
so I gotta move these walls in one it
seems and then I will be back that's
done now it's gonna affect my plans a
little bit though the way I figured this
because the next thing we're gonna do
here is the outside stream this is the
main stream actually I should mention
this is what's going to get our spiders
down the hole but I also want to put a
stream over here that'll push them that
way and that way if they come to this
outside wall just so that they'll get
closer to the center here and hopefully
get down faster and if I was to place
water here it would just spill out
everywhere so we can't do that we need
to do something fancy they're gonna put
a barrier here for it like that now and
replace it and we will put stone above
now it does that but again if we remove
this it'll just come out so we're gonna
dig down all the way here again that's
why we have that layer below like that
and now it's safe to remove our soil
barrier
and so what that leaves us with is this
seven by seven pad here this is what the
spiders are in spawn on but the way I
had this figure of four is this water
stream was like over here so the spider
would get forced into a center stream
now it's this pointing at nothing
unfortunately so if you try to deal with
that actually what I'll do using stone
pressure plates now maybe I'll extend
this and put a water here that'll force
the spider into this stream that way if
he decides he wants to go to this
outside wall instead of going to the
center here like we want them to yeah
okay and then in the center here we're
gonna drill a hole
and I'm gonna copy this pattern and I
will be back there it is that's the
floorplan so each of these pads is seven
by seven but unfortunately because
spiders are so fat you don't get the
full seven by seven here to zip them if
they were to try to spawn say here they
need that three by three air space
around them for this bonding to work and
if they try to spawn here guess what we
got water next to that block so it
doesn't count so we only count five by
five really even though it's a seven by
seven and we're missing a block in the
center so it's it's only 24 blocks of
spawning space each of these pads so 24
times four is 96 right so each layer I
build will be 96 spawning spaces for
spiders which isn't a whole lot but it
will be super effective efficient
whatever when it's all done here and I'm
gonna make six six layers like this so
directly above this one we're gonna have
another layer each layer takes up three
vertical spaces unfortunately we're
really close to the top of the map so I
can only go up another five layers so
yeah that's what I will do let's finish
this up though I realized I'm being
pretty silly with the smooth stone I'm
going to switch to using cobble because
once this is built there's no way of
actually even seen in here because it's
only gonna be one high for the spiders
so there's no way of entering here so
switching the cobble for the inside
stuff and I'll keep smooth stone on the
outside anything that you can see I
guess just to save all my coal which is
dwindling away
so fill all this in putting Kabul over
all the water stream sections just to
save on glass here
one really good advantage of though
making this only one high is spiders
can't really fight the water streams if
they only have a one high clearance
because they hit their head on that one
high clearance so that's the main reason
why I didn't want to use the standard
water canals for this because they jump
around in those and if you let them
climb they will climb so they won't be
able to climb it in here and then we
need to put glass over the areas where
they can spawn I just
technically you probably don't need on
these outside this outside 7x7 ring as I
covered already but I'm going to put it
just just in case it has any influence I
don't think it does it's like that and
then I'm gonna leave a hole in the
center here and then I would start the
next layer so I would put down another
layer of cobble over this I guess
that'll make it dark inside don't want
to cover up my whole though and I oh I
do that more fish this up I'm only gonna
show you one that I'm gonna do the rest
off camera okay
so then this would be the next pad for
the spiders to spawn on directly what
we're on here and we would have the
water around it and it would all go to
the center like this one below and we're
just making a tall vertical tower type
thing then the beauty of all this once
it's all done at the very top we'll have
Pistons controlling lava and the lava
will flow down a column down the center
here and it will light up every single
pad on its way down
because if there's lava right where the
soil block is it lights up
lavel eight level 15 this would be 14 13
12 11 10 9 at the very corner here and
mobs can spawn at light level 7 or less
so if it's light level 9 they won't be
able to spawn so if we have lava flowing
down it should do the trick in light up
however many pads we want using only for
lava so that's cool however many stacks
of these pads whatever I don't know what
the call that's the plan it's gonna take
a lot of resources though because well
let me figure it out here I use 7 times
7 that's 49 200 times 6 only 1200 glass
just to do six stacks of these pads I
don't know where I'm going to get all
that glass that's a lot
good I switch to Kabul though because I
will have no problem getting that much
Kabul smooth stone on the other hand I
would have a problem with that because I
don't have that much coal but yeah
that's the plan I will continue this
more off-camera and hopefully sometime
soon we can see it actually work again
that's not much responding space only 24
blocks that's that's very little so yeah
I'll figure it out 24 times four times
six with six stacks we will have 576
blocks of Bonnie's base that's also very
little so I might have to move the
passive mob farm so I can put in a few
more stacks to get more space I don't
know we'll see but yeah I'm gonna end it
here thank you for watching and take
care as always bye bye um yeah so we got
some bad news guys it looks like I'm
gonna have to load my back up and
rethink all this because even though
that concept looked like it was good it
is not good so it's all closed off
inside there we got the 96 spawning
spaces in one layer and very few spiders
if any at all they're actually spawning
it compared to you know like the 20 or
so that are spawning on top if it was a
flat surface so I don't know if the
glass has something to do with that or
not but regardless my rates suck inside
there the other problem if a spider does
spawn in there he seems to not want to
go in the water streams so that didn't
work out too well they they just wander
around and they don't seem to go into
the water streams it's like they know
to avoid them so oh yeah