hello my crafters almost episode 12 I
thought it would be a guide here to
address some of the questions and
suggestions people have left above this
mob spawning crap I'm just going to
spend a few minutes on that this episode
first thing we gotta do is shut it down
if we can
there we go okay yeah so uh stay please
asked why is there a pressure plate in
your water trap and Lauren jog 45:45
says if you took the pressure plate out
in your trap they would fall in without
having to be pushed and art 96 er says
what happens if you don't use the
pressure plate well that's what we'll
find out first that's what happens it
creates a backflow disrupts the water
pattern that's why we're using a
pressure plate and then recon jeff says
nice design for the zombie trap but why
you use the pressure pad to stop the
water why not just make them flow into
the drowning pit
good question will we're going to try
that out you don't have to eat something
first
I kind of just got this thing working
and then didn't try to improve it at all
because it worked well but if there's a
better way of doing it we should
definitely try to find it because I
don't like building anything inferior
block that off one there so yeah let's
try get it going again and see how this
works out without the pressure plate um
I should probably use glass I don't have
glass great hey hey uh there's just no
time yeah one second okay we're back
here gotta see little fast here
okay hope I got all my stuff back okay
so that's another big no-no so the way
it was working with the pressure plates
the a second zombie was pushing them in
and so it's like their state then
updates they were stuck oh how do I
explain this better since they walked in
here they're gonna try swim hop which is
what they're doing but before they were
stuck the second zombie would push him
in and it would and they would just sink
down because they were still considered
stuck in there in their game states or
whatever that's my theory so yeah you're
going to need to use a pressure plate
for a sign
alright now we gonna shut this down
again sorry if I'm not clear about
things um I have a hard time explaining
things sometimes hey we're gonna try one
more thing after this run something oh I
hope that's all
okay what else did we want to try going
to make our infinite pool here again
actually we going to shut this off okay
okay so we're going to set up like it
was before yeah like that we're going to
place the pressure plate back this is an
something fires of Hades tried he put up
a water source above this pressure plate
and somehow he he kept it there and
that's what we're going to try see if it
works better we're going to need signs
for this cell probably too
and we're going to place the glass here
already
and rebuild the wall okay and we're
going to place a sign here I think I
don't know how he did it
this is how I'm assuming he did it so we
got a floating sign I placed it on this
side so now we should be able to place
water in here and it flows and goes down
oh yeah
got to seal this - so I think this would
work better but it is obviously more
complicated to do
and let's see how it works
yeah works so by doing it that way you
don't need a second zombie to push him
in and I forgot a block down there and
then we died so yeah that works better
it's a little bit more complicated and
you need more more stuff to do it but
definitely a better way of doing it so
thanks to fires of Hades for that
suggestion and thanks for all your
suggestions and and for all your
comments as I know I said place the
boxes bottom so now now they'll drown as
I fixed it okay talk to something else
now
alright so the next thing we're going to
do chip neck 87 asks are you ever going
to go to the nether in this world you
have plenty of lava to make obsidian and
a portal and such dancer your question
yes we will be going to the nether
eventually not probably not for at least
a few more episodes but let's build a
portal right now anyway
and in case you guys didn't know I do
have a diamond pick but if you guys
don't have a diamond pick or if you just
want to save some time now what you can
do is just place lava and build your
portal that way without having to mine
out the obsidian which takes forever and
all you really need to do is build a
mold for the portal
just like that and there's I think you
would probably do it even simpler if
you're quick you can probably just place
the lava yeah
and place water above even easier
because you don't need a mold if you do
that just don't die
so our goal or my goal in the nether is
to eventually set up a base without
switching to peaceful a lot of people
build bases in the nether but they they
build it and peaceful and then they
switch it to hard and their bases are
pretty cool but I find that kind of lame
you should keep going hard all the time
and that's just my opinion
oh and
and I'll probably build another portal
in a house if I ever get around to doing
that still need to build a house and you
need iron and Flint build to make fire
and then you light it on fire
it's on fire they're all done so I'll
probably at least a few episodes before
we do that just I would like to have a
wheat farm or something first and we
will be building wheat farms and factus
farms and all that fun stuff
eventually okay on to something else