that's right
so
yeah so what's going on here you're
wondering well I went ahead and finish
this up and hmm
sure upon what I was going to say I
didn't change a whole lot
or I mean I didn't do anything too
complicated I just put a glass case
around this thing
it's that - hi I have a door here so um
let's see in here this is where the
skeletons were supposed to be
from our second path here I wanted to
have like five skeletons in here for
more firepower and it's three blocks I
hear and the idea is they would jump up
if that door is open I'm standing in
front of it they would jump up they
would see me and they would shoot an
arrow in that direction um it's kind of
hard to make them shoot at me
and keep them from joining the mobs in
the center here so I just put a block
and a half step and they only see me if
they jump I think but I just want to
show you guys this thing because I'm
going to have to redo this all
because um it barely works at the moment
because if there's more than one
skeleton in that room there they tend to
start shooting each other and they kill
each other the second issue is there
needs to be a two-block space here so
because if that creeper gets where I am
over here he's going to blow up the
skeletons in our shooting area here and
the main issue though is there's not
enough firepower it takes too long for
the one skeleton to shoot down all these
mobs as that room fills up really fast
and stop the video here okay so I'm
going to show you guys how I was loading
the skeletons into the replace skeleton
just came up here so we're going to
switch the junction a little quick
hopefully got another one I think you
got one in there I guess even jumping
around into that very few of his shots
back to hitting these guys so I'm going
to have to change a lot of things about
this
so I'm going to tell you what I'm going
to do for one thing I'm going to change
all these tunnels around there's going
to be a junction closer here and one
path is going to go into this room but
before it does that it's going to run by
a few cactuses to damage the mobs so
ideally when they enter this room they
only got one hit point left so one arrow
one arrow will take them down hopefully
ideally so I'm going to pass somebody a
few cactuses and other thing I'm going
to do is I'm going to put them I'm going
to build a room with no water in it and
a glass roof and the sunlight is going
to kill the zombies and the skeletons to
separate them out so that only creepers
will enter this chamber
and then I'll have the second tunnel for
the skeletons to get into their
designated area so I'm carve up probably
gonna build that off-camera since I've
showed you guys how I do the tunneling
already you there won't be anything new
there oh yeah I said it before I'm
pretty much out of class and sand I'm
going to show you guys where I've been
getting the sand from just in case
you're interested
I really haven't explored much away from
this island yet so I'm hoping we'll go
on some kind of exploring mission to
find sand and cactus soon but I've just
been hollowing this out to get sand so
far so hopefully we'll find a desert
somewhere so I'm going to start working
on that and I'll see you in a bit
alright this is a bit of a progress
update
I was gonna test again
to see if you can compress the mobs into
a one-block space just by dropping them
and you can if it's three blocks deep so
they they fall unlock two blocks three
blocks doesn't work if it's only two or
not very well J and so instead of having
a Junction like this I've kind of
invented a new type sort of so this is a
one block wide stream and it's only two
blocks high so they can't jump and then
they approached the stream over here
there's a water source over here which
creates a diagonals low it's too wide
and that makes them brush against this
door so if this door is open they go in
then you can close it and that's how you
can separate the skeletons out and the
other guys they just keep on going and
they're going to go to our compression
room where the sunlight kills everything
with the creepers which isn't built yet
I just wanted to show you guys this
first and so dissol
freak entertainer if you want to build a
mob separator this is one way you can do
it have this diagnosed stream and have
it only two blocks high so they can't
jump and have three doors spaced one
block of parts and fits a creeper open
the creeper door skeleton skeleton door
or zombie zombie door something like
this that's a very simple way of doing
it you still have issues of their
clumped together so so you can do this
water back so that they run by here
again but if you do that let me clock
together which is an issue Zhou has or
you could just send them to a killing
chamber and
and just try to separate them as there
as they come up here from the spawning
beds instead of trying to send them back
through here it's kind of like a
conveyor system you know if they miss it
it's it's a it doesn't come back through
the conveyor just I don't know what I'm
saying you get the idea so I am going to
deal with the deeper separator here oh
yeah another thing we need to check is
this table walk through here dig a hole
here and see if they walk yes city
that's good so we can put a door and
I'll see you in a bit I'm going to work
on that some more all right we're back
we're about to do our first test here
with what I got built this moon is going
down so Sun will be coming up soon so
they're coming through here
got a door here with the lever when I
put it down I should go through I don't
have any water in here yet I just want
to make sure they don't get stuck on the
but they don't get stuck on the door
hinge when I open it obviously a flaw
with this is you have to wait for the
Sun to come up but how to big deal it's
not like you need a ton of Records so
you would shut this down
and you're left with nothing with
creepers in a one block wide tube yeah
so I flicked this junction to stop the
stream of mobs from going here so let no
new ones enter and we can even pick up
the items from the mobs that died which
is cool
and so here's our tests this is just an
maintenance store the goal is to get
them all through there without getting
stuck on the hinge darn
okay it's working yeah so I'm gonna have
to change it around a bit you going to
try maybe using two boys
all right I'll see you a bit fix that
this is a real challenge to get working
properly what I've done now is I messed
around with using double doors and then
have much improvement so now I have a
single door again but it's a position
other way and we're going to set up our
water stream here and pressure plates
and sign hold the water and we're going
to put a water stream here and we are
going to put a water stream here
switch over to easy and I'm going to let
a few mobs collect and I'll show you
what it's doing now okay it's been a few
minutes now the sun's in close to
setting so we're going to switch this so
area down here is about two blocks
instead of just one and you'll notice
the creepers are kind of bouncing back
and forth between the two blocks what
happens is when this door opens it opens
inside towards the creepers so that
they're inside the door so it doesn't
get in the way and then it clears space
for more creepers to get in that that
door space their only issue is can't
pick up all of these items
so I'm gonna show you this little kit
here slide through the answer is a
creeper chamber here obviously you can
only hold so many so this is actually a
good amount I still don't have the
skeleton thing set up and so say you get
records from all those guys and kill
them all and you still have a bunch of
creepers here what you do is you flip
this door closes and then creepers can
enter that door space again you know
it's filling up again then when you're
ready for the next batch Oh like when
you're ready for the next batch just
flick it open here and use a bunch more
you can't get them all to go through but
it works pretty decently
the only other better way of doing it
that I can think of is placing water
sources and moving blocks around which
is not what I consider automated
so next thing I'm going to do is work on
redesigning the skeleton the shooters
range here and hooking up the tunnel to
get the skeletons in here but this
episode is running long so I'm going to
end it here and thanks for watching I'll
see you next time
actually it's one more thing I want to
do just for the fun of it okay see you
next time