hello minecrafters this is episode 15
and today's life lesson don't dwell on
past mistakes learn from your mistakes
move on and improve
this thing here is a past mistake
it was good but it doesn't do exactly
what I wanted to do and so we are going
to move on the best way I know how to
all right good riddance
so it wasn't a total waste I'm not going
to be using this anymore but I did teach
me a lot and we did get a lot of
resources building it but this is the
future this is our second mop system all
right I'm going to show you what this
does get rid of all the guys so this
thing has four water tubes
this one is for the tall mobs oh wow we
are lucky today this one is for spiders
and spider jockeys so one thing we
learned from our last mob trap is mobs
do not collide with each other when they
are swinging up which means with our old
one I added up the mob elevator at 3x3
area because I thought they were going
to get in each other's way but
apparently they do not at all and you
can actually fit over 100 guys in a few
to block space so there's no point
making a 3x3 elevator at all so over
here is a one block elevator for the
pall mobs and over here is a 2x2
elevator for the spiders and what
happens is the water pushes in into this
area they swim up and then they drown
and there drops falling below a we visit
the water school and this is actually a
mob Junction - so I said I was going to
be working on my storage room and I got
a little bit sidetracked this is going
to be the centerpiece of our story
there's many chests all around here what
these leaders knew was a control doors
in our vertical Junction really this
door is closed the mobs can't look
the mobs can't enter this area here and
so he just snuck up on darn it
that's all that broke okay
so when the store is closed the mobs are
forced to swim up and I'm going to have
a second story here and at the second
story I'm going to add a sorting
mechanism to sort the different types of
mobs and I'm also going to have a
mechanism to put them into mine carts if
I want and ship them off to other areas
but I won't start that until I finish
the first story of our storage room here
so to clarify this water tube here is a
elevator for the spiders if this door is
open they enter this left the tube here
this is the killing chamber for this
lasers this is elevator for the tall
mobs and if the door is open they will
enter the killing chamber for the tall
mobs
and elevators are going to go up to a
second-story and I'm going to show you
down below and we're doing this on
peaceful I'm making the exception
because otherwise I'm definitely going
to that that I'm definitely going to die
down here actually let's keep it on easy
just for now
this is the spawning grounds think I
have seven pads here now this is like a
little that lookout area actually I'll
explain this first go back to peaceful
and we'll get some lights on down here
with my old elevator
I had three streams joining together
like this one this one and this one and
then the elevator was up here and it
would go up to the surface that was kind
of a bad way of doing it so instead it
goes up into this little area here and
this is the tall mob spider separator
mechanism the way this works is all the
mobs get pushed into here this little
stream keeps mobs from being stuck in
this area here they're forced to go to
the left and this part here is too high
this part is too wide so spiders can fit
here all mobs can fit here they enter
the thing and what happens is
the tall mobs they they pass right
through here it's all the water is going
straight and this this block of water is
on top of it pressure plates and the
sign keeps it from back flowing so it
pushes a mob through and then the tall
mob goes up the elevator this is the
junction and these are all source blocks
so the mobs go up very fast and this is
kind of like the cork I have on until I
built the second storey and you'll
notice there's an angle water stream
here that is so that they don't get
stuck on this door hinge and there's a
step here because sometimes they we're
getting stuck in this door area and they
weren't moving so even if that happens
if another mob comes up it'll push them
onto this stair and then they'll get
going again up into the chilling chamber
here
there's some pretty fancy out water work
here I got it just the way I like it
took a lot of tweaking now I might make
a tutorial on how to do it later once I
get this all finished because it's
pretty hard to see exactly how it works
once it's all finished like this so this
these blocks here prevent the tall mobs
from entering the spider a switching
area and what happens with the spiders
is they come in through here and then
they hit this app sorry guys I keep
being interrupted here so like I saying
what was I saying
so yes the spiders they going through
there
can probably see it better on this side
going through here and then they hit
this wall here there's only a one block
wide gap there so only the tall mobs get
through but the spiders they hit this
wall and then there's a stream of water
that goes this way and then around the
bend into the elevator here so they're
forced to go this way the spiders and
they get separated that way and then
this elevator here I'm using signs for
it and what it is is it's a source block
here of water and diagonally there's
another source block and it keeps
alternating all the way up so that
there's air pockets and they don't drown
on their way up
and they like the other mobs they have a
door here who crazy water currents in
here going all different directions so
there's a source block of water here I
think yeah here and it pushes the
spiders this into this area here oh yeah
this is what I did you can't really see
it here but there's a source block of
water here going diagonally and then the
stream comes this way and the other
stream goes that way and what that does
is it pushes spiders towards this corner
and so they don't run into this door in
the otherwise they'll get stuck and just
go up
and then this water stream pushes them
in and there's three source blocks here
with a hollow sign spot here so that
this screen doesn't merge into the still
water and above here there are two
source blocks only and this is where
they drown and the stream is going to my
left here and the reason for that is
because sometimes when the spiders were
dying their drops were landing on this
pad here and the stream of water going
this way ensures that the drops that
pushed this way and they don't land on
here and get lost forever and so with
our stream down here there's a source
block here which is a man and the drops
come go up there as far as I can tell
it's 100% efficient and so is the other
one and it's all also source water block
so they climb fast up the elevator then
in my little viewing area here I have
half blocks and I'm going to expand it
here half blocks or so that nothing
spawns in this safe area let's switch to
easy and hopefully we can see some guys
going through here
put some little lights so another issue
I had with my old mob trap here comes
some skeletons pushed over and push
through there there's no air spaces
there so they just keep going straight
odd time a guy will get stuck over here
not really a big issue because as soon
as someone else comes along he gets
pushed into this water
so it works pretty good I'm quite happy
with it it's a huge improvement over the
last one
I'm hoping a spider will come through so
I can show you what happens Hey
keeper keeper okay there's some spiders
Hey
Hey nope
this is the only exception for peaceful
is when I'm working down here
I'm going to show you these spawning
sections
so again I'm using a 16 by 16 pattern
and it's uh each of these pads is 14 by
14 and then there's a water on the
outside get some light in here
okay another thing I was doing in my old
my old mob trap I had three wide streams
we're only using two now they seem to
work just as well if not better and also
I've tried creating a steady stream with
no gaps and I found a doing that
actually makes it worse because what
happens is mobs go into this thing here
even though they keep going straight
they sometimes hop up onto these pads
kind of like this and then they get out
of the stream so these things weren't
working too well I even tried covering
them like that but then what happens is
they kind of get stuck getting into
these things and also decreases amount
of area where they can fall down into
the streams so I got rid of doing it
this way
and there's about seven of these pads I
really hate the hanging these things out
so from now on I'm probably just going
to use T and T to expand this and T and
T mining is a lot of fun basically all
you got to do is put it in a hole like
this and it blows out a three by three
by three area and you just hit it and
run and it blows out a perfect three by
three by three area so to make one of
these pads you're going to need about 15
TNT and in total life I've got 15 on me
and probably another 20 in in the base
if you're worried about like it by a
glass blocks over here the TT blowing up
would probably blow up the glass box too
so one thing you can do is hit it and
cover it up and then less stuff will get
wrecked and your the TNT you'll notice
the torch didn't blow up and if that's
too challenging for you another thing
you can do I think I've never tried this
before cover it up if you got a button
with you
I think you can place the button and
when they then do is press a button here
yeah it doesn't destroy the button so
you just keep reusing the same button if
you want to do it a little safer so very
fun way to go mining very fastly and I
think that's all I wanted to show you
this episode maybe one more thing so I'm
going to keep expanding this and then
the mob trap will work faster oh yeah
you'll notice with my corners now before
I had pressure plates at every corner
with this one now all the streams that
keep going around the corners and then I
have the pressure plates two blocks away
from that edge one two pressure plates
and then this is eight long
and the same thing over here two blocks
from this edge one two pressure plates
and from this same thing and that seems
to work very good if you're using this
16 by 16 pattern and I ran into the eats
Road over there so like stop building
over there so we're running out of time
there's this one last thing I wanted to
talk about this was an idea I had for
the storage room and I ripped it out
because I thought of better ways of
doing it is for the dispensers the other
thing I wanted to tell you about is I
plan on hooking up a wooden pressure
plate here and so when when items come
to the pressure plate it's going to
light up an indicator light to show that
there's items here and there's no items
here the light will be off and I also
want to hook up a timer to it so that
after about four and a half minutes to
five minutes the light is going to start
flashing on and off quickly to indicate
that the items are about to disappear
and that I should pick them up so I'm
going to need to use a about a four and
a half minute timer to do that and
problem is most people use redstone to
do that type of thing and if I was to
use redstone it's going to be huge so
I'm going to have to invent another way
of doing it and I plan on using
boats water and so sand so next episode
I think we're going to go into the
nether to find some slow sand so until
then thanks for watching
and if you want me to make a tutorial of
this just keep the keep reminding me and
I'll probably eventually do it