hello everyone this is ezel and here we
are again playing Minecraft and just
what its June now and that means my work
is very close to being done oh I think I
only have a few more days I think it'd
all be done and then I'll be able to
play Minecraft a lot more again which is
very cool during the month of May pretty
much the only time I've played this game
is why I was recording episodes to post
on YouTube and other than that I really
haven't played much so it'll be fun to
play again do things off-camera I'm
running really low on resources because
normally when I play you know I
although tunneling our speed lunching I
mean looking for resources and other
things I'm almost out of sand out of
glass and I think my meat supplies low
not that that's really hard to replenish
I know I'm out of gold low on redstone
low on coal so
oh yeah and I like ran out of wood too
but I just did a bunch of tree
harvesting so I should be good again for
a while and the only thing I've really
done off-camera recently is I added
these double doors which are not in sync
and I can't get them in sync
because there's a glitch where one of
the redstone torches is only being
delayed by one tick instead of the
normal of two so even though I have a
repeater set to the other door there's
no way to balance it out because it's an
even number and other doors an odd
number so I'm gonna have to check the
wiki on how to deal with that glitch
because I don't quite fully understand
it and the other thing I've done is I've
added blasts around the wolf cage here
got rid of the fences because they look
really ugly and I added this lever here
which is basically a quick-release so
it's F four sets of double doors all
controlled by one lever and they're not
in sync either but I don't care
because I'm not going to even bother
doing all the extra wiring to get them
in sync at the moment there's no animals
coming in here because I have it to
demolish the passive mob evader I built
in that tutorial and then this is the
wiring which you can't see very well
because it's a enclosed circle but I'm
sure eventually I'll put my world up for
download again and you can mine your way
through that if you want to look closer
at the wiring and the one point six
point six patch came out I think that's
what it is they don't show it on the top
left of the screen
anymore which I don't really like but I
think my game is running a little bit
slower now but I see there's different
options here I'll have to play around
with them I can't record at 1080p
anymore so there's definitely some
performance hits since the last few
patches because I used to be able to and
nothing has changed on my computer so it
must be the game you know let's go to
the cannons our celebration cannons
because someone told well lots of people
told me that they aren't working anymore
so I want to see it with my own eyes and
now let's go check it out and here we
are at the cannons guys and our new ones
up there and our colorful paths down
here Oh what I've got a few new ones to
add since our last launch I've gotten
some new donors which is great I would
say this every episode but I know it
would annoy people but once again I want
to say thank you everyone that's donated
I do really appreciate it that's you
know it's kind of like that feeling you
know when you find 20 bucks on the
ground that free money feeling it's
great makes your day and you you know
you tell all your friends oh I got 20
bucks on the ground today you know
you're so happy that's kind of a little
feeling I get whenever someone donates
except it's even better because it's
also a gift and it kind of shows that
you really like my show if you're
willing to do that so makes me happy but
so one of these guys is going to be a
poor victim of our test launch here
because there's a good chance that I'll
blow up the cannon who should it be who
should it be oh boy it's so hard to
choose this guy looks like a chump now
we're gonna blow this guy's cannon up
because I'm pretty sure this doesn't
work from what I've heard and I do not
have a backup maid I probably should
have made one been lazy okay you know
what just to be safe I think I'm gonna
cover all yeah I can't place that
they're just kind of put a little
protective barrier on SC joiners cannon
here and one over here too
probably show me the back up what have
you done knotch
why okay so they're broken hmm well I
don't know what I should do about this
guy's like for lunch doesn't work
anymore let me know what you think
should I rebuild in another area new
cannons or I kind of don't really feel
like building 50 cannons and hmm well
I'll probably experiment to see if I can
tweak this to make them work again but
otherwise I might come up with a new
system of doing this a new way to show
my appreciation it might not be cannons
even I don't know or if you guys have
ideas let me know and uh kind of a
bummer these don't work anymore because
I spent a long time on them oh well it
happens part of the game changes just to
be clear everybody I don't hate knotch
he's I've had people ask that I do like
not she's cool but like a lot of game
developers they don't play their games I
don't think he does very much so they
kind of get out of touch with what the
community actually wants I think and so
they do stuff like breaking almost all
the aspects of the game you know without
really thinking about it I just realized
them surrounded by grass right now which
is pretty convenient because I wanted to
try this for a while apparently you can
grow tall grass
which I haven't seen yet for myself in
my game uh-huh
and you wrote flowers too so that's
pretty cool
so flowers are now infinite mushrooms
are infinite throws a lot of grass
actually and Wow you say you need to
invest in a lawn more now I'm assuming
you can harvest the flowers and stuff
using water so I'm gonna try out now
yeah Wow even harvests the seeds which
is cool no I like that feature though
sometimes knotch takes away features
sometimes the ads and all works out and
then
yeah that's great
gonna have a lot of fun with that
feature a notch has also made one really
great change and I've really wanted for
a while now but you can now you know it
makes sense you can craft wool using
only four string now
and same with glowstone apparently and
when you harvest glowstone it also gives
you a lot more random between two and
four from what I've heard so that's
great
I'm glad he did that because it was just
ridiculous before and so about the barn
guys I'm probably well I'm thinking I'm
just gonna get rid of all these class
individual holding things and I'll get
rid of this the holes in the roof here
and I'll just drop all on I'll drop all
the animals down in one spot and have
them free roam around this building jazz
like this was a good idea I think it
just didn't work quite like I wanted it
to it takes them too long to fall down
the holes and I saw the other day that
more than one can fall down each hole so
it doesn't even separate them like I
wanted it to because animals are under a
block and a half in height so it didn't
work and some people suggested I should
have water currents pushing them in yeah
that might work but again it's still
gonna take a long time even with the
water currents helping so I'd rather
just punch a hole in the floor somewhere
and drop them all down so that not cuz
idea was I wanted to come in here at any
random time and have a ton of animals
walking around or on each of these
things and it's just not working
there'll be one or two sometimes but
most of the time they're wandering
around up there so it's not quite how I
envisioned this wolf cage is working
good though and I added I added this
lever here just to balance it out I
might make it do something not sure yet
and I'll have a balcony yet probably
move the ocean out somehow and probably
pretty chasing around this wiring
thinking let's go check out eats it's
working it's not working it's working
it's not working
last I heard it's working again just
cool really happy a lot of people have
this road is type of road built in their
world so for me if it doesn't work it
doesn't really affect me because mine
doesn't really do anything at the moment
I never finished it which is a little
strange I've never actually built a nice
road that I use which is kind of weird
because I'm one that kind of invented it
a lot of people have added to it of
course I should really finish it
I'll try finish it sometime soon let's
see if it works though
get all the new ez loader is broken
that's one reason why I think I've never
finished this because it's just so
frustrating having it break all the time
I think water currents get messed around
with more than anything in the game code
okay let's try the old-style
old-style works again that's good and
that comes up much faster now it is also
very good I believe you still need to
put solid water source blocks in your
elevator and I'm pretty sure this will
still release two boats unless you have
a monostable circuit hooked up to the
door to keep it open shorter yeah it let
to up there's a pressure plate keeps the
door open too long now the boat or the
road is working though from what I can
tell like wondering about this thing
here no homework
has to be solid water source blocks and
I never changed that but overall it
seems to be working a lot better now
so I should work on finishing it I
actually made it pretty far here I just
need to extend the road and I'm almost
at the other Island finally uh-huh
so each Road working again I'm happy
with that let's hope it stays working
because I'm going to need it for my a
secret project which is another thing I
want to talk about actually I've been
mentioning this project for a while
basically what happened about five
months ago or so four or five months ago
I started working on a big project that
I call the secret project and I had just
laid the foundation for it and as I was
building it I discovered something which
you all know as eats now the idea kind
of came to me while I was building my
project because it uses it for something
and well when I first showed my eats
examples the people kept asking me for
tutorials so I spent some time on that
and then I made an LP which I took
forever to get established but now I'm
finally established in my LP that I can
that tackle a big project like I have
planned so that's what I'm gonna work on
but it is a secret project which means
you guys are not going to see it until
it's finished is what I've decided and
what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna build it
away from my base far away from my base
somewhere
and I want you guys to watch me build it
but at the same time I want you to be
shocked when you see it because I want
your jaws to drop and its awesomeness
and I'm also hoping to kind of make like
a viral minecraft video that spits at
least at least a hundred thousand views
and I want to make a nice polished video
because if you guys watch me build it
when I finally release a nice polished
video it's like oh well you seen you
build this and it won't be as impressive
so you know build a I'm gonna build a
project off camera but as I do that I'm
going to record it and I'll have kind of
secrets let's play episodes that I'll
release after it's finished I'll kind of
record it as I'm building it and then
you can still watch me build it but it
won't be until after it's actually done
which might be a little confusing but I
think it works out best in both worlds
it'll still be a surprise and you can
still watch me build it that way the
only downside is you can't give me help
as I'm building it but I'll have to try
manage without you guys so I'm guessing
there will be about five of these
secrets LPS I probably won't record me
building it in super detail but just
like all the stages I go through maybe
some of my fails as I'm building it just
to give you a good idea of how it all
came to be
and then I'll release all five in a row
probably a week or so after I released
the polished video of my project and the
project isn't really something I need
around my base here it's kind of unique
and somewhat useless it's just kind of
it has that cool factor I should say so
I can build it far away from my base
so I'll be building it away from my base
you guys won't be able to see it that
way either while I'm building it and
then that means I won't be releasing my
world for download until it's finished
once I started and I'll also be able to
continue making LP episodes while I'm
building it because they'll be far away
and there's no chance of you seeing it
so talked a lot about that no hints as
to what it is so don't even bother
guessing because I will not confirm
anything if anything I'll probably just
make you even more confused but anyway I
think that's where I'm gonna end this
episode it was a it was a taki episode
sorry about that I know not everybody
likes those but the next few I have a
feeling we're gonna be doing a lot of
work around my world here it's all be
done work and I'll have I'll be playing
Minecraft more with lots of ideas that I
want to make happen I've got to build a
mushroom farm sometime soon I have lots
of ideas for the hostile mob system
again now that we have trapdoors and of
course there's the secret project so
lots of stuff should be should be a lot
of fun playing Minecraft and I look
forward to it
so that's it for today though guys thank
you for watching and I'll see you again
next time