hey everyone how's it going what's going
on what's new how's the family
we're up here at our record studio area
and I just wanted to show you this thing
here before it's destroyed this is where
the records get made and a little
refresher this is how it works
the mobs get sent to this room here
we'll there everybody but the creepers
die and then they click creepers go
through this door up in this path and
into this water here and then this where
we can set skeletons they go in this
path and they get sent here so there's
two layers of water
skeletons go here creepers go above and
the idea behind this was I wanted notice
there's a hole in the roof here idea was
I would go to the top there for the hole
in the roof is
and the skeletons would shoot up at me
did the creepers and the reason why I
made it like that so that because a
skeleton seems to shoot arrows out of
the top of their head so it was
hopefully to make it so they wouldn't
shoot each other and this is the job man
Tito calls it the quick and dirty f mobs
order this is a fitting term for it
it works good for this case because I
want to need few skeletons in that room
I don't need to sort a whole bunch of
mobs and then you let this fill up a bit
and I'll show you how it works
finally our skeleton
[Music]
they don't always come on and I don't
see any more coming so some of you have
pointed out that I should just make a
creeper her out of the scalp and sugar
the papers when they're in that room and
that's what I'm going to do now and it
makes sense because the scalp is pretty
much go right here which is very tensed
that room there but what I'm trying to
do with this thing is I wanted to have
multiple skeletons eaters
instead of just one and doesn't quite
work so I'll show you what it does the
issue is a skeleton still shoot each
other even though they're shooting
straight up and I'm probably going to
adjust this so that the mobs fall and
take damage so that they only need one
or two hits to die but so you can see in
here we got about four or five skeletons
at the bottom layer and then in there
we've got quite a few creepers so once I
walk over this hole I can put a boat
over this hole and stand on top of the
boat and they'll still shoot at me once
I walk over this will start shooting
and they still blow up the reason is
since the skeleton still shoot each
other da time
the odd time the skeletons will shoot
each other
and the skeletons will shoot up a block
or two so that they're within range of
the creepers and then the creepers blow
up the skeletons so it's probably a huge
hole you know looks like so yeah I'm
going to adjust this so that they could
shoot at each other here so what do we
have here this is for free entertainer
in particular and I'm sure za Bandidos
is going to find this interesting - um
so freak entertainer made a mob and
loader but it wasn't it's very similar
to this but it wasn't automated he had
to destroy the carts manually to free
the mobs from the mine carts and then
the mobs would be inside a water source
and they would swim up and then they so
he had like three tubes one for zombies
one for creepers one for skeletons and I
think he had junctions with the tracks
and he just chose which tubes to send
them to he destroyed the carts and then
they would be in their individual tubes
this is a method to automate the process
so that you don't have to manually
destroy the carts
there's a track piece pointing inward
toward lava here and only side or the
only corner of this lava that destroys
blocks is this one so if a minecart hits
the corner from over here it won't
distort the minecart I better do this
fast and Suns going down or coming up I
mean so set the track up however you
want just like that it damages mobs a
little bit but it's not probably only
takes off
I'm guessing half a heart to our heart
because they're inside water so they
immediately get the fire immediately
gets put out so they don't take fire
damage you can do it several times to
sum up so thanks to freak entertainer
for designing that the mob unloader and
I hope you like this improvement to it
and what else should we do today
okay we're down here with the musical
note box for that Zelda tune that plays
on the timer and a few of you pointed
out that I had the tuned tuned wrong so
thanks for pointing that that out and
try ral 7 sent me a private message with
what I hope to be the proper tuning for
it and I hope I set it up right so I'm
going to play it here and tell me if it
sounds right now so hopefully that's
right now and if not let me know I'm not
really good at noticing those kinds of
things it all sounds the same to me so
[Music]
okay so what should we do now oh yeah
I want your opinion on this
something I'm concerned about in the
storage room is lighting because it's
going to be a big open space
how should I light it just think it may
be having pot lights on the ground in
between the chests and using either lava
or torches or I might make the ceiling
pretty low and have torches in the
ceiling tell me what you guys think oh
[Music]
yeah with this water wall thing I've
been doing lots of stuff with the with
mob sorting before I said only creepers
see what that zombie just did and I was
wrong all all mobs can die in this thing
you can't use it to separate your
neighbors and coffees see a skeleton
fell into and what is this well for half
of the last half of the video I was
recording building this supposed to be a
boat dock
with a rapid dispenser to shoot boats
out into the ocean and it doesn't work
for some reason I think some of the boat
physics might have changed so I'm going
to have to look into that kind of
worried that eats roads are going to
have to be redesigned if the physics
have changed so that they don't use
stacking dispensers but I'll do that
another day there is something else I
wanted to show you guys already
destroyed this thing here um I don't
have any torches darn that'll have to do
so this is a possible new mode of
transportation using mine carts you'll
notice there's only tracks in the at the
turns here I want to see what you guys
think of this so I enter the my carts
nothing happens if I press down we take
off and we can travel on land that has
no tracks on but it is not very fast
it's about walking speed and the tracks
and the corners allow us to take turns
we can also make the my carts go up
slopes using the tracks
and what I would like to make this
actually I'm going to make you guys a
challenge can you create a reliable
method of transportation doing this I'm
going to show you how this works so I
had five mine carts there I noticed this
the mine carts are basically an infinite
booster they'll keep going forever
because they're constantly boosting each
other but they're also receiving
friction from touching the ground which
slows them down and also prevents them
from overloading so listening is
dropping five mine carts so that they're
in the exact same position and they
won't move as long as they're in the
exact same position but if one one card
or more carts is is moved slightly away
from the other ones then it'll start the
boosting and apparently my carts can be
controlled like boats you know how you
can steer boats you can steer mine carts
- what is that noise oh great
don't don't don't don't don't please
don't
[Music]
yeah so you can steer my cart so what
I'm doing here
I'm inside one of the mine carts right
now but there's five of them
if I press down it's going to move the
one I'm in slightly back which starts
the boosting but you'll notice they're
only about walking speed which is a huge
flaw I think they'd be faster if they
were traveling on ice because there's
less friction but you can do some weird
things with them too for example you can
go into the ocean
[Music]
they're kind of glitchy the goal is to
make them reliable so as soon as uh so I
had them in a trench stereo there as
soon as you leave a trench stereo they
start to go diagonally usually but
anyways I'm going to let you guys play
around with that and if you figure out
anything cool please send me a video
response and see if you can make some
method that what am I saying see if you
can use them as a predictable and
reliable method of transportation
because I think it would be cool if you
could make a minecart travel across here
for example straight even though there's
no tracks that's pretty neat
alright guys I guess we're out of time
again so we're going to wrap things up
here I have some good news for you lots
of you have asked me to put this world
up for download and I finally have so
I'm going to put a link to download it
in the description of this video and you
can finally download it and stop bugging
me about it and then probably I'll
upload an updated version of it in a few
weeks whenever I feel like it again and
I'm going to put a link to freak
entertainers channel and za Bandidos and
uh how do you say his name again
I ox i oxys I should have checked
Knox's channel I think so anyway thanks
for watching and let me know your ideas