hello everybody how's it going this is
etho thank you for joining me yet again
and guess what look we're in the nether
again it's been a while since we've been
here and I have something to tell you
guys this isn't really going to be an LP
episode it's more of a I guess you would
say a confession I've done something you
guys might not like I feel really bad
about it but it's done
and I feel I have to confess it because
you'll figure it out if I don't anyway
so here goes I have installed my first
minecraft mod yes now I know I know many
of you are upset right now but hear me
out
you know before you judge me before you
create an we hate etho fanclub and burn
me alive just hear me out
listen what I have to say about this mod
and maybe you'll change your mind okay
so for one thing this isn't just some
mod this is the greatest mod since like
the piston one it's incredible this is
the G all nether mod created by abel
from the minecraft forums and i'm gonna
show you a few things that you can do
with this mod so here in the nether
normally only zombie pigmen and gases
will spawn let's make it a little bit
dark and hopefully some more mobs will
spawn while we're down here
let's just go to this little corner here
I shall pause the video and hopefully
some mobs will spawn there okay finally
it took a little while but we finally
got a mob and yes you are seeing this
for real that is a creeper in the nether
I don't think this has ever been seen or
done before except I'm not Jim self @
creeper in the nether
so zombies can also spawn skeleton squid
slimes all the normal mobs will spawn in
the nether using this mod which is
pretty cool I think
didi ate grass
you'd have to cheat to get grass but if
you have grass you'll also get the farm
animals too which is cool there's a few
other things just going to put down some
soil here one other cool thing normally
if you place water in the nether it
instantly disappears it vaporizes but
now amazing there's water in the nether
what the heck right that's cool
um one other thing I found with this mod
trees will grow normally and same with
wheat and all that stuff but you can
grow trees in that normally in the
nether but when you do they always look
really brown and ugly look at that
beautiful tree it's green bright green
it's amazing
another this is like the coolest feature
and I'm going to show you normally when
you walk through a portal to get to the
nether to go back to the real world
you get that loading screen that takes a
good like minute almost sometimes but
with this this is like the best feature
of this GL nether mod when you walk
through the portal it's instant
how cool is that
I really like that feature and now this
other feature it just boggles my mind I
don't know how it will coded this but
you can see the nether through the
portal and you can see the fire in there
I hope you can see it and not only that
you can you like hear the fire through
the portal somehow it's just amazing I
love this mod but you know it's not
perfect it has its quirks a lot of
really really weird quirks Oh zombie
nearby normally in the nether when it's
when there's no fire or torches or lava
around the netherrack emits some light
but with this mod it's completely dark I
don't know what the deal is with that I
think it's a glitch or it might be a
side effect of this texture pack I have
installed I don't know
I thought that was a little strange some
other weird things with this mod when I
it takes a long time to install it it's
pretty easy to install it just takes a
long time I think it took me two or
three hours which is crazy
it's not like dragging and dropping
files into folders it's really
complicated easy to set up but just
time-consuming
what else was I gonna see yeah another
weird glitch I found with this mod when
I installed it when I went to my storage
room all almost all the netherrack out
of my chest was gone it's just magically
disappeared I don't know what that was
about and even some of my TNT is gone I
don't know why so that's kind of weird I
would give you guys a link to this mod I
have a problem though I searched the
Minecraft forms for it again and I just
can't find it I searched high and low
and I can't find any trace of the topic
I've originally found it's like it never
even existed crazy
but oh well hopefully you guys can find
it and I have another portal here
I talked to Abel I asked him to do me a
favor I asked him to create a gol Canada
mantra he started working on it but
apparently he was having troubles
getting snowed to generates a nice and
that so he's probably not gonna complete
it this is all he has have it done so
far isn't very much but yeah I thought
the thought it was pretty cool I hope
you guys don't mind me installing it
thought it was interesting thought you'd
like to see it but yeah I think that's
it for today guys a short episode short
confession I hope you guys don't take it
too hard I don't plan on installing any
other mods so just this one for now
anyway okay thank you for watching
that's so cool installing the mod broke
my another portal somehow - it's almost
like this portal has to be here for some
reason I don't know why but what I
forgot to say is I am going to update my
world and put a link to download it
again in the description as normal so if
you guys want to check out this mod you
can you don't need to have it installed
to look at it in my world which is
pretty cool I'm not sure exactly how
that works but if you want to check it
out just enter my world go down here and
the portal to the nether is down there
so have fun bye bye