what's up to fools is etho here and
today's Saturday I've got a headache
didn't really feel like doing anything
today so I've been playing Minecraft for
about 3 or 4 hours now which is a lot
for me and I want to show you what I've
been up to working on the storage room
got lots done kind of cool I think I
don't know
aha
and yeah so
a little bit different than I was
expecting it to be I'm quite happy with
it though I really like these uh this
window area looks cool what I've done is
I've I've put the item in the window
here so since you can see from a
distance that there's birch wood in
there so look inside and of course there
is and I decided to use my glowstone so
it's permanent I'm not moving it or
changing anything I got four down below
four above originally I was planning on
like having a wooden pillar that went
all the way to the ceiling and in the
center there was going to be redstone
wiring that would connect to a rapid for
dispenser and I would have a buttons and
levers and stuff and it would shoot out
two cobblestone or whatever but I've
decided not to do that because I would
need to have four of them one for each
corner and since my world is leggy
enough as it is adding four more
redstone clocks would have made things
much worse because every redstone clock
you use severely legs your game so I
decide to do it this way and it's not
done yet I still have to do this part
here and while I was working on this
door area here I noticed it looked a lot
like a creepers mouth
and so I checked and sure enough it did
so I just put Blackwell added the eyes
and now I got a creeper there and he is
to remind me because in my mind I got do
all the exterior yet too but in my mind
this is like the front of the house or
whatever you call it warehouse storage
room and so this guy here is a reminder
for me what's outside every time I leave
the building and a glass here sand stone
sand gravel
um I need I'm going to try in like make
sure area above this glass here stays
uncovered by levels two three and four
because if I place any solid blocks over
this glass it's going to get really dark
in these corners so that's an extra
challenge for me and oh yeah I got I
really like having like water in my
houses I don't know why but ever since
I've been playing Minecraft I always
have to have water at least somewhere in
my house so that's kind of why I have
these and they will probably be like
secret entrances to a basement too
because I'll probably hollow it out down
here and make further floors underneath
the storage room as well and yeah
today's gonna be a bit of a slower
episode guys because I'm not feeling
well
and I've never actually shown you guys
how I've organized things so maybe I'll
explain that a bit so obviously we have
our wool or cloth color wheel here and
the solid nothing in there solid colored
blocks go on the bottom and then the
dyes go on top so that's a method I have
there then over here is for mob drops
and things relating to them so I got TNT
gunpowder string leather bone arrows
feathers Flint Flint's not really a mob
drop but it's kind of goes together
because you need Flint to make arrows
and feathers so and the reason why that
stuff is over here is because it's close
to my collection point here makes it
easy to drop stuff off and over here we
have kind of the odd odd blocks I think
this is a jukebox and these are note
blocks they look the same unfortunately
here we have precious ores that's all my
diamonds Gold's iron coal represented by
black wool lots of clay brick this side
here I have dedicated to food items I
got every food item here at cake sugar
eggs milk wheat bread apples mushroom
soup raw chops raw chops represented by
pink cooked jobs cooked jobs
represented by the grilled meat look and
raw fish cook fish on this side we have
different tools clocks compasses fishing
rods flint and steel shoes pants chest
plates helmets your mom axes shovels
picks swords bows to empty spots over
here is like plants and stuff things
that grow get saplings yellow flowers
red stew red roses seeds mushrooms sugar
cane cactus so everything is grouped
together pretty nicely I think over here
is like switches and stuff that wood
doors iron doors and things affected by
switches wood plates stone plates
buttons levers I'm probably going to
move boats to over here because I
realized that I'll have one for mine
carts so I'll probably have my carts and
boats here and I might have a free spot
open there and this is kind of like misc
random items slime balls I got a few of
those torches redstone torches redstone
dust repeaters fences signs ladders
paintings bed saddles records water
buckets empty lab a buckets on this side
we have like partial blocks so we got
the four different half steps and two
different types of stairs it's cool and
here we have more kind of random blocks
so that's how I got things organized
it's all kind of grouped together I
planned it out in a Word documents I
think I got every block covered pretty
much so that's good and the way the
color like I can't really place leather
anyway or string on gunpowder so I'm
using colors to help me recognize what
which is which gunpowder is kind of gray
so I use grade string as whites whites
whites leather is kind of that color
bone arrows feathers are all pretty much
white so I just did all the different
shades they're still got to put a few
more things up here not quite sure how
I'm going to do it over here yet I'll
probably replace this wood with
something and yeah
and then inside we have the control room
which is still not done there's going to
be a roof over this so it will look nice
and I might reduce the number of these
options like I kind of don't think I
need to have wool because I'll need to
get the skeletons into a fight manually
and so I'm pretty much selecting that I
want wool by doing that so I don't
really need a lever to do that because
I've pretty much chosen it by my actions
if that makes sense the levers are
pretty much only four things I can
automatically do without me controlling
things I can automatically sort string
out without doing anything and so that's
how that's going to work still don't
have my minecart setup I haven't really
attempted it have really received a lot
of feedback from you guys on how I could
do this so thank you for that I think I
got it pretty much figured out in my
head I just need to actually do it
sometime just too hard I hope it's a bit
challenging to make the man carts go all
the way around cause that is a long
distance so something that's a little
bit of an issue yet is the lighting I've
had expected this from the beginning
that the lighting was going to be a
problem
um not exactly sure how I want to do it
originally I'm just going to do
something like this these torches kind
of dropped from the ceiling looks kind
of cool but there's way too many of them
so I'm not sure if I'm going to do it
like this even think you may be taking
the middle out I don't know the other
issue is these lights don't really do
anything because they're so high up I
would kind of like more light towards
these buttons but it's not really a big
deal on vinyl the way it is ah the thing
that really is bothering me is these
torches I have lining the the tracks
look a little strange because they're
sticking out
and yet I kind of need them there I like
how they're spaced but I can't really
use glowstone because I don't have
hundreds of oil stone can't really use
pumpkins because I don't have hundreds
of pumpkins can't use lava because lava
will catch your wood on fire so I don't
know I can't use sunlight because
there's going to be the other levels
above this probably so yeah lighting is
kind of an issue another alternative to
doing the lighting the ceiling is
something like this maybe tell me
what-what you guys like more like this
or like this
because I'm kind of in-between the two
I like the torches along the logs here
that was really thick and I like the
glowstone where it is these corners are
lit up pretty good actually I like the
way I have this and I like these torches
here all the rounds and the signs are a
little bit thin but I can read them
pretty good I don't I still need to get
six more glowstone to which sucks and
let's see what else should we do oh yeah
it's going to say them probably going to
move these furnaces and stuff I'll
probably have would like the planks
where the furnaces are and then maybe
this type of wood in the corner this
because it looks kind of stupid I don't
like the way the dispensers look really
but unfortunately there is no wood
colored dispensers not much I can do
about that and I was going to talk about
future plans too at the moment I don't
have a very good view of this windows
here looking into the side of a cliff
doesn't look very good um that's pretty
cool
um yeah I do plan on building like more
more rooms than this this is just one
room like it's just a start out here
there's no creepers I have been getting
creepers a lot lately
somewhere around here I'm going to have
a tactus farm and a reed farm and maybe
a wheat farm with the delivery system
set up ah
let's see last ayah out here I'm going
to set up an each row to this island I
think I'm going to change this thing
around because it's not really working
because normally I make them eat wide I
wanted to try make one seven wide it's
too many issues so and I plan on doing a
lot of terraforming around here too
it's not going to be this ugly
looking landscape and I will be doing
the exterior of the building but I'm
going to wait till I get more stuff do
it first
and I'll be doing a little bit around
these pipes here and not quite sure
where I'm going to in the front but I'll
figure something out you know originally
I picked this world because I liked the
look of the grass and how I killed all
the grass which is kind of sad but I've
been thinking of maybe using this green
as fake grass I don't know
Green is my favorite color pretty close
to that color
I once I set up a cactus farm I might
start laying fake grass everywhere and
someone else what else at some point of
time I think we need to build like an
underwater base somewhere because
there's just so much ocean in this world
and it's deep in a lot of places
so it'd be a crime not to and yeah my
TNT supply is up to this plus I have
another stack of 64 still haven't
started the cannons but I will get to
that very soon
still got 300 subscribers to go I think
well anyways guys I think that's about
the end of this episode I thank you for
watching I hope it wasn't too boring but
I know we've just been walking around in
storage room but like I said I'm not
feeling well today and not feeling very
ambitious so and I put a lot of work
into the storage room and I didn't want
to get too far ahead I thought you guys
seen it
and as well I think it's important that
you guys know a little bit about the
plans of what's going on and why I made
the decisions I did in this world like a
lot of planning and organizing did go
into this storage room that you guys
might not have really thought about or
realized unless I pointed it out to you
like even when I originally decided on
the size of it and everything I first
figured out how many different types of
blocks there were and that's kind of how
I got the size of the storage room
that's why it's so big there's so many
different blocks and you know there's
lots of settled details that you might
not think about like these three
redstone items are organized together
they're not like one here one here one
here so little nice details like that
all around the storage room a lot of
work went into this
and other things too like just so
happens 12 items fit here pretty nicely
that don't really go into any other
categories or
and on the other side there also is
another 12 items I figured that out
added them up all technically it's 10
because I doubled these ones but that's
in case future food items get added too
and yeah I mean happy it's done I was
really not sure how I was going to do
these corners until just last night I
figured it out I built them one way and
I wasn't happy with how it looks so I
redid it at first I focused on the looks
the second time and it turned out much
better this is the first first attempt I
just put a bunch of chests around and it
looked really bad so yep quite happy
with it let me know what you guys think
you got any ideas things I should change
let me know the only one I won't listen
to is if you tell me to move the
glowstone because this is staying right
where it is okay thank you guys have a
good night