hello hello
this is etho
and i don't mind they're just having a
party on my roof
how's it going everybody uh
i've been working on the treat on the
slime farm a little bit
i wasn't really sure how i was doing it
last episode
i got a little bit of a better idea now
but one thing i did decide is that i
wanted to
make a switch so that i could turn the
slime farm on or off
and i came up with a pretty easy way of
doing that
which most of you suggested to me too
just using water
here we are at the slime farm
sometimes i find the slime balls just
randomly
[Applause]
on the ground like these suffocates
somehow
but yeah this is uh this is what i got
so far it's not done yet
as you can see these are pistons all
along here
they're sticky pistons
all along this side all along the side
i had plenty of slime balls to make them
thankfully
and i just have it lit up in here right
now
so that you guys can see
i need to put lights in the ceiling
though
because these torches are going to get
washed away
but maybe i'll show you the wiring here
just just stay put guys stay put i'll be
back
so i'll have a lever
and this wire here activates all the
pistons
and every so often there's a repeater
uh piston over here still gets activated
by this wire
one over here gets activated by the
repeater
one over here gets activated by the wire
again this kind of goes around
like that
[Applause]
and it goes all the way around
doing the same thing
just like that
one thing i kind of decided is i don't
want to have any pistons running on a
loop in my world because
because i find they uh like the game a
lot
so i don't really want any continuously
running
elevators or anything like that
so if i'm gonna make anything with
pistons
they need to be manually activated
that's kind of what i want
so like this even though this causes a
lot of lag
to switch this on and off it's manually
activated oh
ah
there's actually a lot of slimes down
here
yeah i'll show you how this works
nice got a lever over here flick it
water gates come all the slimes get
pushed
to that corner there
that one's stuck on the chest it's not
supposed to be there
[Applause]
they can't fight the currents
uh one thing i did find out though is i
need to change this water here because
it's pushing me back
[Applause]
but yeah that's all i got so far
and they'll all kind of go towards a
corner like that
[Applause]
yeah it's kind of challenging to make a
slime farm
that's a weird shape like this because
there's only three chunks where they
could spawn
there we go
but this seems to work okay this is
actually very simple
i was going to do like spawning pads and
stuff but it just
didn't seem like it was going to make
sense because if i was to have water
come out of the
out of the ceiling onto the spawning
pads i would need to make the spawning
pads a diamond
shape for the water to go all over the
spawning pads
which would be fine but okay seriously
it would be fine but you can't have
water canals
on diamond shaped spawning pads so
didn't really uh make much sense so i
just did a
totally flat land like this i might make
it two levels still i'm not sure
and i gotta change all this
[Applause]
my armor is almost all done
okay but anyway my plan is i kind of
want
a few options here
one thing i'll probably do is i'll make
a little ladder elevator to bring the
slimes to the surface
much like uh roboticos uses
i'll probably copy his slime
slime evader thing but i also want to be
able to transport
the big slimes to the surface just
because i think that would be cool
so i'll probably make another
elevator thing for them it'll probably
be slower
but i'll have a way of getting the big
ones to the surface too
hopefully anyway
this isn't what i'm going to be working
on this episode we're going to do
something else
okay there's a few other things i should
probably mention about my
slime farm plan here um
obviously when the water is all over the
ground like that no slimes will be able
to spawn down here so that's how you can
shut slime spawning off
the water will also push them to
the slime evaders i'll probably have two
in this corner somewhere not entirely
sure how i'm
reading that up yet uh
so the water does two things shut slime
spawning off and it also pushes them
unlike my hostile mob system with that
the mobs are automatically killed and
their items are automatically delivered
constantly and you can either pick them
up
or if you don't you'll miss them and
items will despawn
with slimes though they don't spawn
nearly as often as hostile mobs so i
don't want their items just
being automatically delivered because i
might miss them if i do that
so uh
slime ball collection will be done
manually by flicking a lever
cause the water to flow to bring the
slimes up a slime elevator
and possibly to a killing chamber above
is the plan
the way slime spawning works is a little
bit
weird the
spawn on hard if you switch at the
peaceful though
they don't disappear well they spawn on
easy
normal or hard the little ones will
spawn on peaceful
the tiniest ones but if you switch it to
peaceful the big ones don't disappear
which is nice for my what i've heard
also they don't
despawn if you're within 128
blocks from them and that's in a
spherical
three-dimensional distance
so if i'm in my base these guys that
spawn down here shouldn't disappear
until until i kill them which is good
because we're only we're only about
60 blocks below the surface
and my base is definitely not 60 blocks
away from here so it's definitely within
range
uh for for this here i need to make this
three high so that the big guys
can spawn on here and not not split
i also need to light it up so that the
other hostile mobs don't spawn i'll
probably just put torches
in the ceiling because
they should light up the ground decently
enough
i may also just use glowstone on the
ground
although i'm not sure if uh
if slimes can spawn on top of glowstone
it's kind of kind of an unknown thing i
think
because obviously hostile mobs can't
because
light stone emits light so
hostile mobs can't spawn on it so i
don't know if anyone knows if science
can
or not but i'm kind of guessing they can
but i don't want to take the risk
without knowing
yeah so i'm going to work on this some
more later let's go do something else so
some of my longtime subscribers might
remember this
this is my ultra simple mob trap
just walk in all the doors close and the
mob is
stuck in here and can't get out
it was a neat little thing problem was
often
the tall mobs would get stuck on the
door hinges
joker hd reminded me of this other day
and i kind of
came up with a new way
using pistons again
ultra ultra simple
[Applause]
nothing fancy
just use sticky pistons oh no what you
do is you put uh
you put a redstone wire underneath here
like that your pressure plate on top
and then sticky pistons around
like that and then
put your spikes in
and something over top
that's the new ultra
ultra simple mob trap
and they're stuck and there's absolutely
no way for media out of here
[Music]
you can also chain many of them together
i believe
just like that and you can make a giant
grid of them
fun stuff
they'll also uh kill like small mobs
like chickens
and i found they killed little slimes
when the
[Applause]
when the blocks go up
so yeah that's the new super simple
mob trap
right i guess we should test this out to
make sure it works
as well because i haven't tried it yet
oh we don't want spiders
[Music]
there's a bunch of guys over here
oops
creeper and a spider
awesome
how's he going in there
oh this is scary
cool let's try skeletons i don't think
they'll be able to hit you
when they're in there because they got
the
ceiling over top
cool
yeah that's the simple mob trap revised
so one other thing i wanted to work on
this episode just a little bit
is the uh hostile mob system
this spider setup things still working
great
i tried adding like piston crushers at
the top of it
to crush the spiders that were
activated when the spider touched the
pressure plate
i should have got it on camera but i
didn't it worked
pretty good but i found it was lagging
my game a lot
like every time it activated i did a
huge like spike
so i got rid of it
like i said i don't want to have pistons
constantly
being used in my world
like automatically like that so
i got rid of it because it was causing
lag
so at the moment the tall mobs are just
falling down here on top of my roof
which is a big issue i've actually had
my house
blow up and not my house my storage room
blew up
in a few places already so i should get
this
taken care of
so i'll have the tall mobs
come out here
and i'm gonna add a
junction here
right right above it's probably really
hard to see
yeah i want a junction right here i'm
going to use pistons
to do my mob junctions now i think
really i don't see much use in using
trapdoors anymore
just kind of kind of
kind of disappointing i guess
what's the best way of doing this
the sticky piston here maybe
still have trouble placing them
there we go
okay maybe i'll just have a lever here
to test it for now
oh you know what i built in the wrong
place
try again let's go over one
okay sandstone was there
and the sticky piston goes there
the library bows here
good
okay that should work fine and dandy
so if the sandstone is there there's a
the roof is solid otherwise there's a
hole here
now i'm going to make them swim up this
hole if it's open
i'm just going to put a pressure plate
down here to hold some water back
temporarily water will go here
and see
signs and stuff
[Music]
another pressure plates
i think one right there
and a sign here
one here oh no
actually i don't want to do that
i'm gonna move this over one
extend this again and we'll put another
sign
here
water like that
no dead zones it's good so the mobs will
try to swim up here
[Music]
and they should be able to if it's open
i'm going to
oh this might be a problem
i can't put a sign here to hold water
back
could be a serious flaw
let's see
and sorry about the lighting i know it's
really dark
okay i'll try it like this and see what
happens
[Applause]
and build it up and i'll just
put the cap on top
[Applause]
[Music]
okay and maybe just dig a hole in the
ground here
[Music]
and lock this off
and hopefully this works i'm going to
get some mops up here and see
if the junction works
yeah so it's definitely not working uh
the downward water flow is preventing
them from swimming up
so i'll have to do something else
so i got a working method now guys this
uh use pistons again except we have a
horizontal junction here this works much
like the door junctions work that i used
to use
just have a diagonal stream
right now this path here is closed
because this block is in the way
but this one's open if you flip the
lever
this path is closed
but this one is open so
it's pretty simple uh
this torch here i believe inverts one of
the pistons so
uh if one of them's out the other one's
in
and pretty pretty basic
uh now that i think about the one other
thing i could did is i
could have just had a trapdoor with
where the prison
where the piston was before
and i think that would have solved my
problem
with them not being able to swim up
because i could have had like a water
block trap door
and a water block above and they would
be able to swim through
the trap door
but it doesn't matter this way works
fine for me
it's nice that it splits some left and
right over here so they're far apart
uh i believe this path here will lead to
the cook house i'll probably just make
uh
actually i think what i'm going to do is
i'm going to make a tower that goes up
they'll swim up they'll fall down and
take
as much fall damage as they can without
killing them
and they'll be a light source above so
if they are
skeletons or zombies they will burn in
the light if it's daytime
and creepers
can then be taken out they'll only be
creepers
left uh this other path
is going to lead directly to a chilling
chamber to kill all three of them
and the loot will run
into here and hopefully i'll be able to
turn it on and off
like i did with the spider one
like this
that's the plan so i might do that off
camera
well that's where i'm gonna end the
episode today guys uh
i'm gonna keep working on that slime
farm
and i will keep working on the hostile
mob system i'll probably do those things
i said
and i may also add like a lighting
switch to the hostile spawning
pads below so that i can turn
that on and off like i can with the
slime farm and i think that would be a
good idea
i still haven't come up with any great
ideas for my new base but i'll be
thinking about it
and then we may start a new base
highly efficient and thought out
unlike this one here
although this one's pretty cool too
uh yeah secret project
is going very slowly don't expect it
anytime
soon i got the foundation laid and
that's about it
but it's coming along and
i think that's all i'm gonna say uh
oh yeah i was uh every now and then i
look at my
subscriber numbers and view counts and
stuff using a
website called socialblade it keeps
track of
the growth of your youtube channel
and lately i've noticed mine has jumped
quite a bit the last few days
i thought it was from uh co-star
gave me a mention in one of his recent
videos
and i got a huge boost in subscribers
from that but i've also noticed my view
town has gone up like
it's like 1.5 times what it normally is
which i thought was kind of strange
uh i thought it was from the mention
from cole yeah
definitely helped but uh i think i
realized what also was contributing to
that
kids are out of school so congrats guys
i hope you have a good summer and i hope
you enjoy
watching my videos during your summer
and i will see
plenty of you so
that's it for today thanks for watching
see you again next time
yada yada take care