oh yeah
[Applause]
[Music]
why why why did you do this well it's
because I'm excited that's why I
realized something I can't be excited I
can't sound excited with my voice I can
show that I'm excited by my actions
I'm excited why am I so excited because
my youtube partnership finally went
through so I'm approved everything's
good and that took forever to do that
red tape every step of the way yes my
partnership went through and that took
months actually they don't tell you
whether or not you're approved or not me
anyways for like two months I think then
I finally did get approved and I went to
complete the complete the partnership
they send you a link with a few more
steps you got to do when I clicked on
the link it's like sent me to a webpage
with an internal server error and then
monkeys ate your web page so even though
I was approved I wasn't able to become a
partner because there was problems on
youtubes end so that took another two or
three weeks
finally after waiting and waiting
sending in bugs reports and stuff like
that my request finally went through so
I'm a full blown partner and I'm signed
up for Google Ads adsense now
so good news bad news good news on a
partner bad news there's probably going
to be ads my videos now so yeah sorry
about that guys let's fight to make
money for playing video games I'm going
to do it and I'm sure you would too and
if anybody hates ads the most it's
probably me I really hate ads but yet at
the same time it's a love-hate
relationship because I hate them I hate
watching them so much and yet I love
them because without them we wouldn't
have radio stations and television
stations they're probably no YouTube and
countless other websites on the internet
wouldn't work without ads so they are a
necessity to get the things we enjoy and
so I have no problem taking part of that
but yeah I hate ads but I don't complain
about them because of that and also
because there is always ways around ads
like I don't listen to radio commercials
because I have an mp3 player a Zune go
ahead and make fun of me if you want
they are better than iPods and I don't
watch commercials on TV because I
download or stream all my television
shows which are commercial free and I
don't see any ads on the internet
because I have adblock installed so
don't complain about ads deal with them
or find ways around them that's my
philosophy because they are required in
life but yeah oh yeah I was gonna say
this last episode but congrats the SC
joiner for coming uh or for getting a
thousand subscribers now that's awesome
also thanks to brandy beast for
your YouTube help it's starting to come
in handy now that I'm a partner and
hopefully everything we're so good and
hopefully you guys don't mind the ads
too much
but yeah unn with the show yeah you know
we got squid they must have just spawned
I'm gonna leave these guys be and see if
they end up in my collection point and a
lot of you said that's we don't de-spawn
that's not true they do I don't know
exactly how that works but it seems to
take a long time and eventually they do
give it a little push you can make it
buddy you're almost there you're almost
there fine enjoy the rest of your life
[Music]
okay now I forgot what I was gonna say
we've caught me off guard oh yeah in
case you didn't to figure this out
already I didn't actually blow up the
world
I made it backed up and I'm gonna
release a backup or I'm going to release
a new upload of my world in the
description of this video for you guys
to download if you want and I'm not
going to release any more updates until
after the five thousand five thousand
subscriber special
because I don't want I'm gonna start
building our cannons for the special and
I don't want anyone watching the display
before the 5000 subscribers special and
yeah the clay is still here yeah there
forever or until I feel like it if you
guys are wondering about the donations
I'm not going to update you every single
episode because I don't want to give the
impression that I'm begging or anything
like that although I just in a sense I
kind of been but at the moment I am at
34 donors and one thousand eighty five
dollars and 51 cents so very cool guys
thank you very much much appreciated I
know some of you are like kids that are
wanting to donate that's kind of funny
to me I don't know if I actually want
you to donate because you know 10 bucks
to you guys it's probably a lot more
than it is to me because I'm a lot older
than you and I have real bills to pay
and I make real money to have a job so
if you're a kid you know save your money
and buy something fun for yourself or
for your friends or family instead of
donating to me
unless you come from a wealthy family
than I don't feel bad about it
everyone else keep donating if you want
of course now that I'm a YouTube partner
I will be making money from
advertisements and stuff I can't be
goofing around this is my little world
um let's go and do what we were doing
last episode alright here we are at in
their giant blob faucet thing testing
testing uh good gravity the tool first
time trying to water
I didn't look too good I think the water
cushion the fall way too much I'm gonna
try lengthen the water all the way and
see if they still survive at one two
three four five six seven eight so
that's the lowest the water can go
[Music]
obviously the water wouldn't be going
this way but I just want to check in
please take damage or not because
ideally after they fall I want to have a
water current to take them away quickly
so that they don't get in the way of
another mob as it falls otherwise the
second mob probably won't get injured
leave it then I think a lot of these
suggested I should drown them on the way
up to I might try that I don't know how
reliable it will be though
what I'm worried about all right here
comes the creeper
hmm the waters nothing work and this is
where I speak okay so we might have to
go back to one of those other methods we
tried last time actually I'm gonna try
drown them first to see how that works
here we go again
we're gonna try drowning on this time
I've made this quite a bit bigger I kind
of just how high I would need to make it
hopefully they don't drown on their way
up I mean like completely drown
[Music]
it's too big I'm going to make it small
so I've adjusted it and it seems to be a
little bit unreliable
sometimes they drown on their way up
sometimes they don't one hint that's
good that's what we want one hit you hit
the ground I appreciate that skeleton
and you didn't die
so I've been watching the sink for a few
minutes and I've concluded that drowning
is a fair bit less reliable than
weakening weakening the mobs with
gravity one shot the odd time they will
actually drown in this tube shot and
sometimes it down in there too sometimes
they take up the three hits to kill
after they get out so yeah
I'm probably gonna stick to gravity how
about not exactly sure how I'm gonna do
that yet since it has issues to be two
shots I don't want to do the I don't
want to shoot them with dispensers
because that's not really a long-term
method I don't think because it'll take
four arrows every mob that goes through
and I'm sure it'll have problems too so
gravity is still the winner in my
opinion some of you suggest I should use
slow sand and do a setup like I had last
episode with the horizontal thing with
the lava I don't think that's a good
idea either because if the mobs bump
each other around it's going to change
things quite a bit
so yeah gravity seems to be the winner
at the moment someone also suggested
that I have like water block a lab uh
that they have to swim up and then water
to put out the flames I've actually
tried that before they can almost make
it all the way up but they died in the
lava and flames don't work as this cows
about to demonstrate they always kill
the the mob unless you distinguish it
but yep so gravity is a winner let's go
check on us wits if they made it to the
collection points and yeah I'm not gonna
use cactus either because cactus are
almost always a bad idea
oh it's probably the worst time little
squid hunting especially when you can't
find your collection point others I
think I see some squid yep we caught two
and that was only probably fifteen to
thirty minutes
I see there's one over there still let's
go see why he didn't want to come looks
like there's a hole in my floor yeah so
you got stuck in a hole Hey oops gotta
fill those all up otherwise you'll have
that problem some more holes here and is
our other guy over here still yes how's
it going down there I'll probably just
leave them there it's nice to have a pet
anyways that's it for today guys thank
you again for watching and yeah I'm open
for ideas and I'll see you next time