hello everybody this is etho and we're
back again here at the barn we're gonna
be working on the Barney on this episode
and I haven't really done anything since
last episode because I haven't had time
to so let's get to work
I was really secretive last episode
about what I'm doing here so I'll just
give you a quick explanation of things
this wall I'm leaving blank at the
moment because I'm going to be putting
the squid aquarium here so all my squid
are gonna collect to some sort of
aquarium here inside here is where
wolves are gonna be stored and if I want
I can come into my barn and tame them I
might create a storage system to for
them somewhere eventually so by the time
the animals come to the barn I've
decided that I want to store them here
so the sheep-shearing if I do that will
be will happen sooner and I will have an
option to either shear them somewhere
over there or else have them run all the
way over here and sheared and these
platforms these blocks these sandstone
blocks are where the cows and sheep are
going to be stored and I can come in
here and die sheep if I want or milk
cows or or just look at them and laugh
it's up to me so the trick here that I'm
going to be doing is separating them so
only one sheep and one or one cow will
be on each of these platforms is my goal
so to do this I came up with a trick
when making the record studio I've
discovered it when I was trying to
let's see where do I want when I was
trying to separate the skeleton so they
wouldn't shoot each other that's gonna
put them each into their own holding
area but that didn't work because more
than one skeleton can fit in a one by
one area so I just abandoned that but
for this I think it'll work because
cheaper fatter than skeletons and other
tall mops and so are cows
actually no I'm just gonna fill the
solid and then break out the blocks I
don't want and I'm making this three
high just so it's not so claustrophobic
in here this might cause a problem later
though how's everybody doing how's the
family
that's good that's good we should get
together sometime
okay okay I'm gonna finish this up this
is getting boring okay I got that done
now um I shouldn't add one here in all
the corners you figure out how this
works yet I'll hopefully explain it
better in just a little bit
oh okay so we need to run blocks all the
way around and there's gonna be a wall
for the sheep and cows to walk into
that's what I'm adding here that will
help align them properly select they'll
fall down these holes but since I made
this soups well I'm gonna finish this
first and I'll say what I was going to
say okay there since I made this three
hi I really should probably make it too
high but I just don't want the ceilings
so low I'm gonna have to raise these a
block and I think I'm just gonna put
glass on top of all of these so mob
stand job excuse me mobs can jump one
block they can't jump a block and a half
in height so that's kind of the
principle behind this
that's one full block but we have an
extra half block here so they won't be
able to jump out of these holes once
they fall in them
so that's one important key to this the
other key is since they'll probably be
jumping around here if another sheep
tries to walk into the same hole or a
sheep or cows tries to walking in the
same hole as another animal they're
jumping around we'll bump the sheet back
and they won't be able to fall down the
hole as well so that's the other key to
this so they'll just randomly walk
around here and eventually they'll fall
into one of these holes that's free
hopefully again I haven't tested this to
see if it actually works
and I'm gonna be pretty mad if it
doesn't I'm not mad but you know upset
I might even rage quit so I'm just
making making the wall here okay now I
think I'm just gonna add an inside thing
here too and then I'll probably make the
rest glass so I can see them walking
around up here and so I'm gonna run that
tube over there all the way here and
it's gonna land it's gonna drop them on
to this level I'm making right now
and the Wolves are gonna their pipe is
over there there I think not over there
and I have to run that here - whoa leg
all right excellent so yeah man probably
put class oh you know what I might want
to raise it yeah I think I'm actually
going to raise this one block just for
looks oh I do not like doing this okay
well I'm gonna finish that up off-camera
because it'll take a while and then
we'll be back and I might run some of
these pipes okay so here's where we're
at right now I added a glass roof to
this there's a water break here and
another water cushion down here for the
wolfes land and I'll probably be
changing this a bit yet because it
doesn't quite look great all right so
the sheep and the cows are you're gonna
fall down this hole here unfortunately
since I set it up this way there's not
an even probability of them falling into
each of these holes they're more likely
to favor this quarter here I think these
holes in this area here and less likely
to favor the ones over here but it's
fine they'll walk around and eventually
they'll fill up all the holes the other
pipe here is for the Wolves they'll fall
down
this from here is the plan so rather
than having a two pipes leading here I'm
just gonna have one single fat pipe I
think which will be achieved by making
it six wide I think it's probably
impossible to see now it's dark I have
the other thing we need this to be high
enough I've got a three high clearance
here so the animals are free to walk
around however they choose without
bumping their heads on anything but
again the problem is this pipe is in the
way so they will run into it but it
doesn't matter much okay so I'm gonna
run a pipe from here all the way to
there and I'm somehow gonna connect the
wolf pipe and the cow and sheep pipe
together here's just a little quick
update of how it's going and it's a big
pipe that's for sure wrap around like so
so this is one of them this one goes to
where the wolves go and the path next to
it goes to the cow and sheep area so I
have to hook this one up to this pipe
here somehow and dull give you another
update soon alright guy she's mostly all
done here now so let's see how this
works I had a hard time testing this
because when a passive mob stop spawning
and I can't get them to spawn again aw
crap
well I didn't have time to get them
working again so I stopped playing
minecraft and I've been busy with work
three days later I started minecraft and
they are spawning again so that clip
just seems to fix itself over time as
well because when I left playing
minecraft before it wasn't working and
now it is hot dang it which makes me
think it's actually programmed into the
game on purpose and it's not a glitch is
what I'm thinking now so let's see I
have a big circle here which is kind of
a problem because it takes them a lot
longer to fall down the holes if I made
a smaller circle they would fall down
the whole spots sooner and I've added
these soil blocks here because I think
they slightly helped them to fall down
easier helps to align them better but
I'm not sure if it's actually better
yeah they're sure not falling down
it takes them a while but they do fall
down eventually cow just went down so
when they fall down they jump for a
while but then I noticed they stopped
jumping so I'm not sure how well this
actually works I'm gonna add a block
here this will be a block and a half
still so they can still walk in see the
F after enough time they fall down so
it's kind of a successive project and
it's kind of a fail and I think I'm
gonna add a half slab here I keep
pressing a scoop until I haven't played
Minecraft in a while because when they
were falling down they were sometimes
taking damage so you still have a block
and a half clearance here but they
shouldn't take damage when they fall now
and can see they have stopped jumping so
I think it might be possible for them to
walk into the same hole as another
animal actually because mobs are like
the sheep and cows are less than a block
and a half in height so this is kind of
level ground here let's go down so the
idea is when they fall like this they
would automatically fall into their
little separate things on their own
automatically and then when we come to
the burn these things were all supposed
to be full and we could milk the cows if
we want if they give us milk why am I
not getting milk oh I had some I had
some three four five six seven eight
nine ten
give me your milk
that's weird what am I doing wrong here
guys I thought I'd get milk doing this I
didn't have some when I was clicking
this Jack okay well anyway and the other
thing is we would be able to dye the
sheep when we come in here and then we
can hit them their wool Falls neatly on
these little blocks here and my other
idea was the Wolves land in here if the
doors are open that they would be able
to free roam in this barn and kill the
Sheep automatically as well but I think
that she might be too high now for them
to do that I don't know because I
haven't seen any wolves yet
let's look at the the piping here how it
is okay this is where the wolf separator
is guys they come and then it's before
it would keep going straight here I
removed all that instead it goes the
right here now and it goes up this
little staircase thing no dead zones
this is for the Wolves goes goes goes
and then they fall down and the Sheep
one I just I shortened the pipe there
and made it go off here they fall down
there's a water break so they don't take
fall damage and then this dream takes
them along again with no dead zones
which is important and that's basically
how it works and the barn is close
enough to my storage room that I'll
likely be within 32 blocks of these guys
so they won't despawn as I'm doing stuff
away from here which is also important
but I'm gonna keep tweeting this again
it would work better if I made it
smaller which it does seem to be pretty
random though like which holes they fall
in despite this pipe in the middle and
yeah that's that's what I've been
building guys so eventually I'm going to
build this width arm I don't like that I
can't get out of here now I'll probably
make a passage up here too so that it
can come and walk in this area and I'll
have it covered too yet yeah so the Swit
farm goes here and I'll probably have a
walkway somewhere around here so I can
go up to the next level here and that is
the plan guys so thank you for watching
if you got ideas let me know I'll be
tweaking this to make it better and this
wolf thing doesn't look very good so
I'll be changing it as well I might even
get rid of these doors I don't know and
yeah so thank you for watching guys and
I'll see you again next time