hey guys this is lethal how's it going
as many of you guys probably know the
beta version 1.4 team up today a lot of
you guys are excited about it I am too
now and so this episode I'm going to
dedicate to it there's been a few
changes in the game and we're going to
look into some of these and of course
one of the major changes is they added a
new type of mob the wolves so I figure
one thing we should do this episode
we're going to do it right away is we're
going to go and try find a wolf and so
we get to go on another adventure for
science yay so I'm going to get some
supplies here and apparently they're
pretty rare so I don't know how long
it's going to take us to find one might
be a couple minutes might be the whole
episode or you know it might might not
even happen
so we'll see I'm going to make it
sword let's mind about to break
and yeah so it should be fun
I think they only spawn in certain two
biomes I think they have to be in a
forest and we're going to need I got
arrows I need some bone to tame them you
contain them and then they'll follow you
around I think and yeah let's go
adventure well that was fast man that
didn't take long at all ah yeah rare my
but these things are so easy to get all
right let's go minions on your feet oh
there's so many of them so many of you
have been wondering Oh what happened to
the mob system with the new patch well
take a Jess
I think the wolves I have is a pretty
good indication that's working fine so
the first time I took them off for a
walk okay you know what we're gonna do
we're gonna go and find some mobs to
kill let's go to the other mob system I
have by general spazzes house hopefully
all fall oh whoa
they're bumping my poor all over the
place yeah they're kind of glitchy at
the moments they and they leg the game
like crazy if you have I think I got 17
now and for some reason they're not
coming up they're here
oh yeah and so one interesting thing is
these guys will attack sheep and cows
and stuff if they're a neutral I'm kind
of lost but they won't when you tame
them so that's going to make things a
little interesting with my mob system oh
no I think one just died hopefully we'll
get some mobs here pretty quick I see
one don't fall down the hole guys don't
fall down that one either oh man I got
lava here that's not good oh right I got
this thing set up not something to work
what
it's okay guys I kind of want to take
the hostage stand it on attack peaches
Wow
I can tell how much house they have
fighter tales his fans tales all the way
down Rosie's little now pretty much for
long health all that there's a ton of
loss of it
yeah yes so I'm a bad guy I told you up
a little bit evil but I actually don't
like killing these guys that sighs
hoping a creeper would do it for me
because I wanted to try something and I
need to get rid of these guys to do it
so unfortunately this feels wrong there
- cut - nice I wish I wish a we did evil
when you attack them then it wouldn't
feel so bad
days so everything is working still and
what I'm curious to see is how long it
will take for wolves to spawn so let's
kind of watch them for a bit
most of these pads won't to work with me
up here just the ones kind of the very
back corner there oh look there's a
brown sheep that's the first one I've
seen I kind of thought they went into I
want to get that brown sheep
why can't I get you it's the first brown
rule with up alright back for watching
so another thing has changed is the
water currents are a lot more powerful
now most people don't like that I think
that's going to be good and we'll look
into it a little bit more at the end of
this episode that there's a wolf
yes Oh something really weird happened
today it's probably the most confused
I've ever been in Minecraft ah so the
new patch came out today and I was
excited and I logged into minecraft and
I came over here you know I got this
pipe extended now it's still not fully
set up so the annals are just falling
through the dirt to their death right
now and I was standing here watching
watching them die I was kind of
wondering if I would see a wolf fall and
I never did and so I decided hey you
know what I'm not going to look for any
wolves I'll do it later
tonight when I record my LP episode and
I'll go on an adventure and find a wolf
or something and so I went over to an
island to clear some more grass and then
I came back oh yeah
I also before I left though I set up I
set up like a little whirlpool thing so
that the animals wouldn't die when they
fell just like that and then I left the
clear some grass
and when I came back I was just walking
around this corner like this it was a
nighttime and I saw a wolf in my house
first one I saw was in my house and I
was like whoa how did that happen
is he going to attack me you know and he
didn't and then I went outside and there
were three more wolves out here there
was wool everywhere in leather
everywhere the Wolves had been killing
all the sheep that were collecting here
and the towels as I it was like a war
scene you know
so I tamed all the wolves and then I
discovered that that they won't attack
friendly animals after you tame him
unless he attacked on us first they
don't randomly do it on their own
anymore so that was interesting
and then I went back to my house and
there were like eight more wolves here
like right here exactly where the other
one was within like a minutes and I was
trying to figure out what happened you
know because for one thing I'm not far
enough away for them to spawn here and
it's like they were responding in my
house which I thought was weird look a
wolf just spawned in my house how did
that happen there's another one man
another
so I didn't see them come in through
this thing all I saw is that they were
in this area ash I've ever made one of
the mad yet Oh
gather all the one health when they come
in here them
oh they're fast holy No hey okay whoo
yes I had no idea was happening because
I thought for one thing they wouldn't
spawn this biome because I think this is
a swamp biome and yet they seem to and
the other thing is it seemed like they
were spawning in my house which didn't
make sense at all because I thought they
would have to spawn off grass and
oh yeah so then I went on YouTube and
someone sent me a video showing he had
my world and he made a video of wolves
going through the pig separator not
there's a wolf yes that's what's
happening so in his video he has my old
save though where this wasn't all set up
but he showed me that they fit through
the one high area for the pigs and just
by chance when I team up here I saw a
wolf in the big separator and saw what
was happening there smaller than a pig
so they don't get stuck at this spot
where the lava is so they don't die they
fall down into the item stream they run
along here and then they fall down the
collection pipe and since I don't have
the micro date set up there's nothing to
stop them from entering my storage room
so that's how they were getting into my
storage room
so yeah they spawn on grass and in light
Passaic the normal mobs I don't know if
they're any rarer than the normal moms
they probably are a little bit
whoa hey that's not good that's not good
oh my goodness
ah that was teamwork yes I have no
problem being wolves because apparently
I've made a wolf separator before they
even came out by pure chance
is that so that's pretty cool
I'm pretty sure I'm the first person to
make a wolf separator
because I did it before the patch even
though
um
I had to clarify another thing every
wolf that spawns
they take up the account as a passive
mom so if you have too many wolves cows
and sheep and chickens and pigs won't
spawn anymore so some people have been
wondering about that
more wolves you have that you're feeding
these guys you'll have and you can see
there's wool here
I'm sure wolf was over here just
recently
so I guess which go back up to the mob
system
so yeah it's easy to separate the walls
and it's easy to do it without killing
them so I probably will be using them to
automatically separates earth to assure
wool off sheep
let's see yeah if you wanted to make a
wolf separator you could do it oh yeah
so like I said before pigs can't fit
through a gap if there's a ladder here
because the latter makes it makes it so
they can't quite squeeze through there -
the pigs are too fat but the wolves are
smaller so they just fall down if you
wanted to make a wolf separator
you probably should get rid of the lab
on top although it doesn't seem to kill
them ever but it will damage them and so
you can separate the Wolves and then you
should be able to send the Wolves where
the sheep go but the problem is if you
get too many wolves and these other mobs
aren't going to spawn so I need to find
some way to control how many wolves I
have in my world I think I would only
need three or four and I can't use team
mobs because the team moms will
automatically attack the passive mobs on
their own so and I think the neutral
wolves will despawn there's a wolf gone
after sheep
laughter that one so anyway okay some
more fun facts about the Wolves if you
hold out bones or pork chops a kind of a
bag for the food they tilt their head
like that you'll notice his tails down
because he's damaged from the big
separator once you tame them if you can
tame them
they start at normal health full health
so that's interesting so even if they're
at low health when they're neutral as
soon as you tame them they get to full
health and I'm wondering if it's somehow
possible to get a evil wolf to to attack
the mobs okay didn't see that one coming
Oh does my last one mmm so also new in
the patch is cookies I don't have any
cocoa beans so we're not gonna be making
any of those there's another day well
that's that's my team
so the other interesting thing this
patch I think is the water stronger
water currents apparently there's more
angles that the water can go into let's
go over here you can't make wolf sit
when they're in the water otherwise they
would drown good boy so I want to try
something with water I want to see if it
makes you walk faster in it and if so
how much I think that's faster it's hard
to tell
maybe not I don't know this is if you
don't press any arrows yeah that must be
faster um so the other thing I'm
wondering about is how that's going to
affect each road I kind of don't think
it's going to affect it because there is
a max speed on boats so eat so it
shouldn't make any difference if it does
speed them up it's going to cause
problems because if the boats hit going
too fast there's an issue with them foot
going through the ground and then they
break so let's check it out
yeah I Pete that's the same
ya didn't notice any difference I think
that's the same uh I will be building
more stuff down here pretty soon there's
gonna be something here
actually there's going to be quite a few
things down here in the basement my
house isn't going to be complete until I
have some kind of secret underwater boat
passage kind of like I had in my first
starter house like some way to go from
the ocean do it the basement of my house
and go from the basement of my house to
the ocean so I've got to do that
someplace I think that's it yeah yes
that's all I wanted to talk about with
regards to the patch um yeah
achievements think it added not yet
anyway someone said that they were gonna
add like sandstone stairs and it's the
other one
yes stone stairs I don't know if that's
true or not I can I don't think that
I've added this patch and one thing I
want to talk about before we end this is
a guy kind of a delicate subject credit
as you guys know I come up with a lot of
ideas and designs and stuff in my videos
and there's been some confusion about
what you should and shouldn't do when
using these and so I'm going to try to
clarify that this episode because it's
been coming up a lot lately there's
actually been arguments about this and
other issues too so I'm going to explain
what I like and what I don't like and
what you should do and what you
shouldn't do or three yards to crediting
me so one extreme people some people are
over cautious I sometimes get PM's
people asking you know if it would be
alright if they added my boat design
into their world and if if not they're
they totally understand these people are
being overcautious anything you see in
my videos any of my ideas or designs you
are free to use in your world so that's
why I make my videos to give you guys
ideas and designs that you can use that
give you fun ideas fun things to make to
make Minecraft more enjoyable for you so
you don't need to send me PM's because
my inbox is flooded already and you
don't need to ask for permission to use
or build things that I've built you're
allowed to so my ideal thing I like to
see people do is to give me credit
mention my name or whatever and then
link to one of my specific videos or to
my youtube channel in their video's
description ideally I don't expect
people to do that though um because it
is a bit of work you know looking for a
specific video and then linking it in
the description and uh you know this is
something some people do and I really
appreciate it because it brings more
people to my channel um
the other thing is just mention my name
if you're using one of my ideas or
designs just mention hey this came from
Ethel I would appreciate it that's very
easy to do so these three in the middle
here are the acceptable ones these are
the three that you should do that I
don't mind if you do third one is don't
credit me that's acceptable if you don't
mention my name or link to my channel or
anything that's fine but if you don't do
that please don't
credit yourself for the idea or the
design okay I do that too sometimes you
know like with the mob Vader I didn't
know who made it I couldn't remember so
I just never I never mentioned their
name when I built it and you know I
didn't claim hey this is my design this
is why I invented either so it happens
but generally I tried to do this one
with people's videos or at the very
least I'll give someone a mention if I'm
using someone else's design but these
are the three acceptable ones a word of
caution though if you do this one it's
very easy for you to fall to the
unacceptable where you don't credit my
ideas or designs if you don't give me
credit it kind of bothers me if you
imply that the idea or design is yours
and most of the time this is
unintentional that people do this it can
be as simple as you know putting the
word I or mine or me or my in one of
your sentences and then you give the
impression that the idea or design team
from you so be careful if you do this
one that you don't too
accidentally do this one okay and then
finally this is probably the worst thing
you can do it's never happened to me yet
and it probably won't because
minecrafters in general are really nice
people but don't blatantly steal my
ideas or designs and claim them as your
own that's common sense that's not a
nice thing to do
yeah and also you guys are free to
change my designs all right yeah or
change my designs or improve on them if
you want go for it some people have done
this with eats and that's pretty cool to
see some of the things people come up
with usually when people do this though
they do mention that the original team
from me it's good to do either this or
this if you're going to change something
on my designs I'll let people know where
it came from and then just explain the
changes you made and I'm good with that
in general though guys you can probably
tell it already I'm a pretty calm guy
and I don't usually get upset about
these things I did I feel bad about this
now I someone kind of did this one where
they took one of my ideas and kind of
implied that it was theirs I'm pretty
sure they did it by accident but I made
a bit of a fuss about it and then he
took the video down and now I feel bad
about that because I didn't really want
him to do that I just wanted you know
he's mentioned my name somewhere and I'm
more than happy with it
okay any questions this send me a PM and
I will hopefully respond to it I'm still
flooded and that's it for this episode
thanks for watching guys and I'll see
you next time