hello everyone this is etho down here
doing some spelunking in a new cave
system if you look at the coordinates
I'm pretty far away from spawn point I
am clearing out the caves underneath my
future base getting it ready prepared
for my hostile spawning system so I need
to light up all the tunnels and while
doing that I get to enjoy exploring
collecting resources fighting mobs so
lots of fun look I just like just got
started I got all this stuff already
diamonds redstone lots of coal iron gold
lapis Lupus lazuli whatever lots of that
but I found something pretty cool want
to show you guys it are you ready yeah
add that to the wiki we're at lab a
level first time I've seen a dungeon
with no no floor like that lethal and no
I didn't mind it out it was actually
like that a little bit nervous poking a
zombie spawning and knocking me into
this
well I'll just ah cocoa beans nice I
think it's the first one I've ever done
redstone and I'll leave the rest this
stuff so just why did you see that
here we are it's my future base location
and working tirelessly preparing the
land getting it ready for building the
base there's lots to do I got a little a
little camp set up here I got stuff
cooking furnaces this is a what I've
gotten from a spelunking so far lots
lots and lots of iron redstone lapis
quite a few diamonds again even gold so
it's going good soil glass got lots of
sand and I've brought some TNT and stuff
from my other base because what I got to
do is I got to clear at least clear the
grass off these islands around me but if
I can I should try to get rid of them
completely
I've already mostly got rid of a fairly
big island over there it's just a little
bit left before I did that though I
planted some soil down so that I could
get the grass to travel closer to my
centre here when I make grass travel I
like to make it at least two wide so
that it'll go faster and I got a little
well set up here water that won't freeze
and yeah so after that's cleared I'll
probably clear that one out using tea
and tea it's pretty big and I got clear
that one this one's huge I'm a little
worried about I might not get rid of
them I just try to remove the grass
your mum a lots of thieves are lit up
now though I think this episode I'm
going to start to building those EMP
units though so let's get to that so now
I've marked out this rectangle here with
these little pillars around this center
point here this is going to be my mob
area it's going to be a bit off the ice
I think six blocks up total and it's
sixteen wide and 22 long so fairly big
but not too too big
I believe the entrance of my base will
be from this direction and then you will
go up a little bit to the mob area here
I got to fill in this rectangle and put
a layer of soil all the way all the way
to fill it up and then I will be back
that is a strangest looking table I have
ever seen but now Adso it's just a soil
molding for my mob area floor here it's
a little strange to start building like
this already since this is important
part of the base so I should build it
first and I also know I want it off the
ground so that's why I'm doing this
because I need to run wiring underground
and land out like water canals and stuff
hidden underground so I need it at least
three blocks up but I think I'm making
it six blocks up here just so I have a
little bit of a buffer in case I need
more
so let's see which direction are we if
the entrance to my base is on the side I
figured this out on paper kind of and
have 4 e MP units on this side three on
that side and four on the side and all
the items can merge kind of in the
center area I'll probably have a few
other things in the center will be
walking paths and I think I'm just going
to fill this with ice for now which is
not as difficult as you might think
I just can place the water I think up to
two blocks away ice is already starting
to form just like that
automatically fills itself in I've used
a lot of soil blocks building this so
it's a good thing I have to level up
these islands around here otherwise I
might run out because I pretty much use
them all at my other base building that
slime farm so don't have a whole lot of
soil left okay well I'm going to let
this freeze over it's not going to be
ice in the end but I'm just using it as
a start just because it's a easy to make
ice floor I started laying down the
placement of the EMP units this is kind
of what it's going to be like there's 11
of these in total I'm not I haven't
decided
officially on any of the block types I'm
using that right now I'm just using
sandstone it's a little bit hard to
choose what type to use because I have
nothing else built in the base so I have
nothing to match the style with but
that's for now I'm using sandstone this
won't be solid ice either in the end ah
I was thinking about maybe using snow
but if you guys have ideas of things
that look good with ice and stuff let me
know there will be a little bit of ice
here yeah but the way this is going to
work this one's going to be for chickens
this one's for pigs this one's for sheep
this one's for cows and I know it
doesn't really make sense to have one
for sheep and cows because I don't know
how to separate the two so why would I
have one for each well probably I'll
have the sheep and cows together in this
one but I'm making one for both for
two reasons one in case I ever figure
out how to separate the two or someone
else does
like if notch ever adds scarecrows right
over to the game we might have new ways
of separating mobs you never know the
other thing if new mobs get added to the
game I'll have another free chamber
available so I might be able to you know
use it because otherwise I have no way
of expanding this let's see what else
I believe this one will be for wolves
this fat one here is going to be for
spiders it's going to have to be a bit
different than the other ones this one
will be for squid this one for slime and
again I'm going to have Sambi or I might
do creeper first zombie skeleton and
again the only one I can automatically
separate is creepers and even that's a
little bit tough to do so in all
likelihood I'll probably have creepers
then zombie skeletons and creepers and
all together in this one and this one
will probably be free and if a new mob
gets added to the game or I find some
way to properly separate them
automatically then I will use this spot
yeah that's that's the plan so I'm going
to build these up again I'm not decided
on the look here just trying to get to
the shape going so that's kind of what
they look like
I think I think since there's a lot of
ice around I might start using color
wool more because it kind of I think it
would go well with ice as well you could
have lots of different colors probably
without looking too strange because ice
is a lighter block uh-huh anyway I'm
going to keep working on this well I'm
out of sandstone again guys so I'm gonna
have to get some more sometime but let's
let's keep working on this for now each
of these is going to need I believe five
sticky pistons I know one goes pointing
down here another one goes here glass on
top glass on that one
and then I think it goes or was it I
think over here just three of them
stacked on top of each other like that
the nice thing about posting my videos
online I can always look at them as a
reference later so instead of having to
walk all the way back to my base to see
what - how to build these EMP things I
was able to just look at my last let's
play episode which is nice yeah so chest
go here kind of like this I may put like
a pillar here
maybe this for looks yeah levers one two
three four and that's kind of how you
build these things so I'm going to keep
at it
mmm
well it seems like I made a huge mistake
I'm going to have to redo all these
walls the problem is kind of how these
corners are meeting they're a little bit
too cramped I think I don't think it's
going to be a problem with the wiring
but just the look looks kind of cramped
and also the way the water streams are
going to flow I'll have to have the hole
right here for this one to go here and
this one to go here and that's not going
to work very good because I'll be
walking over this all the time so I kind
of want instead this being one - I want
it one two three wide in the corners so
to do that I need to move this wall back
one block also these ones I have kind of
five wide and with these spider walls I
have them at four wide a little bit
worried I'll have trouble with that
later - so I think I'm just going to
make them five wide just to be safe even
though I probably don't while I might
need to I don't know
I move the walls back this one had to go
back two blocks this one had to go back
two blocks and this one have to go back
one block so that's unfortunate I had to
do that but it's a good thing I caught
it as soon as I did because that would
have been a problem later on I'm sure
now kind of standstill here I'm out of
sandstone so I can't work on this facing
anymore
but but it's coming along behind these
things I'll need about six blocks or
sold for wiring but of course you won't
see it it'll be hidden behind them
thankfully grass is finished spreading
so it's sitting there until I figure out
where I'm putting my passive mob
spawning pads I'm guessing the hostel
and the passive spawning pads you're
going to be above here I like at least
24 blocks above where I'm standing so
I'm going to try make it look balanced
though and make it a little bit nicer
than I did with my other storage room
right from the start
it's starting to look messy under here
that's fine if you guys are wondering
how ice blocks move with sticky pistons
it's a little strange going down the
what do you call it again the pusher or
whatever disappears when it's extended
and
goes back to normal when it's put back
together but the ice block creates a
water block where it was so it's a
little bit glitchy at the moment I'm
hoping that it's fixed going up once
again it disappears but doesn't create
water thankfully so no problem going up
and down this is going this way that
there's a problem and same with the left
right or like east-west north-south
there's a problem I'm thinking I'm going
to just work on leveling this island and
hopefully I'll get some sandstone from
doing that because there's sand around
here so a little bit deeper I'm thinking
they're sandstone so it looks like from
a distance and see we have mob spawning
on here so we need to brown sheet and to
keep that from happening I'm going to be
using TNT so apparently if you hit it
with flint and steel
it works like it used to hopefully I
don't make too big of a mess I'll
sandstone here I'm going to try to do
the bulk of this with tea and tea
oh whoa there's some sandstone it's kind
of I don't really want to get though
it's a little too deeper so I'll
probably have to go back to my main base
in my normal location I go for young
sandstone but I'm gonna level this
island anyway I don't know that looks
kind of cool to me doesn't it it's like
half the hills is blown away any of the
areas that I go too deep I need to fill
in the soil so I got to be careful with
the TNT but like that areas like over
there I can use TNT no problem and they
also have a stone base so I don't need
to worry about going below well I might
I'm at Y 64 that's what I want this
whole thing to be once I get this all
cleared I need to fill this in with
water it'll freeze over and you will
never even know there was an island here
and no mobs will be able to spawn here
well guys I think that's where I'm going
to end today's episode I'm really
enjoying building the new base there it
might be pretty confusing right now but
don't worry it'll become a lot clearer
as I work on it more what I'm actually
intending on doing
it's a strange project that's for sure
but will be fun thank you for watching
though and I will see you again big go
go eh I'll see you again next time