beautiful sunset just beautiful hello
everyone welcome back we're going to
continue our adventure Jen today in our
new world and what we're doing right now
is just getting set ups getting started
collecting resources this is what we got
so far we're doing good will soon start
building a base somewhere we need to
explore and find a good location as well
hopefully I didn't wait too long toe to
bed as good it's good today I want to
check out that deep cave we found
because I'm mostly interested in finding
iron and redstone at the moment I get
that then we can dart start doing some
cool stuff I don't remember exactly
where that deep hole was I think it was
over this way
it's sad this is like one of the only
times I would actually use a map in the
game and take advantage of that feature
and I can't because you need redstone to
make a map so not too happy with the
whole map feature I've only ever used it
once in canopy carnage and other than
that I've never found a use for map
okay well I'm definitely lost here I'll
sail around for bits and hopefully I'll
see you there I'm looking for that
desert okay we got something here you
got to check it out so I use that 6-iron
I got last episode to make some iron
tools okay gotta be brief Eman creepers
I don't know where I'm going here ah day
we found at Eve
those creepers get past the water
they're just going to start flying at me
really quick they start going with the
current Gemma actually looks like
there's a hole in the ocean over there
yeah there is okay maybe I'll seal this
up and let's still see where this goes
all right we got iron cool I can't go
too far because I don't have any armor
and have to be careful more iron sweep
out more there coal on a dead it dead
ends
okay so I'll collect the stuff and then
we'll be back to the surface oh it's
just so frustrating I keep getting lost
and sailing around for 10 or 20 minutes
now trying to find this place again
finally found it and only because it's
nighttime whoo okay well this is what we
got
nice 64 plus 8 cool Levin iron and some
more random stuff okay so we will go try
find that deep hole again see I knew it
was close that's where our chests and
stuff is and this is where the hole is I
marked it with torches otherwise I would
have not found it and the desert is over
over there
EPIK mountains in front of us cool cool
okay I'm not sure how we're going to get
down here and there goes the boat
clear the area age of spiders okay okay
the water is flowing down just ride the
water it's not too mad okay there's a
later there we want to go as deep as we
can
another layer here pretty epic looking
cave system I'm really excited to go to
exploring because I'm pretty sure the
generation has changed for caves again
so this should be fun
in creative mode I use that TNT x-ray
trick to check out the cave systems of a
few worlds and there does massive now
there's so many caves underground I
better fill this in just a habit of mine
okay cool cool let's go down deeper
good careful
can't tell where the water ends right
down to the bedrock redstone over there
all right over here too unfortunately
there's some serious water currents
pushing me around cool mushrooms
underground wander through bad news over
there yeah he's just gonna burn nice
let's check out over here creeper hey
buddy what's the matter you don't like
water don't know how to swim
oh we got lapis right up there thought I
heard something walking to me going up
going up dead-end cool okay I'm gonna
collect some of this stuff check it out
fifty three redstone crap well what that
all of this is gonna suck that's the
first time that ever happened to me ah
yup so I don't know what's gonna happen
but I'm about 90% sure I'm going to die
now because my escape was ruined by the
game crashing so creeper gets a cheap
shot on me I did it oh I don't know how
I did it
I just helped forward just about walked
into the lava but the creeper totally
didn't see me trick them up awesome and
even reveals lapis for us so I don't
know how much sweeter that could have
gone wow I hope that's not going to
become a regular thing memory crashes I
know that's a huge problem for people
that use texture packs
I'm just seeing the guy team from over
here so why not go over here right isn't
that logical thinking go towards the
danger whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa okay now
why are you chasing me yeah yeah brains
over brawn
there's some serious mobs around here
why so serious
best thought out of torches I do have a
lot of coal oh sorry I think I just blew
into my mic all right well there's I'm
gonna watch out for that
full speed ahead hey nice shot
ah those guys are so cheap doubts they
shoot so fast almost they make that jump
there's more and I'm not healing I know
you're over there
come out come out wherever you are
nobody said fighting had to be fair
where where is he ah you like my job
home skeletons by far are the most
freaky because they got that super loud
sound that place when they shoot the
first time gets me every time these guys
are really quiet okay fine be that way
I need blocks just like all these caves
above me that are freaking me out
I leave this all the way along here
perfect for creepers to just fall down
pretty sure this dead ends well maybe
not shoot me as soon as he can see me
there you go he's over here right yep
through the blocks one mark one more Oh
looks like it goes down to bedrock again
I say bedrock it's actually the lab a
level whatever and I'll do the resource
collecting off camera because that's
ception aliy boring oh did not need to
do that lighten it up
que sería looks pretty safe
Oh Oh where are we this is somewhere
else we can't get through here I believe
they're zombies above you where is he oh
he's up here okay he's not coming down
light it up light it up get you better
than that man
okay well I'm gonna get lost in here I
know these caves are much more complex
than they used to be they just keep
branching off into more and more
directions so I think what I'll do I'll
just collect whatever resources that
pass so far and then we'll head back
because I I got a lot here and I'll
probably die if I keep going as this
harvesting some coal here and I punch
through the wall there's abandoned
mineshaft on the other side so that
might explain why I keep hearing mob
noises oh I can see I can see some
wooden planks up there too uh-huh
I'm not going to tackle it right now
because I'm fairly loaded I'm going to
take this stuff back first and finish
harvesting what we passed by and then
maybe we'll come back here sometime
oh man how's those well that was a very
good run look at all we got that's some
good startup resources now I got to get
out of here though and I'm really
worried I'm gonna die here just reminds
me of the 404 challenge we got all those
cave systems going up where there's
probably what mobs lurking ba+ we have
this lab around which is making me
nervous
and I can hear some mobs so I figured I
did it on film come on we can make it
why is he so close where are they
almost there his water is not pushing
these it's like pushing me all over the
place - it's not like riding up a water
column
come on mom why
cheapo oh my goodness
ah ha ha ha freak me out why don't you
ah just mate just about made poopbox a
reality there well I made it back safe
and sound guys quite intensive that was
really my first experience caving since
1.8 came out and I gotta say it's a lot
harder now I'm I wasn't expecting that
at least if you have no armor because if
you're playing on hard with no armor
basically 4 hits and you're dead that's
it so because your health recover so
slowly you either need to like encase
yourself I found and let it recover uh
you can't really I don't know it's
really hard to run away from guys I find
like skeletons follow you pretty good
maybe it was just maybe this time I
don't know yeah this is what we got 22
gold I think we got three stacks of coal
that time 71 lapis 76 redstone this is
what separates us from the primitive
savages that live on this island
aka creepers and we also got
what else did we get I think like a
stack iron I don't know if I said that
already so pretty good run we're getting
established really well here but I don't
feel overly safe having this stuff just
out in the open now so I should start
thinking about a shelter another
beautiful sunset so before we end this
episode I think I'm going to try find a
spot to build like our first main base
where the storage room will be that kind
of thing so I'm going to scout around
I'm probably going to do it in a swampy
area for the green grass of course and
they're nice and flat I am actually kind
of thinking of building in the water I
don't know we'll see I'll look around
and I'll let you know I may have found
it here this is looking pretty good to
me
we're in the middle of the swamp biome
just good we have the desert over there
pine forests there and there I believe
the mountains are that way and we're
just like in the middle of a giant ocean
which will work out really well because
as usual I plan on making a hostile mob
system I don't know if I'll do it on
camera or anything because you've seen a
million times but I definitely do want
one and this will work out good in this
area because I won't have to place
torches over all the land around here
because it's mostly water so that'll
save a lot of time and efforts which is
good we're also in fairly deep water
here it'll be make it easier to capture
squid and stuff if we do that and as for
the building I plan on making kind of a
cross between
a boat harbor treehouse and maybe
abandoned ruins or something kind of a
mix of the three if that makes any sense
I'm not sure exactly but that's that's
the fun of the LP we get to figure it
out what are we going to build I don't
know yet I'm excited yeah okay if you
guys got ideas let me know but for today
I will end it here thank you for
watching and I'll see you again next
time