[Music]
hey everyone you so here again and
there's been no changes on the mob
system in a few days now we'll get to
that again later we're gonna spend
another episode or two in the nether
though and finish up the 360 cannon I
think so uh let's head over there now
I've done a little bit on it since last
episode
and I've noticed something that the
longer I stay in the nether in one point
the fewer zombie pigmen there becomes
more gas at spawn guys close they went
explained to liya
sometimes we shoot them directly I shot
that guy I'm pretty sure dead soon can't
remember if I had the wit their last
episode is trying it out is having
trouble with the gas destroying the
floor so should be fine now and I've
made one large addition actually lets
you guys are complaining about the sound
I added a very simple track in the
nether very simple point A to point B
and back again but I actually have to
set up pretty cool so underneath this
cart is a pressure plate and this here
is a document e7s Meis switch I'll put a
link in the description to check out his
video but basically there's a my cart
with a switch underneath of stone
pressure plates and the way I have this
wired if I'm in this carts no cart comes
to take me away by hop to this cart no
cart comes it's only if I hop from this
one to this one well I get sent away so
it's pretty cool I think and same ones
over here if I'm on this pressure plate
nothing happens if I'm on this one
nothing happens
if I hop from here to here nothing
happens but only if I hop from here to
here because you come up the ladder go
here and then get sent off there's a new
patch coming out that's gonna make all
this your relevant pretty much but I'll
show you how it works anyway just in
case you're interested so yeah that's
that's the document II sevens nice
there's just these they're half slabs
all around and this stone pressure plate
underneath this carts so we have two
stone pressure plates one there one
there and then this is the well let's
let's look at it run from in here that's
uh blah laughs whatever his name is door
booster door opens car goes comes around
back
this one goes around so that's how that
works
then over here I have a little hole to
go down and there's a redstone torch
underneath the door directly and then I
have a kind of like a hybrid and eat
here there's two wires here yeah
first ones over here there's one
pressure plate directly above this one
the the Mies and that heads to a
repeater with the four delay goes down
another repeater with the four delay
and it goes to this redstone torch here
the other pressure plate is directly
above here and it goes to the torch and
then it goes to the door so all you need
is like an and eight and you need two
repeaters for the Mies pressure plate
and that what this is doing the reason
for the delay is just to give the
pressure plate because you go instantly
from one to the other so both are
pressed down at the same time and so
what you're doing is you're just giving
it enough time for what the pressure
plate you hop from to go back up and
that's what the delay is for just a
short delay I found four torches wasn't
enough of a delay so you need I think
five or six and I just have it set at
eight here to be sure yeah so that's
that but there's a new patch coming out
with boosters properly implemented so
not sure how useful any of this will be
don't maybe runaway minecart now it
gives a pretty good boost this is about
90 blocks long this track not quite sure
how far it'll push you and the booster
just goes for five blocks here and then
goes back and then resets
[Music]
but anyway that's not what we're gonna
be doing today we're gonna be working on
the cannon again I'll show you the
progress I've made since last episode I
ran out of glass but yeah some more now
I got sixteen stacks cooking as I speak
so should it be a problem anymore
so that's kind of what I got built right
now store some stuff and let's take a
look down here kind of a little glass
case all around I'm a little confused if
this is north I'm pretty sure it is you
guys said to look for the owl but it
points to directions so I don't know
which one I'm supposed to be looking at
but I found that the TNT jumps mostly
this way and I'm not sure what other
direction it jumps to if it's either to
the left or to the right slightly but
I'm gonna try build this cannon so it
doesn't matter what direction you build
it because I don't like designs that are
Direction dependent oh no way no way we
have company what's going on here that's
awesome
oh how can I kill these guys Hey you
[Music]
okay
you guard the cannon while I'm away
[Music]
that's awesome so I guess a few are
still spawning but it might be because I
was moving around but it's mostly just
gas okay so let's get to work I'm gonna
try finish up this cannon before we do
anything else in my LP plan is to finish
this up and have a few test launches and
then then I'm gonna build another 360
cannon in the normal world
and while I build that and I'm gonna
make a do toriel on how to build a 360
cannon and once that's all done I'll
release my world again and you guys can
play around with it so that's my plan it
was easy for you dude
yes so I'm gonna work on it some more
and I'll give you some updates hopefully
I gotta add it there's gonna be two
booster packs I think I don't think I
need three so I'm gonna work on that
right now okay
so this here is the first booster rack
this inside ring this outside ring is
for the shells you go in this gap here
so above the first string where you're
gonna make no shoving we're gonna start
making another ring I'm gonna leave
enough space so I can walk around on
this ring so it's gonna be a little bit
different than my original design the
second ring is gonna be one block higher
[Music]
so I think I could put it here
probably shan't bother with torches
because let's get blown up anyway what's
this from a little bit hard to imagine
right now oh wait how do I get out of
here now ah of course I picked the side
with the ladders on usually don't even
pay attention to those guys anymore I'm
so used to
[Music]
it's weird if you spend some time in the
nether it's like not freaky at all
anymore
[Music]
especially if you have iron arm on
Hannibal all manuals my glass Oh
[Music]
actually I need this ring one more he
hit my glass actually I think I'm gonna
I don't think it matters that the glass
gets destroyed I think I'm going to
stand out one more block although I
would prefer it doesn't
[Music]
so annoying okay and this is going to be
higher in here spending more than two I
will probably be at least four I don't
like it all claustrophobic like I think
I have to kill that guy because he's
going to be a problem gotta beat you
[Music]
all right I'm gonna stop it for a second
okay so I ripped the ceiling out a bit
tear
now you're gonna raised up one more
kinda for safety and I realized that I
really shouldn't be coming down the
center there because that's where the
tubu strings are ones here other ones
here so I made another tube here
probably just temporarily and I'm gonna
get rid of going down here so wire will
be placed around where I'm standing
right now and this this will be gone
[Music]
because it's in the way I need to Center
free there I'll give you another
progress report and a little bit just
going for a tea and tea run I watched
like the video and I realized I wasn't
using the Mesa switch correctly so just
want to show you when I exit the
minecarts I don't hop out here I go to
here and then hop up
just because I was explaining the
pressure plates and stuff I messed up
the proper order
[Music]
I like that this stuff can't get
destroyed at some point I will make my
base looked a lot prettier I'll probably
do astroturf and freeze and I might use
some blue wool and stuff because I think
that's what the nether is missing is
blue where you stall the water make you
a lot more homey once you get some color
I think like blue green you know start
looking start looking a lot better
[Music]
well that gas this gun that's weird I'm
not sure if they'd be spawn like normal
mobs it's kind of strange we only had
two stacks of tea and tea I think I have
like five total I don't worry put all my
I don't know where I put my stash I
think it might be at the firework
andit's
although I think I checked there and it
wasn't there I find it hard to believe I
used that much though okay I'm gonna
create a world backed up and I will be
back okay I got the world backed up now
I need to do a test here I'm wondering
if I need to make my booster rings - hi
in my original design I did it as a
guard so that the TNT from the second or
third ring when it fall down and land on
top of the first string I'm not sure if
I actually test it if it's required so
we're gonna find that out and now it'd
be better if I can make this only one
high so it'll place some wire and some
TNT so if it falls down to the center
there it's good if some of it lands on
this first ring on top of it
that's bad there's a good chance I'm
going to blow up here too
all right let's check it out
[Music]
I seem fine yeah I think that was okay
and all right so we're gonna do another
similar test I think this time I have a
block in the middle of each new string
and I want to see if any land on on the
center block there
[Music]
place TT I think there's a guess lion up
here so to do this fast
and no seemed fine
cool so I might have a center block too
[Music]
all right another major issue I'm having
at some point I'm gonna have to get rid
of this tube from the base to the I
don't know you would call it the deck or
the control area place where you stand
you'd never come down here once it's all
built but if you ever need to repair
anything or just for me to build this
down here I need some way to get back up
without preferably jumping in the lava
so I can't use ladders because they will
obstruct the the missiles so it won't be
a technical 360 cannon if I have some
sort of obstruction so I need some way
to get up without having an obstruction
and I can't use water because this is
another my original design I used water
so I'm thinking I'm gonna have to try to
do something with boats so I'm trying to
figure out how high I can get into a
boat
and that's too high still too high no
way yeah yes that's it that is one two
three four plus the one that's five and
[Music]
that's not very much the other thing is
I need the boat to be far away from the
explosions here because otherwise the
boat will break that's why I got this
like little offshoot here something to
think about
all right so I guess so that's about it
for today wrap it up here I did extend
this out one more and I'll when it's all
done I'm gonna replace this cobble stone
on the outside with glass of course and
probably a lot of this floor will be
glass a big majority of the canons gonna
be glass so that we can see all around
us the best we can and it won't be
overhanging like this either I'm gonna
try work on that boat issue getting a
reliable way up and down and yeah so
we'll dedicate another episode Kay's
cannon I think and hopefully by then it
should be done and we can move on to
something else but anyway thank you for
watching