hey everyone this is etho thanks for
joining me today
minecraft beta 1.5 t mount is pretty
cool lots of new and exciting changes
have been made that the community is all
excited about as you can see the
Baconator is not to drop cooking pork
chops that's one of the changes that
pigs when they're chilled by fire the
drop cook pork chops so I might be
changing necks lots of cool things came
out in the patch then it I'm going to be
talking about we're going to dedicate
the whole episode to the patch a new
video settings don't really know what
this does except lower my frames per
second and a half cuts it in half to
change the GUI
I think larger Otto's the best and we
have achievements I'm not one of the
most exciting features for me but I do
like it I'm not going to complain about
extra features to the game and it adds a
little bit of fun I like the way they
have them set up I think the way they're
set up they can keep adding more and
more achievements to it and make diagram
bigger so just have basic ones for now
and also we have statistics which I am
which I like a lot more I like to know
what I've been up to in the game I've
only played an hour since the patch came
out and part of that was while I was afk
so maybe half an hour
yeah lots of cool things and let's hit
down of course one thing now you need
solid bladders but when you craft
ladders now you'll get two instead of
one so kind of isn't a big deal one
thing I do not like though is you can no
longer jump and catch a ladder that's 3i
which is something I do a lot normally
because I think the part that climbs the
ladder now is your feet your lower half
so kind of unfortunate I've been talking
with the guy called Neutron like I said
his name right he was having trouble
with his mob system at one point for and
I am pretty sure everybody has been mine
still worked but I noticed the rate was
a lot lower and now it's back to normal
that's 1.5 so that's cool it's working
very fast again of course the highlight
of the patch is probably the new booster
stuff ah that's what I've been playing
around with mostly so one thing I really
like about these things is it's now
possible to have mine carts going around
in an infinite loop without stopping
before that was a real problem because
that's what I was trying to do with my
storage room here have an infinite loop
and even now when you log out you'll
notice the minecarts just on an open
track if you leave and come back that's
loading slow
why is that loading so slow it keeps
going so they added while they add it
but now in the world saves it saves a
the momentum of the my card in the file
so when it loads the file it still has
the same momentum and it doesn't stop
dead on the track which is very cool
so I'll be able to hook up my mana card
system really easily now oh this is
going to become very useful for my
secret project as well which I will
hopefully get to eventually I guess I
may as well show you how to graph the
new stuff even though you've probably
seen it a million times already now so I
liked how they make it use gold gold now
has a real real purpose or real use
that's how you make the the booster
rails the powered rails make six doing
that and you can make detector rails
with the pressure plate instead of a
stick there oh okay I don't know how to
make detector rails
all right give me a sec all right sorry
about that guys I don't consider myself
a mind for a Minecraft professional
really I guess it's use iron instead of
gold and you get six so that's that's
pretty good one iron each and same with
the Boosters there one gold each to make
okay and yeah sticks like I said you at
two now um that's pretty cool I think it
actually works out better I think
especially if you're doing something
like an e throat um oh yeah I should
probably show you guys what's up with
eats because some people said on my
channel comments that it's not working
when in fact it still is yeah if you the
cool thing about getting two ladders now
is ikan that may eats roads a lot easier
because you get twice as many and you
don't need to make them go up
if what I said made any sense that seems
to be fine
when I came in there though the boats
were everywhere like they all got out of
position somehow from the patch but when
I reloaded it too don't seem to work
fine so no worries I know I haven't uh
extended the road at all yet I only do
so many things you know oops I guess I
should try to make sure it still works
if I have three boats in that's
important when you're making an each
Road always a test with three boats and
yeah they still line up properly it's
only if you steer a boat and then ride
it into a return thing that they seem to
get messed up well that was that was
weird
and wonder why two books shadows seem to
be having leg spikes little bit
different than normal
anyway I'll look into that more later oh
that sucks I can't get out of here
hello No yeah J yeah I'm going to focus
on the minecarts but first I want to
look at a couple other things now a very
cool new feature say you want to quickly
put items in your chests if you hold
down shift and then click on them they
instantly get added without having to
drag and drop them and same with the
taking Mount hold shift and then go into
your inventory so that is really cool
for saving time it does not work with
dispenser so which really sucks for me
so I'll probably start using chests a
lot more and what else is new and that
we got new saplings which is also one of
my favorite things about the new patch
I'm a little scared to go outside though
for obvious reasons oh yeah I'm going to
take you up to my tree farm
show you something I found interesting
so these were all these type of saplings
before the patch but after the patch
they got randomly switched to the new
kinds as well how can you hit me when
I'm up kidding oh wait I thought I was
on fancy haha I almost think the
performance is better now with the new
patch although I am getting those
strange leg spikes although I've always
been getting like leg spikes but the new
leg spikes are different somehow but
they're shorter I don't know it's
strange
yes hello saplings were randomly
switched kind of like many patches ago
when the tree's leaves randomly switched
to the three different kinds of leaves
I'm going to skip ahead today all right
this is a little better right
all right yes much better
so the saplings there's now three kinds
and I don't have to set the normal kind
and grow them with bonemeal I can grow
them in any biome I'm pretty sure even
though they're normally biome specific
which is weird and so now you have three
types of renewable work you got three
types of renewable wood which is cool I
just found out like two weeks ago that
there's this dark wood here I didn't
know that I thought it was the same as
the regular wood but it's not because I
don't have any of these trees really in
my LP world yet feel pretty far to see
one and they dropped the new saplings so
that's very cool very liking that
feature and also there's weather now
which is great I still haven't seen it
though
so it rains and it snows and when it
snows it replaces the ice and the snow
on the ground and snowy biomes which is
great because I've always wanted to
build and snowy biome but I've it I
don't know what I'm I really don't like
wrecking the landscape and pretty much
anything you do is going to wreck the
landscape before because you had biome
specific trees that you couldn't regrow
and you have the snow so and if you like
spilt water or something it would
destroy tons and tons of snow blocks
that you could never get back so now you
can live in snowy biomes and still have
them look like snow biome so that's cool
I might build a base in a snowy biome I
here's someone creeping yes
now if you're not allowed in here
no sorry whoa there you okay is that it
is that everything can I talk about my
Kurtz now yes I think I can talk about
minecarts now I'm going to get set up
and then I'll look into them a bit okay
we're not going to do my cards just yet
I forgot to there's something else I
want to point out about saplings it's
now possible to mix and match leaves
with different kinds of wood so for
example if you like these messed-up
trees I think these are I think these
are alpha trees still it's possible to
do that to make trees like this sort of
mix leaves with different kinds of wood
however you like so for example I have
the dark wood from these type of trees
and I'm going to mix it with the leaves
from these type of trees it's actually
something I never see people do for some
reason I don't know I don't really know
why people don't to mess around with it
like making shapes and step out a tree
wood and leaves this is probably going
to kill me
doesn't need to be that deep well maybe
it does actually give me a sec I'm just
going to do this off camera mm-hmm was
there a point to this I think I was just
looking for an excuse to make a giant
creeper head out of wooden leaves for
some reason oh wait now yeah is showing
that that you can mix different leaves
with different types of wood so I have
this type of wood from these trees with
leaves from these type of trees and it's
possible to mix the three types of wood
with the three types of leaves I think
that was my point and also I want to
show you guys because this isn't very
this isn't done very often I don't think
that you can make shapes and stuff out
of leaves this way which is especially
useful if you're making gardens and
stuff and you want leaves shape
different in different ways make vines
or whatever as long as you have wood
within I think 4 blocks of a leaf the
leaf will not die something like that so
you can place your wood blocks and then
grow trees and then kill the trees and
their leaves will stay that on the logs
you placed first yeah okay
something else I'm noticing now is that
these new saplings don't like to grow in
closed-off space as it seems and not as
well as the other type the normal type
of trees like they really don't want to
grow
they might not be able to
oh it might be because my class blocks
are too low they might need more
vertical space I'll look into that more
later I guess alright now we can talk
about the new powered rails and the
detectors as you can see this card is
still going it has been for I think two
hours now on this loop keeps working
even if you log off so I see a lot of
potential in this the new tracks they
can't curve at the moment I don't know
if they ever will and you need to power
them with redstone in order for them to
propel the cart otherwise they act as
brakes if I push his cart over the brake
it'll stop pretty much pretty instantly
if you apply power to it when it's on
the powered rail nothing happens it
needs to be going at direction in order
for it to get boosted so what that means
is you still need some way to get the
carts going so we'll still probably need
to use door boosters or something like
that so the old way is not completely
lost and yeah it's a it's launched
but you'll notice it how far'd that go
one two three four five six seven eight
nine well ten tracks this one's going
nine ten eleven twelve thirteen so this
one's going farther without being
boosted and so what that means is these
boosters do not instantly bring the card
up to speed so you'll need several of
them the mine card or the Minecraft Wiki
says like if you're in a cart up it
loses momentum a lot slower so if you're
in a cart to maintain maximum speed you
need to space the powered boosters 16
blocks apart for maximum speed and they
go up to 128 blocks in between each
other so to keep the car going at eight
blocks per second or whatever you need
them 16 blocks of parts well
one every 16 blocks that's that's fairly
reasonable I'd say but if you're out of
the cart they lose momentum a lot faster
a lot lot faster I think you need to
space some probably three or four blocks
of parts to keep the cart going at a
decent speed oh yeah another thing about
these which i think is pretty cool if
you apply power to the booster it
transfers to all adjacent ones
so this one torch is powering all these
boosters so that's cool I'm guessing it
goes for 16 blocks but I'm not sure the
best way of powering them probably is to
put the torch underneath the boosters
so let's hidden instead of on the side
and the detector rails they send out
power I think if you're in the cards and
go over them they don't detect empty
cards
so you still might need to use wooden
pressure plates for that if you need to
detect empty cards all they do detect
empty cards so very interesting mm-hmm
okay I'm going to get my thoughts
together a little bit here and then
they'll start talking some more the old
booster methods still work which is
great so old stations should still keep
working and old applications like Pez
dispensers and that still they'll still
probably be used but they might be done
a little differently now the test I'm
doing is just placing a minecart here
this is my third time doing this now and
all three times it ends up exactly here
that's how far it goes with that boost
so what I want to see is if it's going
to go farther
actually that's no I hate doing that
okay I'm going to just have one I'm
going to place one of these boosters
here now I see if it goes farther use
mixing the old booster system with the
new the new tracks mmm looks about the
same to me so I think these things only
add momentum if if the carts lower going
slower than the maximum momentum that
they can apply and the old the old
boosters that make cards add momentum
higher than the maximum for these so I
think that's why I didn't go any further
kind of interesting I called ham 464 it
just started during first time singing
it
little worried something Bad's gonna
happen
see like a line in the sky right down
here
one
down here too
it's pretty cool though I liked it
I was just in the middle of setting
something up and I just pray
yeah I think people still be using door
boosters and stuff like that
originally you know I thought the way
they were going to implement these new
power rails was a
I really like the ring
I thought a cart would like go over to
the break and stop and then you could
hook up
a button to the power rail and when you
press the button it would send power to
it and then it would shoot the card off
that's how I thought it was gonna work
that would have been a lot simpler I
think but then it would have been only
one direction
but with door boosters
um
they have this slope here which is what
will
allow the carts to move forward
let's try this out I got one booster
here a booster here
I don't know what's gonna happen let's
see
to make it
his barely got on the door
from that one
yeah it's not enough you'll need more
momentum
now let's try take this longer
I wonder how long the ring laughs
let's try this now hopefully I'll make
up the hill and Auntie Laura
yep I don't know
and I require bit of effort Fitness
working in a way we can actually use it
is at the moment with these new boosters
I don't see any way you can press button
and have
carts start moving
without using the old boosters at the
moment
I'm going to have to keep looking into
that if you can't do it I'm sure you can
something now but if you can't read that
pretty much useless away anything
does the only other ways to put a cart
down and then push it yourself
anyway that's the end of our episode
today thank you for watching I'm going
to keep investigating this stuff and
I'll try to figure out how to even
commend it better future Zilla patch
it's a very cool patch I'm very excited
about it and yeah thanks for watching
until next time