hey everyone we're at episode 10 already
time is just flying and I've been
working on the mob trap relentlessly or
over the last three days now and let's
go check it out
I've pretty much only been doing grunt
work nothing nothing interesting really
so yeah like I said before there's this
higher level mistake I made and I wasn't
very clear but this is actually a
randomly generated lava pool and I
thought it was the lava level and that's
why I start digging up there but in fact
the real lava level is quite a bit lower
yeah I've been mining Street for three
days
probably good six hours at least mining
this out and I can't take it anymore so
we're gonna try to hook up our trap now
and the lava level is do you remove one
of these blocks
that's the lava level so this is what I
got figured out this is where the mob
elevator is gonna be it's gonna be a
three by three area all these things are
canals that will carry the mobs to this
elevator and then it the mob elevator
will take them up to the surface and
I've been looking for guides on how to
build this and I can't really find
anything concrete since the since that
Halloween update nobody really knows
what to do it seems
so I decided to make them three-wide the
canals because I thought spiders might
not fit if it's only a two to wide canal
and so I made them three wide and I
didn't know how big to make these little
areas for them to spawn on because if
it's too big they're not gonna wander
off into the water and if it's too small
it's gonna really lower the efficiency
so I took a random guess this is a 13 by
13 with a pattern repeating every 16 by
16 because the waters 3 and so yeah
let's get started oh boy how do I get
out here
oh yeah so the first thing we're gonna
do oh yeah I want to show you all the
resources full full half polish full
more junk those are all the goodies I've
gone through for Diamond pickaxes and
got all this stuff so we're pretty much
set we can start building cool things
now so oh yeah another thing oh another
thing I wanted to mention when I was
digging this out I was like watching TV
on my computer and I wasn't really
paying attention to what I was doing and
so this ended up being a lot longer than
I wanted it to be I wanted it to be wide
and short and it ended up being long and
narrow
so it might not work perfectly but
hopefully hopefully it's still okay if
you're gonna if you're gonna do this you
should make it wider and shorter but oh
well I was watching the movie more than
the game because mining is very boring
if you do it for hours and hours and I
really wish I had some TNT and that's
kind of why we're building this - okay
so of course it's night time it's always
night time when I go outside I brought
lots of wood with me
and what we're gonna do we're gonna
start setting this elevator up and I'm
just gonna put a little fence around it
so the weight comes and falls on on me
while we're building this and hopefully
it's not so dark that you guys can't see
anything
jiae's so what we have to do J I hope I
brought all the things we need cuz that
there's no way of getting out of here
once we start we're gonna be putting
signs around here so I brought this and
I'm gonna put that there
and we're going to make a water pool and
craft our signs we are going to be using
a lot and a lot of signs and of course I
have no sticks I hate when I do that so
I'm probably not gonna show you all this
I just want to show you how it's going
to be done first because this will get
boring too
and some people were wondering what I
use to record I use fraps and I edit
with virtualdub
I barely edit my videos I just cut out
boring stuff which is a lot usually
okay so what we're gonna do to get a 3x3
area we are going to put sign here sign
here sign here signs there we need to
make a 3x3 area of signs and on top of
that we're going to place water and to
do that yeah probably not gonna have
enough wood
or signs
okay so to do that we're gonna use it
another trick here you can place a sign
on top of another sign to make a
floating sign which is very cool
and that will allow us to place water on
top and I'm hoping no we got a place
water in all all nine blocks that sucks
Wow
yeah I should do it I don't want to sort
of place one in the middle we have to
place a block there do the sides oh this
is going to suck okay let's check it out
make sure it's right perfect so we're
gonna have to do that about thirty times
and we're gonna have to keep moving this
pool down lower and so the next water
would be here signs here water signs
water like 30 times to get to the bottom
which is a long ways down so I'm not
gonna let you guys watch that cuz that
is gonna be so boring so I'll see you in
a bit well it's coming along slowly but
it's not as bad as I thought it was
gonna be still got a ways to go and I
ran out of wood
so I'm gonna do this off-camera some
other time I'll show you what it looks
like so the reason why I don't want
flowing water is because I don't want
the mobs gathering in one place and
getting stuck which is also why I make
why I made this a three by three instead
of a two by two which is in normal just
so that they have more space to get up
here without getting in each other's way
but also the water is not flowing down
so they'll be able to swim up here
faster
and these spaces in between allow them
to breathe while they're while they're
swimming up here so they won't drown
because we don't want them dead we want
them get up here and then and then we'll
deal with them so yeah taking awhile but
it's an important part of this so I'll
take my time on it and I did fall down
there by accident and discovered there's
the ladders so one more thing we need to
figure out is how we're gonna do the
water
genell's here um all the water has to
flow this way to this point the elevator
will be here actually we need we need
pressure plates or I'm gonna use
pressure plates just because I like
using pressure plates you can use signs
can't use ladders cuz ma Polly gets
stuck on them
and that's for the elevator don't use
ladders either because they'll get stuck
on them so I'm gonna put three pressure
plates and count seven one two three
four five six seven place three more
place our water and if you guys didn't
know this already if you have a stream
of water that's three wide
you can grab water from the middle
without making it disappear one two
three four five
I think you guys have any ideas on how
to do this better let me know but for
now we're just gonna try something like
this I'm I tweaked it a bit let's see
here one two three four five six seven I
want to use the same pattern for every
one one two three four five six seven so
that's good we that are repeating
pattern now
I'll just copy that all the way down
work out the sides here yet same deal
three pressure plates there one two
three four five six seven three more
here one two three four five
oh boy what's that noise I hear someone
jumping in water around here
[Music]
so yeah that's that's this what we're
gonna do something like that and then
this will get dug down two more blocks
that will come down here
[Music]
and it should come together pretty good
if you ever watch mobs they don't move a
whole lot from where they spawn so I
think this is a good size to use I hope
[Music]
and yeah
so one more change that's been made is
the tree farm is now bigger it's a four
by four step a three by three so that's
good
just in time I'm gonna need a lot of
signs and at some point we're going to
add a fence around it too so I'm going
to keep working on that mob system and
[Music]
when we're all done I'm gonna take
torches out and we're gonna test it out
together and hopefully everything works
well but I'm gonna end things here now
so thanks for watching