look at that sunrise that's beautiful
only I had a camera oh yeah yeah that's
how we do it one day I should check out
that folder because I'm sure there's
five hundred pictures in there that I
accidentally took because I have fat
fingers and I always bump theft ooh
button not because I'm fat I just have
fat fingers okay so this is etho we're
on chocolate island some people were
confused about that last episode this is
chocolate island my starter my starter
place here still sick yes what are we
doing here get to that in a second
oh yeah the quick it's pretty much done
here
this is what it looks like now so the
recovery quick kits this is a door lock
just if we want it to look neat have it
closed most of time open it water will
probably be on all the time only turn it
off when you want to restart it but
these are all empty right now I haven't
gotten around to filling this yet but
that's a project for another day that's
what it looks like I tried putting
leaves above here like I said I like
using wood planks sandstone logs and
leaves now they're like my favorite
combination
yeah okay so what are we doing today
we're going down to the mob system on
peaceful right now so all is good go
down the mob evader here
I've been remodeling doing some Manor
major renovations took out all the water
it's all lit up down here and what I'm
doing is I'm converting these spawning
pads so that we have that spider option
that we talked about last episode so
these half slabs here can you come out
if we power the pad and also on the
outside I have this setup to let these
retract and extend with Pistons to
certain to turn spider spawning on or
off see where's my main wall the
opposite side another thing I want to do
is a maze will do it right now
set this up so that it can handle squid
because squid spawn a lot now so we
should have a way of dealing with them
down here
okay so my old-style mob evader we use
pressure plates on the ground what we're
gonna do now is we're just gonna change
these two sides the blocks were the
pressure plates are so one here one here
and then do the sign on the sign trick
one there and do it on the other side I
should maybe put up a torch it's
probably dark now get here we go do it
again
and place the signs sign on the sign
make it match this one get pushed around
here
okay and what that does is it allows us
to have a hole here that the squid can
fall down and that way they won't clog
up the system that's the whole point of
this and the other mobs will swim over
top the water and swim up so split sink
the pall mobs they they swim that's how
that's gonna work I made these pads out
of cobblestone just because it's
abundant my ice base I'll probably make
them out of sandstone because that's
what I like and I'll show you how I'm
been wiring these so what I'm doing is I
just shave off this top layer we'll get
our torches up at the time here shave
off the top layer really blowing through
my diamond
blue shiny rock pay taxes here takes a
bit of time doing all this but you know
it's important we do this I'm kind of
doing this so that I have a working
prototype of this mob system so when I
build a new one I'm sure it works you
know because there was a little bit of
doubt raised to me
last episode by certain people I want to
make sure this is all working and also I
want to test out that that they can
spawn on pressure plates I'm pretty sure
I tested that in the past and it worked
I know they also can spawn on signs and
if you have a sign at their head level
they will spawn but they won't move
they'll be stuck in the sign I know
that's the test I did before - okay so
now these ones with signs on dig them
play some cobble so that it looks good
well cobble doesn't look good but just
that it looks uniform like that and then
I fill this in a little outline of our
spawning pad this 6x6 oops okay so
that's our basic shape then I put down
the sticky pistons there's four in each
of these put in the corners okay and
then we take this all down
and it's probably getting dark again
okay we dig that down I place four
blocks around on the right side get
roads these blocks showing here all four
sides
oops sorry about the camera control the
place it was cobble for that uniform
look and then we dig this down one and
replace it with cobble just to look make
it look good okay so that's the inside
of our spawning pad we place down wire
then in the center here just like this I
got it working so I don't need to use
repeaters so it'll save more redstone
and they'll be less delay and hopefully
less lag so there's 12 redstone dust and
a pad cover the four Center blocks to
cut the wires right so that the wire
points at the piston and then I'm not
sure if mobs can spawn on redstone but
at the moment none of my pads have
torches in if they can spawn on redstone
there's one block here where I'm worried
they'll be able to spawn inside the pad
so if they can and I'm gonna have to
replace or I'm gonna have to open up you
to these pads and place torches and so
that that doesn't happen but what I do
is I just cover this in a shanty my half
slabs place them on the Pistons
fill this in corners and the center and
that's how I've been changing the Pats
so they take a few minutes to do each
one but it's it's all for our future
plans let's test it out I will be
connecting from the bottom underneath I
think but you can also connect to the
sides here where the water normally
would be and they pop up like that and
go down so that's what we want so these
are all wired now all 16 pads and the
sides are all wired I'll show you how
they work so this is like where my
master controls going to be I think
let's just connect here somewhere
oh I think I'm on the wrong side yeah I
marked the main side with two torches on
the wall there yeah so this is where the
control will starts I break that torch
they all go down and I just need to
build up my pads here and I'll probably
put some lighting under here probably
leave it like that so this is what the
pads will look like on top when they're
done
and so I'm gonna keep working on this I
am maybe we'll do some other stuff I've
been working on those spawning pads and
stuff wiring everything but I've ran out
of redstone now there's no more redstone
around here so we need to go back to the
lab back to ethos lab to collect some
more I could take the suicide booth but
then I would have to drop off all my
items and I've never shown you guys
actually how to get there from here so
we're gonna go on a little journey here
it's not too far
bases at X 1024 and Zed 512 and we can
get pretty much all the way there just
by boat let's go around here and also
there's something pretty cool on the way
I wanted to show you guys some nice
scenery so just go around this Bend
there's some little squid
ouch oh no oh no whoo yep that could be
a sealer okay so there's this look canal
system through here this is man I dug
this myself
man-made and it goes to this lost
clothes goes to this opening here now
this is really cool I like this area a
lot it's like deep oceans and high
cliffs small islands it's pretty cool I
may eventually build some stuff around
here just because I like the way this
looks eventually I think I'm just gonna
build a minecart system through here
anyway
just to simplify things because using
the suicide booth is quick but it you
know it's you can't carry stuff to the
lab using it so we should have minecarts
I may also extend the eats run out that
far too although I might not make the
eats roads super fancy because that's a
long ways to go and we just keep sailing
straight wide open ocean here chunks are
updating kind of slow yeah that's where
the ice started so I just followed that
ice when I saw it until I found a nice
open area which is where we ended up
building the base
and over here it's kind of a arid land
nothing special I don't like arid places
like that this is usually where I get
off you can see somebody old boats here
still that takes us to 8:35 and 307 so
pretty close just go a little bit
further this way on land bunch of ice
around here keep following the land here
used to look a lot different though
that's the big landmass I blew up it's
all frozen over now and there's the lab
just like we left it and yes I could
have used Pistons to move grass up I
wasn't thinking about that last when I
did it so that is a better way of moving
grass as many of you suggested well what
happened here man like three colors of
wool on the ground meat crazy okay and
this is where my redstone is somewhere
I hope I have some they always iron
I'm gonna take that with me to bring
some of this oh that's it it's all my
redstone so I'm running out again okay
let's head back those are empty ages so
we hit back through the portal we are on
hard by the way I always make sure
even if it's just a quick pass through
there and we're back so that's how you
get to the Lapp case you were wondering
there were a lot of confused people
about how to find that area now you know
so I'm gonna run out
redstone I'm sure I might put a halt on
this whole mob system renovation I'll
meet you down there
all right guys long story short here I
got distracted and I started watching a
movie The Prestige excellent excellent
movie and while I was watching it I was
working on the mob system got late next
day same thing I rewatched the prestige
while working on the mob system because
it was such a good movie and now many
many hours later the mob system is close
to done so I've gotten a lot done but
it's taken it's taking me forever to do
what I've done here many many hours
probably at least eight so yeah we have
well one thing I did kind of dark I'll
just run through all the changes I've
made I got rid of all the soil and stone
and gravel and replaced everything with
the clean cobblestone finish so even
everything is cobblestone now all the
canals all the pads the ceiling the
walls it's all cobble okay other thing I
did we have a lighting system now get to
that a little bit I've also added a
squid killing thing here I finished this
up put some lights around
so I got four water sources here in the
center they push the squid to this lava
and they'll kill them if we want if you
don't want to kill this food if we just
want them to collect I'll keep the
trapdoors down and this squid will land
on top of them that's that plan that
should work pretty good I think I still
don't have the water canals in here it
wanted to show you this before I put
them back yeah and I started working on
a little control room viewing area type
thing that's what this is here not not a
whole lot done on it yet I added like a
sliding door thing cuz I always wanted
to build one of those since I saw one in
a document view that's cool there's a
lock for it
so the mobs can't get back in if we have
it locked or can't get in if it's locked
I should say let's let's go down here
show you changes I made with the wiring
and stuff
or how the wiring works so this I think
I showed you this before and I just
added this cobblestone wall here these
go to the Pistons there's a piston right
there
it goes all the way around I added
torches in here because I noticed mobs
were spawning on the redstone or else
they responding on these uh repeaters
I'm not sure so I may need to add
torches in my spawning pads after all
because there's four blocks where I
think they'll be able to spawn if
there's no light this goes all the way
around and these Pistons are for the
spider thing to turn spider spotting on
or off the ones that wrap all around our
for the outside ring I have and these
paths down here this wiring here is for
the spawning pads ooh
so why are you go straight right above
here is the spawning pad there's another
one above here another one above here
and another one above here so there's
this one wire handles four of them in
total there are sixteen spawning pads
and I have four wires so four times four
16 another wire
and another wire and there's one more
over that way this here is the wiring
for the sliding door pressure plates
above here and here and the wires split
and go to this redstone torch
there's a wire above that block and one
above that one and pistons bottom ones
over there and there's another one on
top of it they're pretty easy to set up
those sliding doors it's just a little
hard to see right now
and I forgot how to get out of here oh
yeah over here so this one goes down to
that lower wiring for the for these uh
pressure plates to come out I did hook a
lever up for pretty cool like I don't
even know how many there on just tons
I'm sure I should I'll be able to tell
you in a second if you shout this okay
so there's 16 pads there's four on each
and then there's one two three four five
six times two is twelve thirteen
thirteen times four is the den fifty-two
I believe so 52 plus 16 times four is 16
times four
oh brain leg brain leg 40 plus 24 is 64
so 64 plus I forgot what I said thirteen
times four is you know I'm gonna I'm
just gonna use especially this is stupid
13 times four plus 64
hundred and sixteen fresh or a hundred
and sixteen of these half-slabs pop out
of the ground that's a lot one piston
for each and there's also a hundred and
sixteen of these lava lights I thought
about the lighting a lot tried different
methods different types of lights some
that pop down from the ceiling like
using glowstone that comes down and then
gets replaced with cobblestone and you
know what
lava seemed like the simplest best
solution for me so that's what I chose
as each lab a light only uses one piston
no glowstone which is a nice feature and
it's pretty pretty simple the wire uses
little redstone with this method so oh
yeah and like the ones where the
glowstone comes down from the ceiling
and then retracts and gets replaced with
cobblestone that takes a lot of space
and it also each light takes three
Pistons at least I believe so with this
one they all take one they only take one
the light is pretty dim but it's spread
out very evenly because there's so many
lights so that's the way I like it and
that's bright enough that mobs won't
spawn so directly what the heck how did
I fall no no what happened there oh you
know what oh you you know what happened
ah by the way I came here to get some
redstone out of the chest
as apparently I had four or five stacks
here but you know what happened there
I fell through the ground because there
was a repeater on the ground I'm sure
that's what happened
oh I gotta hurry back my stuff better be
there that was a long walk actually
dang it I bet you I lost a lot of stuff
there
my pistons are fine I got a lot of
redstone back I think that's what I'm
mostly concerned about losing redstone
that's sucked
okay I just did that to get rid of the
water so that I could pick the slap up
make sure there's no items over here all
the lights are directly above the half
slabs down there put this back and I'm
gonna be a lot more careful and walking
around up here now there's a little
override switch up here Jason want to
test things out this took forever to dig
out and I had no TNT around I don't know
what happened to it all like it all
disappeared somewhere yeah I definitely
fell through a repeater B oh wait yeah
yeah I did because I just mined this out
there's no way I could fall into that
lab otherwise anyway so there's a lava
all the way on the outside and then
there's these four lines here and it all
kind of comes together this thing gets
activated it moves this block over lasts
directly below here so the lava gets
replaced with a cobblestone block when
this is extended and when it retracts
the lab is able to flow again and it
goes over top the glass that's how it
works and managed to keep it all within
2 blocks high which is great because I
really did not want to mine out any more
than I had to it took a few hours to do
uh-huh eventually I'll release my world
again and you can check this out in
further detail if you want and I'm gonna
have these little viewing areas here
thanks placement something like this so
this lever I'm actually going to change
to the lighting because it makes sense
because the lighting access is on the
side and I'm gonna change the spyder
option to this side because the wiring
for it is on the side because you go
down here to get to the wiring for it
I'll have that will have a glass on this
side too all the way mobs won't be able
to get in will have lighting on this
back will position it just right so that
it doesn't interfere with spawning here
and yet no mobs will be able to spawn in
here in the control room but that's all
a project for another day cuz this is a
getting along a lot of work to this
pretty much had to remove the mob system
and recreate it a hundred times more
complex a lot of work to it if you're
doing stuff with lighting I'll explain
how you calculate this so lava glow
stone pumpkins fire that stuff has a
light level of fifteen torches at a
light level of 14 so it's one less so
where the block where the lava is is
light level 15 where the glasses is 14
and this is three high so it has to come
down three more
so 13 12 11 is where this half slab is
light level 11
spread out 1 block this way is 10 then
diagonally here from that is 9 so that's
the lowest level of light right here at
level 9 and hostile mob spawn at level 7
or less so it's plenty plenty right in
here don't have to worry about them
spawning when the lights are on except
in these canals because they're not
filled yet so that's how you Tet delete
that same thing here I'll calculate it
so that like this cobblestone here is
that light light level aid at least and
everything out there will be lower so
let the in spawn so that's how that's
gonna work and then I'm gonna have an
elevator somehow to get to the surface
yeah pretty much right above me is
underneath my tree farm and cactus farm
that open area where I have nothing
built so I can pretty easily linked an
elevator to that section there somehow
and I think I think covered everything
oh I never showed it dark would have
been a mistake
so I don't have that wired down there
yet so I still have to work on wiring
this stuff major leg when you switch it
for a few seconds anyway and it's dark
in there this episode's pretty long so
we'll probably can't do the tests this
episode but maybe next episode little
spiders in there flip that down and
probably get some I know we'll get some
I've I've tried it already spiders
didn't spawn when they're down yeah
there's a spider right there so it's
working just like I wanted it to happy
about that
anyway thank you for watching we'll
probably have this almost done next
episode so take care