readings all this is ether
I'm just down here at the end of the
eats road and I was about to add in an
elevator thing to the surface
it's really loud and I'm thinking
putting it right here so thought you
might like to see us so what I'm going
to do is I'm just gonna think I'm just
gonna have like half slabs on round
around it
there's gonna be another each road in
front here I think Jesus I want to go
further
this cell probably replaced with
sandstone just because I really like
sandstone
it's like the brightest block in the
game I think that's why I like it's in
the default texture pack anyway yeah so
they'll be a boat elevator here
right-click to go in the boats and then
automatically you'll start going up to
the surface and then you'll dock is the
plan not exactly sure how it's all they
don't work
and out of fill this whole shaft up with
salted water blocks I'll probably have
glass tubing here we place some of it
the boat would probably have to be at
this level here for it to be convenient
and it's a sunny day outside so no there
goes the Sun actually I'll probably have
a load from this side because now I'm
not planning on having a roller on the
side for reasons you'll find out later
so I'll probably have some sort of easy
loader here and I'll probably hold the
boat down using trapdoors maybe maybe
I'll have a trapdoor right here okay
yeah just like this so the boat will be
held underneath it and that will
probably mean I need a pressure plate
underneath as well so that when I hop in
the boat it activates this trapdoor and
opens it I wonder what happens if if I
put it directly beneath if it'll opened
I'll probably use a stone pressure plate
yeah that might work just like that okay
well I'm going to work on this a bit and
then I'll give you an update all right
I'm ready to do my first test here so
I'm gonna have an easy loader here it's
gonna be the sandwich type so I have to
use this water pattern
oh yeah I guess I need some water here
for the boat to float on just for now
okay so this well we're just testing
this release mechanism right now the EZ
loaders not actually going to go here
okay and return the boat returns gonna
be above here I think from the surface
it's all just been try this out I kind
of think I need the pressure plate where
the water is there oh maybe not that
works that worked pretty good let's try
it one more time okay all right so
that's the way I'm gonna do it then
because that works really well so I will
be back in a bit I'm gonna work on this
some more well I got the boat elevator
all done now guys now that it's finished
I'm thinking maybe I should have made it
at the oral of it but I don't know it
something everyone's pretty familiar
with boat elevators have been around for
a long time but if you guys want a
tutorial just let me know and I'll I'll
make one for it it's pretty simple it is
seven by four and you can make it go as
high as you want
and let's see so I got like an easy
loader here to load a boat into it if
for some reason it got destroyed or
there's no boat when you first make it
so you just put the boat here goes up
there left then up a water elevator and
it gets into position over there I put
some signs here by the way the thing I
like about this as soon as you hop in
the boat the trapdoor opens and you go
up a lot of things like this you need to
push a button or a lever or something to
get it going but I've never really been
fond of that type of active activation
method it's kind of why I did the East
Road like I do it soon as you hop in the
boat of things and I used to make mine
carts I used to do it that way as well
I'd have a minecart on a pressure plate
when you say on the pressure plates
booster would come and push Amaya cart
that's the way I like to do these things
but anyway enough blabbering let's go
for a ride you just right-click on the
boat trapdoor ribbons solid water source
box in here all the way to the surface
and this water stream here pushes it
over onto another trap door I need to
build some kind of platform here because
right now I'm just dangerously
hovering on the side of a cliff but the
idea is you add eggs at the boat step on
a pressure plate trigger the trap door
it falls down and resets and if you want
to go down quickly you can also use this
as a water break boat goes in through
here it's back where it was we can exit
through this door here though so pretty
pretty simple I'll show you how this is
done this is the sandwich type of easy
loader type you need to use if you got a
block directly above the boat when you
place it so it goes over here I got a
water stream here and this water stream
goes to a wall and this one pushes it
this way so it's pretty hard to see
sorry about that but it's is you can
barely see if there's a to wide gap
there water's being held in place by
pressure plates and the water elevator
goes up pretty pretty straightforward
stuff but if you want a tutorial just
let me know how we take 15 minutes to
build or so
nice thing about using half-slabs if you
do this easy loader tight as you can
actually jump out of here but it's a
full block you need a ladder to get out
if you falling but anyway that's the
thing I like it you could also do that
water elevator difference
the speedy one with the flowing streams
but that takes more space and takes
longer to build and I've just put
sandstone in the corners for looks and
yeah that's the what new water elevator
and let's head back to the base and work
on some other stuff oh yeah just one
more thing guys if you guys can think of
a name for this for me I would
appreciate it just leave in the comments
and I'll choose the one I like the most
I could I like to refer to I like to
name the things I built just so it's
easier for people to refer to them later
so I'm drawing a blank if you guys
didn't think of a name for this let me
know anyway back to the base one thing I
want to give a shout out to someone to
sell garter I think I said his name
right hopefully he released a pretty
cool video the other day a world tour of
his world that he's had for many many
months he's actually won the first
minecrafter i ever subscribed to so that
was back in the day when I made my first
minecraft video like seven months ago
so I'm gonna put a link to his world
tour in the video description check it
out he did a pretty professional job of
it and it's neat to see a world that
someone's been working on for well over
seven months he's probably had it for
close to year now so check it out anyway
maybe I'll get you guys at this speed
what are you doing around here
the barn looks like a mess right now I
ripped out the entrance to it because I
didn't like how it looked and now just
in general I don't like the barn it
either so thinking about setting fire to
it very soon so I'm gonna have to rip
all this stuff out and then all once
they get rid of all the glass the wiring
the doors sandstone I'll set fire to it
and get rid of it there's a nice idea I
learned a few things from it but it's
kind of not in a good place and it's not
really working too well this is my
future plan for the barn it's much much
simpler basically the sheep and cows are
gonna land above this trapdoor here
they'll be held in place by these two
ladders so a lot of sheep will clump up
in this area and a lot of cows so it'll
be really easy to gather wool just come
outside boom boom boom boom boom and get
like 20 wool and then when you're done
it'll be a button here hit it drop door
opens they fall down into lava or
something like that and then more will
spawn and you'll have another 20 sheep
and cows their type thing
this one will be for wolves not quite
sure how I'm gonna hold them in place
but they'll come down here so I need to
run that pipe that Towson over to here
and I need that wolf pipe over there
down it's over here so that's the new
plan and that thing's gonna burn much
cleaner
something else I did just the game got
rid of all the water and signs down here
so I didn't need them for anything and
that's kind of worried the signs added
late to the game so that's why I got rid
of them um and I moved the ocean just a
bit I don't know how much I'm gonna move
it total it actually took quite a while
to do longer a nice expecting what I did
is I filled it up with netherrack
Heather acts really fast to destroy so
it's a good block to use so I had to
fill it all up and then mined out all
the netherrack I went pretty quick but
it still took a long time because
there's just so much water and yeah one
other thing I added one day I'm probably
going to rip out my minecart timer thing
and just make this a lot simpler but I
haven't done that yet
yeah I added this thing here just for
chicks the trap door is closed the
cactus or attacked I go down the stream
to the collection area in there if it's
open they fall in lava that's just so if
I ever decide I don't want cacti drops
any more I can destroy them quickly and
then they won't collect here and like my
game unnecessarily not that it will make
much difference but it's just something
quick and easy to add so I'm I decide to
do it anyway oh yeah and you guys
probably know this already but I'll just
confirm this I do have a 360 Canada in
my world now it's right over there and
see it from my base and you can actually
hit my base with it so if you want to
have some fun when I release my world in
it's right over there
one other thing I was messing around
with that is adding these sandstone half
slabs just to see what it would be like
kind of to bounce out the ones at the
bottom I don't like how it looks like
this if you guys have any ideas on how
to make it look good let me know I was
thinking about doing it all around
having sandstone but not like that that
looks ugly although the other way I was
doing it before by the way I have this
here the wooden door frame just because
a lot of people seem to want it let me
know if you like that the way I was
doing the trim around the top was using
wooden stairs like this that's another
option I might do although it looks a
little bit more plain you can't really
tell their stairs
this too much wood and the variable
timer is finally gone yes so I can
finally work on this area here again
which I'm excited to do my current plan
for out here is just to make it look
nice like kind of I might have a
fountain fake grass and trees and that
kind of thing out here although I'm not
really not really certain yet um what
else I'll probably I'll probably keep
this thing it does the job it's fun to
watch oh yeah the new squid or the squid
tank that's gonna go below the storage
room now since I'm ripping the barn out
although I haven't really started that
either yet but I'll get to it eventually
and yeah that's what's going on in my
world
so the spider systems working really
well for me I'm happy with it next
episode I'll probably work on tall mob
stuff let's see today I also finished my
first secret episode working on the
secret project so I'm making some
progress with that but I'm probably
going to end this episode here today
it's going to be a short one gonna try
to record a few more today yet few more
videos because I got family visiting
soon so I won't be able to make any
videos for a week or two so I'm gonna
try to get ahead so that ty can still
release some during that period of time
otherwise you're not gonna have any etho
for two weeks or so but yeah that's it
for today thank you for watching maybe
y'all add in a little clip from the good
old alpha days and one other thing I
should mention about video responses a
lot of people seem to being upset that
I'm not approving video responses I
still am every day approving a few the
problem is I can't keep up with them
anymore so I have about a hundred is
sitting in my inbox right now that I
can't get to
the other problem is people are kind of
abusing the video responses they seem to
be sending me responses as a way of
getting free advertisement for their own
videos I'm hoping you guys will stop
doing that just because you know I try
to give people free advertisement when I
when I feel like they're deserving it
and I don't mind giving you a
advertising through video responses but
you know some of the videos I'm getting
have absolutely nothing to do with the
video that their response to they're
just they're not video responses they're
just videos so please send me videos
that are at least related to the videos
I upload so like a lot of people send me
let's play episodes of theirs most of
those I ignore the only ones I will
accept is if they actually have a lot to
do with the video that their response to
and yeah so keep that in mind
oh yeah and the tutorial videos I'm very
picky about those in particular make
sure your video responses to my tutorial
videos have something to do with my
tutorial otherwise I'm definitely gonna
ignore those and yeah so don't abuse the
system and I'll be able to get through
more videos that way and I proved the
ones that are deserving okay but keep
them coming
I like watching videos you send me just
thought I'd let you guys know what's
going on with that and that's it for
today thank you for watching