hey everyone how's it going
this is etho and another good episode
here for you guys before we begin our
activities though squiddy is gone I
killed them
uh he was in my way you'll notice this
doc things a little bit different now I
was trying something I said I was
watching a video by 777 static 777 I'll
post a link to his channel in the
description but basically he made my
dock here but he finished it I said I
was good I needed to make it eight wives
so I tried making it 8 wide I'm still
having problems with it though and I'll
show you why I haven't really been
working on eats oops that was a very bad
example okay let's try this again I'm
going to ride two boats into here and
you should see the problem one looks
like it's lined up pretty nice
let's get another one in there that's
the problem
the boat is stuck underneath this boat
instead of being up right next to it and
that's kind of the issue that's been
discouraging me from working on eats at
all lately I don't know what the deal is
with that if you go in the boat it still
seems to push it a bit but I don't know
it's not quite the way it should be or
the way I think it used to work well I'm
going to mess around with eat some more
now and once I do a few things out we'll
start building some roads a lot of you
have asked what happened to the eats
Road because remember when I first
started that's that's one thing I was
working on well it's right down here
right where we left it
and actually we're going to take it for
a test drive because I thought it had
stopped working - I thought it was
having problems and now it seems like
it's working again so last night I made
a few changes to it that I was going to
abandon this thing because it was in the
way of our spawning pads but since I'm
not using these anymore there's no
reason to shut this road down this is
for you Adams uploads a lot of people
have been wondering if you can make them
two drops and stuff yes you definitely
can you can do turns do all kinds of
things that's so we'll get into some
time soon but for now I'm just going to
mess around with it off-camera and when
I figure a few things out we will start
building some etes roads but this
episode I said we were either going to
go entering or work on the mob system
and I left it up to you guys and like a
whopping 99.9% of you said that you
wanted me to go cave exploring so that's
what we're gonna go do no no no that's
not right about ninety percent of you
guys wanted me to work on the mob system
so that's what we're going to be doing
and I made a few changes in here I think
I have too much sandstone now so I might
change the floor but these are embedded
with the mob system I've decided
like we're going to have a chicken house
to get eggs type thing we're also going
to have no we're gonna have a another
area set aside where we can route the
steamers and cows so that we can get
milk from them and also applied eyes to
them so that we can make our dyes get
more colored wool yeah enough talking
for now let's get the work I gotta go do
some setup and get some glass and stuff
and I'll see you guys in a bit okay
everybody we're up here on level three
I've got it set the peaceful because
we're up for next to the tall mob
killing things I was making a lot of
noise I just moved this ladder thing
over a bit because we're going to be
working on this middle area and the
first thing we're going to try to do
with this passive mob system is make a
chicken separator and to do that we
pretty much just need to draw in all the
mobs through a layer of water since
chickens float down they get stuck in
the water and other mobs fall through
the water but I'm a little bit concerned
that this might not work because the mob
faucet thing I was dropping them like 20
blocks and some of them weren't going
through the lava
I'm worried I don't have enough Drop
Distance here for this to work but we'll
see as I'm going to set up this vertical
or horizontal screen here don't have
enough sauropods great okay we're gonna
put glass here I guess you need signs
here we're just gonna build a soil first
see if it works they don't want to waste
glass cuz I don't have infinite
resources
[Music]
get some signs we need 400 three sticks
and we're gonna have water going over
top these signs we took last year got a
few animals up there
oh no I need sticks almost did it again
probably only need a few sides for this
project so as I make a few I don't want
to sign mod guys I'm fine doing it the
normal way thanks for all the offers
need up to your platformer yes let's see
that's one two three four we need to
make it go eat probably Oh try six first
there's a chance this might work
just Lee's cough okay
so I think more the water already I'll
pose with some more glass do a quick
Indiana Jones same here
the water isn't far out
okay so I want to remove that soil where
all the animals are above and see if any
like sheeps cows or pigs get stuck in
this water they fall through it works we
don't kill them trying to make a hole
here
the chickens might get married too you
know
let's say the pig fell through she fell
through
faceless I'll not be so bad
cow got stuff that's all animals there's
a chance that cow might have landed on a
chicken I will just slow them down
either way you see how he's like yeah
he's falling through either way from
jumping around he pushes his way through
so even this should wear I mean
especially if I make this a long you
know we watch what I got recorded here
and see if I can notice anything though
what happened with that cow okay so I
couldn't really tell what happened
I think the cow hit the water and not a
chicken
but it doesn't really doesn't really
matter because this seems to be working
so I'm going to raise the water one
block though which I'll probably do now
it doesn't seem to matter how far you
drop on because like it helps but I
think just from jumping around all the
animals will be able to free themselves
anyway even if we get stuck in the water
it kind of seems like it's random if
they fall through or not it's like
sometimes they try to swim up through
the water and sometimes they don't taste
glass here this is what a whole will be
another hole over here where the
chickens go through I can't um LEM is
built out of glass I'm pretty confident
with this I like to build mob systems
out of glass just so you can see what's
going on inside it's just
I swear that you coming up over here and
trying to walk through like you can find
the staircase and climb their way up
around
okay I'm going to skip ahead today yeah
and we'll continue on normally if it's
nighttime guys I don't skip ahead
I play the way I should but when I'm
recording it's a different story I want
you guys to see what I'm doing
hey it's morning again let's get back to
work the video is getting a little bit
long
hopefully we'll finish this up this
episode the chicken separator the whole
mob systems going to take a long time to
do hey that's me glass and OH
oops precious glass
you know the thing I hate about setting
off TNT the most is I have to spend for
sand on every TNT I don't really care
about the Gunpowder because I got
infinite gunpowder basically but yeah I
get collecting the sand as it isn't fun
especially since I haven't really found
it desert yet make a good one okay we
got two high opening here now and
chickens will have a separate passage up
there all the other mobs will be down
here
and we're just going to set up some
water here to demonstrate actually we
should get an infinite pool up here
somewhere I'm running out of resources
good enough pace a little land in a
stream below and we'll extend this later
but just for this episode
[Applause]
put out water here for the separator
oops all this doesn't look good
what did I just do
[Applause]
stinking ah
poof
yeah I did too much damage with that but
definitely got to be careful in working
with the water
today we'll just have that for now and
this all either shorten it or extend it
depending on how it works I'm going to
have to watch the system for a while
unfortunately no mobs will spawn above
me if I'm over here I'm going to make
things a little more tricky so I'm going
to have to make a long path or something
out here so that they can and that's
what I'm going to do now I'm going to
watch it for a bit
so I've been watching it for a while now
and it seems to work very well that I've
shortened it completely and it still
seems to work um some things I've done
also I ran that tube all the way up
here's final whereabouts I need to
collect all the items together
and so at the moment there is no mobs on
the spawning pads above last time I
walked away they like instantly started
spawning let's see if it happens again
it was nighttime though
they aren't this time you have four four
up there last time I just walked away
and like instantly 20 spawned up there
the pig fell through they seem to fight
falling down pretty good
and so basically all this does is it
makes chickens take this path here all
the other moms take this path down below
and so next thing I'm going to attach to
this is a pig separator which should be
fairly easy to um something about the
spawning pads they're not done I do plan
on making them a lot more efficient I'll
probably cut them into boat cut them
into quarters is these big spawning pads
takes a while for the guys to walk off
into the water so I'll probably do it
like I have my hostile spawning pads
which worked very well and I think
that's where we're going to end it today
guys I know many of you wanted me to go
to the nether for adventure oh we will
be doing that sometime soon because I
got a bunch of things I want to do in
the nether I want to set up a base that
looks nice and is relatively safe I want
to make that 360 cannon to shoot at
ghasts and I want to make some sort of a
train station at some point I should
call it a minecart station I guess and
the thing I really want to do in the
nether like more than anything is set up
a zombie pigman mob system so at some
point we'll get to that but for now I'm
going to try get more down on this small
system because and a half way done I'm
curious to see how it will turn out too
but that's it for today you guys thanks
for watching I'll see you next time