okay I thought about this a little bit
and you guys are going to see the secret
project today for the first time the
real secret project yeah today's kind of
like a good-news bad-news episode I
suppose good news so we're going to go
see the secret project the bad news is
it's unfinished I've actually only spent
about four or five hours on it so far
which is really nothing considering I've
been supposedly working on it for two
months but you guys seem to think I'm up
to something huge which I'm really not
while it is kind of a huge project but I
haven't done anything to it really yeah
so something has happened which is why
I'm reviewing it today I didn't really
plan this but that's what happens
apparently someone else has made the
same thing as me so it's no point
keeping it a secret anymore
I don't think may as well show you guys
since you really seem to want to know
what it is so here we go
this is the real secret project isn't
over here um yeah it's supposed to be a
Frogger game that you can play with your
guy so it's not a mop system like you
guys thought it's actually a Frogger
game
I'll give them two details about that in
a little bit here so I'm going to give
you a little bit of background about
this project it's actually something
I've been wanting to make for think
about nine months now it's when I first
came up with idea it was right around
the time someone made the first pong
game in Minecraft using redstone and I
thought hey how cool would it be to make
a Frogger diamond and I would use mine
carts as the vehicles that you got to
get past and I would put zombies in them
so if you were walking by the zombies
would hit you if if you get close to one
of the carts and you would take damage
and you lose a life and have to start
over type thing and then my idea for the
logs and the Turtles was to have boats I
don't know if I have the setup so I can
launch any right now let me try I got
rid of it too darn used to have an easy
loader here but yeah there would be five
lanes of boats
what happened originally as I was
building this and I kind of came up with
idea for eats as I was building it and I
got distracted and then I start an LP
series and yeah and not much has changed
since and I still keep getting
distracted with other projects instead
of working on this one which has been
like my BB for nine months I've keep
telling myself I gotta finish this I got
to finish this and I still haven't done
it so yeah I was searching YouTube the
other day and just to make sure that no
one else has made it yet tonight found
someone has finally someone minecraft
pg5 made it and he did an exceptional
job on it too he kind of a beat me I
should say I wasn't really impressed
with his I his was a lot more simple
than I was planning to do mine I was
gonna have a lot of redstone and and
logic checking and stuff in mine it was
very simple and elegant which is kind of
why it was so good to gal link is in the
description now definitely checked it
out it's very cool I don't think he has
any dislikes on the video nor should he
because it's a very cool video but yeah
I have minecarts
basically this what the way this would
work is they have a door here keeping
you from entering the play field when
you're ready you would push a button the
door would open then you'd be free to go
out here minecart should be zipping to
the right left right left right and they
would be I was planning on doing them
each individually like and have them
each set to a specific pattern to go by
and you would have to find the pattern
kind of like in real Frogger to get by
without getting hit by the minecarts I'm
just going to skip to a date again I'll
be your back and I'm back so all this
cobblestone here is this kind of
temporary just wanted to get to
the basic shape setup as plan on
replacing it with something nicer when
it was all done so one thing I was going
to do is I was going to keep track of
the players lives so you would start
with three and I would keep track of it
using a memory unit in redstone um I was
also going to keep track of time so as
soon as you go through the door to begin
you the time would count down and if you
didn't finish the level and then get
your frog across to the others to the
other side and time you would lose a
life there's another thing I plan on
doing you know in Frogger when you go
outside of the play field and
the black area you lose a life I have
these pressure plates set up here I'm
going to use to detect if the player
goes too far to the left or right major
difference between mine and mine craft
pg5 which I thought was pretty
interesting so I was using boats for the
the logs and the Turtles and then we're
going to go right left right left right
you know and you would have to
right-click and hop between them before
going through the point of no-return
here you know minecraft pg5 he did his
out of pistons so he had Pistons coming
out of the water and you would have to
hop across before they they retracted
back into the water that was pretty cool
salt is very noisy though so one thing I
didn't like about it but very cool um
yes I was going to have lives it's going
to have time you would there'd be five
doors at the end here one for each fraud
you got to get cross finish the level
when you would go through one of the
doors memory unit would keep track with
that and then it would be closed so the
next time you go through the level that
door would be closed and the other four
would be open type thing if you tried to
go through a closed door again it would
know it was closed and you would lose a
life kind of like in real Frogger if you
try to go to the same one that you have
a frog already you lose a life the other
thing I was planning on doing was
keeping track of levels using redstone
and memory units so once you get all
five frogs across the pond here into
there five doors then you'd finish a
level you'd probably gain a life then
and
probably a victory tune would play using
note blocks for finishing the level then
the next level would get progressively
harder more minecarts would be on the
track and the pattern will change
pattern for the boats of change there
did be fewer boats as you go as you
advance through the levels so it would
get more difficult was what I was hoping
to do and let's see what else yeah as
you were playing as planning on having a
Frogger music loop playing using note
blocks all the time if the game the text
that you died then it would play like an
oh you died music tune type thing so I
was planning on doing some stuff with no
blocks um but yeah I haven't gotten too
far I got it all like figured out in my
head I just have to do it and I still
plan on finishing it even though I'm
showing you I just don't really want it
to be a secret project anymore where's
the ladder there's the ladder good job
so the last thing I was working on or
the most recent thing I was working on
is hollowing it out under here so that
the I could set up the boat loops so
when this is a boat launcher type area
this stream here when it gets the other
end it comes to one of these type things
and then it falls down and then there'd
be water stream underneath taking it to
the left and it would constantly loop
the boats and there would be doors at
the end to control the timing of the
boats like a neat system
and I was very careful at the end here
so that the boats wouldn't lose any
speed when they're getting launched
otherwise they wouldn't make it across
this pond here and yeah so that er
that's some of the things I was planning
on doing
that's the secret project I hope you
guys aren't disappointed
it is a cool project I think and I look
forward to doing it but I'm going to do
it at my own leisure you know as I feel
like working on it I will and I don't
have to worry about you guys hounding me
what's the secret project all the time
because now you know so hopefully
hopefully it'll get done eventually
though also I did record I think two
episodes of me building what I have so
far if you guys are interested I will
post them like if one day I don't have
any videos to post I'll probably post
those videos if you're interested and
you can see me building this and get a
little bit more detail on the plans for
it all but yeah that's what we got so
far so I was kind of hoping to have more
done on this before I showed you guys
but you know I have been posting videos
pretty frequently and it's hard to do
the LP series and then work on this in
the background at the same time that's
you know a lot of Minecraft to play in a
day so just then it happen and it's
pretty busy in July and then I had
family visiting then I got sick so all
those things add up and just kind of
just sat here for a long time and that's
that's what happened more good news
though since you guys know what this is
I don't have to hide it anymore so I
will be posting a new download to my
world in this LP episode check the video
description for a link
and this time I will be sure to start
off in the eye space I kind of messed up
last time starting on chocolate island
and then people can't find it so start
at the eye space I'm going to call it
ice cream land in so that's like
chocolate island you know ice cream land
we're going to start on ice cream land
and you can check out the new EMP units
you can check this out if you want and
all the other little changes that have
been going on in my world you can check
them out oh yeah I think that's
everything
so next episode we should be working on
the spider mob system and I will say
goodbye for today thanks for watching
what am I forgetting forgetting
something I don't know
okay bye bye