hello home wreckers
this is etho and this is another
exciting episode of is minecraft I'm
just on the roof here and I've noticed
there is a ton of mobs on the island and
that's kind of a side effect of lighting
up tunnels in the area since I can't to
spawn in tunnels and I don't have
torches all over the island they spawn
very frequently on the island now and
they're spotting on top of my roof
sometimes which I don't like that's
better okay so I figured out the
lighting I'm going to turn around and
you're going to see what I did
no more torches Oh actually one sec I
forgot to check a name okay so this was
an idea suggested to me by CX gamer
originally I was going to raise the
track one block I tried that it looked
terrible let's stuck out way too much
another option would be to lower it but
I don't think that would be the best
either so it's a level and there's these
little cutouts on the side of the track
which is where the stairs are and
underneath the stairs our torches which
light up the storage room very nicely
and it kind of highlights the track and
you still have a half-block wood
highlights around the chests and stuff
so it looks good
I think same with over here at the
sandstone so it's a pretty good idea I
think I didn't do the pot lights they
were another good suggestion I did add a
few around the place so like I got some
here just for a variety I might to fill
it with lava I'm going to create a
backup before I do that first and I've
been working on this a little bit just
now got a lot to do on it
I had the front nicely curved but this
back part isn't curved nearly as much so
I'm going to have to probably make this
front curved a lot less so it bounces
out a little better
this is my new furnace room I might try
to move the furnaces like embed them one
block so they look better or something
and of course I'm going to add texture
different block types
instead of just solid wood so I think
that's a I don't think I'm a very good
builder in this game I think of myself
more as a inventor and a guy that likes
mechanisms and stuff
I think basic trick to building is to
have a variety of different blocks that
look good together instead of having
like solid wood in this whole storage
room kind of mix and stone in and and
tree bark look and stuff like that just
to add a lot of variety and I think it
looks good and of course don't build
stuff square kind of try to curve it if
you can or you know make a variety of
different shapes so it's more
interesting stuff like that I think it
helps and you know other things too like
before I just had to to live indoors
here nothing so special about that now I
got water controlled doors that are
synced together it's a lot more
interesting than just having double
wooden doors like every that you've seen
a million times but yeah expert I wanted
to check if our squid buddies have a
chicken while he is alright we got a new
pet
hahaha
okay we should stop goofing around we're
going to head over to the candies and
make a little bit of a follow up visit
there and so I'll see you guys there
okay here we are again they are still
looking well okay so why are we here
well I feel kind of bad because I told
people if they wanted a different name
on the cannons besides the initials
just send me a message and all I'll
change it to whatever they want and some
people did that but I did not actually
make the changes because of my
disorganization
so she us anyone
d je r un so I think I should make those
Corrections
let's see AG donate it again thank you
very much that's the third time now
I like however I kind of like made fun
of people's initials okay
the law Canon is the AH come on
and we need to find Toby J solder is
Jacky TF and we need to find CV
let's see here err CG this is not all
we're going to do we're going to be
doing some other stuff here I did see
your name but I wasn't sure if you were
saying something in Japanese like thank
you so I didn't to actually put it but
now I know that's that's actually the
name you want J that is everyone except
for OB where's OB obi-wan Kenobi where
are you
PG yes see Vandy MF l see
and see and if I made any other mistakes
let me know and I'll correct them
because I am likely to do that
where's OB Curious George minds me of
Curious George
she likes bananas so yellow is a good
color I'm sure I check them all where's
OB wte Sam Oh gobo huh that's weird
one sec there we are
now why but I forgot about this row ob
is e ot1 thank you everybody
and I asked apat today oh yeah we got to
fix the essays cannon
there we go work now and I have had a
lot of people asking me how I build
these cannons and wanting a tutorial so
that's what we're going to do I'm going
to show you how I built these they're
very simple what I do is I just got
across usually I figure out what color
or block I'm using first sit above all
the load underneath place water
in all four okay and it all comes to
words the center here and at the center
you place a block and a half block which
I don't have any let's see let's do a
stone one move the block underneath and
oh man I'll have a glass okay
since I don't have a glass I'm just
going to use soil and I'll replace it
later I used to put three glass blocks
around and I'm going to try use note
blocks for the top on this one purple
[Music]
there you go let's see if I can place a
sign on these first not I guess let's
make it all purple this is try rel seven
I hope I said that right
thank you that's the guy that helped me
with the Zelda tune in my storage room
for the collection point
okay and now to run the wiring is pretty
easy I usually put the button over here
get some redstone place redstone on top
one here one here around I put so many
of these place six repeaters and that's
it so it's pretty simple all you got to
do is make sure the wire goes to all of
the T and T will be one here here here
and here
and then the repeaters delay the time
from the boosters to the projectile and
this wire sends the signal through this
block here to the T and T inside and
then what I do or have been doing is I
dig a hole down here and then another
one over here
this is to set up the display type thing
place a block one down from there don't
dupe straight down
and this should connect to my tunnels
that I've set up yep and then I have the
redstone torch on the block I just
placed here and if we go above if we can
go above you'll see this wires all lit
up now that's because it's a redstone
torch is underneath this block here so
you can attach anywhere on this wire
before it's connected to these repeaters
here and then I cover this up oops
and you would place another torch here
for the vertical wiring like that
Bradshaw flyer place one or two
repeaters wire wire there now it's
hooked up to the system so that's pretty
simple so one other thing I wanted to
try here I had this idea to put lava in
the center and someone else sent me this
idea - we're going to try it on cannon
that won't burn down let's go to the
obsidian one I have the most faith in it
put the ladder right here oops oops and
I'm curious if we place T and T if it's
going to go boom even if it explodes in
there since it's in lava
it won't do any damage it seems to be
okay low so this is another way that we
can achieve the flaming TNT like we had
with za Benji dose cannon except it
might burn down the wool cannons in the
wood ones so I might not make them all
like that
but it seems to be working okay I think
that's all I wanted to do here I'm going
to check the time well I guess we're 20
minutes in or so so time to end it here
I guess next episode I'm going to give
you guys a choice do you want to see
adventure or do you want me to go back
into working on the mob systems and if
you choose adventure you want me to go
cave exploring or do something on the
nether so let me know I that's what I
feel like doing one of those two things
and that's what we'll do so leave your
comments and thanks for watching
I'll see you guys later