hello everyone thank you for joining me
again today of course everybody knows
the big news minecraft beta 1.8 is out
now officially out the real patch has
been released and wow man so much has
changed it feels like a different game
to me it's a good thing I really like
the patch adds a lot of cool new
features I'm not going to bother trying
to say them all
in this episode I'm not very good at
summarizing stuff rather today I kind of
want to talk about how it's going to
affect the LP and the things I like
about and stuff like that I'm sure you
already are familiar with most new
features probably seen a few dozen
videos about it already but before we
get started I'll show you the trivia
game added a few new things to it has
absolutely nothing to do with 1.8 so why
not start there so I've added a a
general win and loose tune to the game
this was a sent to me by craft 9 1000
thank you dude I got a lot of responses
for different tunes I could use so thank
you everybody I use this one because it
had a lot of depth to it and it was
still relatively simple but I do really
appreciate all the responses I got to
give me a lot to choose from and a lot
of them sounded really good actually so
thanks everybody let's try it out I
think right now I have it so the left
side always loses and the right side
always wins
that sling sound I added a delay so that
thing moves over after the tune plays
instead of jeering the tune otherwise
the piston noise Tanner exit tune that's
pretty cool true B games just about done
this is the loop this is the memory
array so I got glass blocks for the
wrong answers solid blocks for the right
answers you know how it works the only
thing I need to add to this yet is a
score counter so something that keeps
track of the actual number of wins and
then I can use that to determine if the
game is won after you've gone through
all 11 questions and it will also be
able to I also need something to reset
the whole thing once you go through all
11 questions right now I'm just using
this button to clear that stuff but
anyway we don't need to talk about this
too much today one major thing about the
new patch is the lighting is very
different it's cool in ways some things
I don't like about it though for example
glowstone doesn't seem to glow anymore
which is disappointing it was one of my
favorite blocks and now it's just kind
of an ugly texture I don't know I'm not
sure if that will change I absolutely
love the dashing I'm so glad you can do
it all the time I was worried you want
to be able to and I don't know if you
know this but if you do it over ice you
can actually move it super speed kind of
one guys sent me a video
where he had a roof three blocks up so
like this all the way and when he would
jump you'd hit your head on the roof and
he said you could get going
16 blocks per second so twice as fast as
a minecart on ice just crazy ah he sends
me a video response I'll hopefully
approve it and you can check it out I
don't remember the link to it or
anything unfortunately but yeah so lots
of cool stuff added I love dashing and
stuff I love running around with the Sun
Pro so much fun and fighting mobs and
stuff whoo feels like you're going so
fast I love the brightness setting too
so at night you can make it pretty
bright and you don't need to increase
the contrast when video editing which is
great but as great as the patches and
everything as much as I like all the
nude features it has created quite a
problem for me and that's what we're
going to talk about now we need to
decide where this LP is going and I
really want your guys input on something
at the moment I'm leaning strongly
towards starting a new world a new LP
world and just putting this one aside
because there's a lot of problems with
the new patch and I don't think it's
fixable
really
first of all the new chests will talk
about their cool they play an animation
when you open them I like that
bad news for one thing their lighting is
dark I think I would have to replace all
these let me try yeah so if you replace
that they become proper again not an
impossible task but just one of many
issues I have to face the other thing is
they are now smaller they don't fill a
whole block so for example I can see the
sand behind there which doesn't look as
good
so yeah chess or one issue main problems
though are at the eye space so I believe
we should head there now and then I'll
talk about them here we are at the eye
space looks a bit different now doesn't
it with the new lighting a lot more I
guess orangish brownish yellowish I
don't how you would describe it yeah
this is where the majority of the
problems are which is unfortunate
because this is like my new area this is
where I had all the plans and now
they're kind of done away with with the
new patch first of all as many of you
know passive mob spawning has changed
significantly spawning pad above does
not function anymore and I cannot get it
to function anymore I'll talk about the
spawning how it works in just a bit here
but yeah basically passive mob spawning
is out of question now so most of what
I've built here is for nothing
again you can see the glowstone isn't
glowing which makes this place look kind
of crummy the chests are messed up you
can see through the cracks they're black
I have to replace them all but the main
problem now is that snowy biomes don't
exist anymore they were not included in
1.8 they were taken out of the game
which means if I destroy this ice block
here it will no longer reappear ever if
I destroy snow on the ground it will no
longer reappear
it no longer snows in a snowy biome that
will no longer reappear which means my
infinite source of snow my main building
material is also gone so yeah that kind
of sucks this is in a snowy biome
anymore it's just a pine forest biome
with a lot of ice and snow
built into it basically so that's a huge
issue of course there's also the issue
with the mob systems the hostile mob
system we'll go check that out yeah
actually what I heard was that the snowy
biomes will be re added to the game in
the 1.9 patch when it comes out which is
probably not going to be for weeks or
months from now and since this is where
I'm in working I don't really want to
wait for that yeah anyway let's let's
check out the hostile mob system so it's
switch to easy as you know you can't see
tags above mobs heads anymore that's
that's okay with f3 you can see your
seed now that's cool
first guy Enderman you still a block
already a lot of people are wondering
about the fog thing if you need to
change your fog distance I've heard you
hold f3 and then press F yeah not cool
you can see them Enderman are white when
they're on low fog that's cool you can
use this x-ray yeah so hostile mob
systems it's possible to make them work
still I would have to adjust this I
don't know if there's any blocks that
Enderman can spawn on or that mobs can
spawn on that they won't the Enderman
won't pick up I'm not sure about that
yet I'm guessing there is at least one
or two different types so I could have
to change everything to whatever type
that is or the other option is to lower
the ceiling in there to only two high
instead of three high so that Enderman
won't spawn but as is right now my mob
systems are all broken
Enderman will take pieces away until
water starts flowing down and it totally
gets messed up same with on chocolate
island all those mob systems are broken
the passive one and the hostile one I
would have to spend a bit of time to fix
the hostile one there as well so just
more reasons why I'm thinking of making
new world
yeah so this is what happens is keep
ripping pieces out and it falls apart
water starts flowing like it's not
supposed to and it just stops working
after time so this next issue is a
really big one and it's actually the one
that made me realize that I probably
should just start a new LP world it's a
severe issue I don't think there's any
way around it as many of you know
landscape generation has changed in the
1.8 patch now maps are generated using
fractals which allows for some pretty
pretty amazing landscapes in the 1.8
worlds but unfortunately the 1.73 worlds
and the 1.8 world generation does not
work together anymore and so this is
this is a boundary of my 1.73 worlds
this is where the 1.8 begins this is a
problem all 1.73 worlds have there's
ocean biome all around the newly
generated around the old chunks and they
stretch on for miles as far as I know
even in COEs world he started he made
another portal and he went a long
distance in his world and he he had the
same problem he started in an ocean
biome and it seemed to just stretch on
and on
there will be islands in it and stuff
but I don't know if there is actually
any of the other biomes beside ocean I'm
going to keep I'm going to go as far as
I can and see if I see like a swamp
biome or something one of the new ones
okay I just I was wrong about that I
went about 500 blocks and I found a
pretty big continent there's a desert
I'm in the pine forest right now I even
found a ravine there's a tree down there
that's cool you can see there's some
cows down there
very strange isn't it there's no grass
how'd they get there I'll talk about
that soon yeah
so I just there are more biomes it's
good but even with that I still feel I
want to start a new world let me wait
let me know what you guys think about
that if you think it's a good idea I
think it'll be fun be quite the
adventure I thought we should go check
this out actually test out the new
brightness setting at night here too yes
I think it'll be fun starting a new
worlds let me know what you guys think I
was looking around at seeds today sure
for a cool seed I found one that was
pretty neat but if you guys know any
really outstanding seeds let me know
also I'm not really sure what to do if I
do start in a world like should I
continue from episode 102 like should
that be the first episode in the new
world or should I just start give it a
new name and stuff like doc am did with
his new world tour let me know about
that in these new areas strongholds
won't generate I'm pretty sure villages
don't generate and I'm not sure but I'm
guessing the abandoned mineshafts might
not generate either kind of hoping to
see one down here but I didn't find one
the only way to make that happen is if
you edit the world file and change one
of the values but yeah this lighting
this new lighting is pretty cool okay so
I did find an abandoned mineshaft after
all I just said new generate very cool I
probably want to explore this on camera
though because I did not bring torches
and I'm on peaceful right now which
would be pretty lame
I didn't bring equipment I find a lot of
the times these things just catch on
fire because there's always latha around
all the wood burns where's my sword got
to find a chest where's a chest
others none okay anyway uh I should
probably mention about the new passive
mob spawning because I have a lot of
people asking me about that so let's
head back to the ice base I do have a
world backup by the way I have restored
it probably about 20 times today I had a
lot of trouble getting the 1.8 working
today my game got corrupted somehow and
levels weren't generating properly I
couldn't login to the minecraft server
the huge huge huge issue to get it
working okay
okay so passive mob spawning is
completely different now it's no longer
just if mobs are 24 blocks away from you
and within the 144 boundary type thing
anymore
where they would only spawn on grass now
they seem to only spawn as you're moving
around so when that chunk loads or
something it seems to randomly decide if
it's going to place the passive mobs and
they'd spawn on other stuff besides
grass now as well you saw in that ravine
we had some towels it's because they can
spawn on stone now I'm pretty sure they
can spawn on blogs like wood soil grass
probably quite a few other blocks I'm
sure there's a few types they don't like
half slabs water
that stuff's probably the same where
they can't spawn on it there's also some
other conditions like they will not
spawn in certain biomes from what I
understand what I understand and from
what I've seen I talked to a guy named
the sprue today and he said they will
not spawn in ocean or desert biomes even
if you have grass in them if you place
grass in a desert biome you won't get
any passive mobs and I agree with that
that's what I've seen as well
yeah today I saw a pig spawn on top of a
tree like the very top would blocked in
a tree is where he spawned inside of a
leaf block which was very weird and he
was like stuck there the sprue also sent
me some pictures showing pigs on top of
a roof and one of the buildings of the
village there's no way they could've got
up there unless they spawned and it was
like a cobblestone roof if I remember
right
so yeah I don't know how lighting
effects spawning not sure if it has any
effect I'm guessing it doesn't but yet
you don't see any animals in cave
systems in the way I believe that works
is they only will be placed on the
highest block in a location so they
could be placed here but they probably
won't get placed down here assuming this
was a soil block because there's a block
above and I believe that's how they
prevent them from spawning inside of how
citizens excuse me and prevent them from
spawning inside of houses as well tongue
twister just my theory I don't know for
sure how it works but that's what I've
observed all right guys anyway I'll
probably end the episode here today
thank you for watching as usual this may
be the last episode in this world I'm
not sure we'll see please give me your
feedback about that if you have any
suggestions if I do start a new world do
you have any very epic seeds I could use
I found one really good one on the
forums day which I'm planning on using
but if I find a better one I'll use that
instead
now those Enderman are up to no good and
if you have any suggestions on the
format I should do if I start a new
world let me know I'm thinking I'll
probably just show everything at first
and slowly start showing you less and
less resource gathering that kind of
thing as it as I did established kind of
like I did this one go back to basics
and then as I get established we'll get
back to the complex builds and stuff
should be good I think it'll be fun if I
do lots of fun anyway take care thank
you for watching bye bye