Hey ladies this is Ethel and guess what
times blunting right now I never show
you guys when I'm spelunking just
because whenever I asked if you want to
see it you usually say no the majority
says no but today I stumbled across
something pretty epic so I want you to
watch this and I'm out of food here so I
can't miss it
and my oh man that's crazy this is the
coolest dungeon I've ever found
skeletons down here spiders up there
that's pretty pretty weird just gotta
make sure I shut this off one left had
always spawned out there Wow
that is pretty cool
I found a duel spider dungeon in this
world too before with the zombie one
nearby but I think this is even cooler
Wow gold okay so let's check out what we
got my favorite item and we have some
wheat gunpowder lots of iron some more
buckets oh that's where the other larger
land and one chest left do you think
we're gonna get any cookies nope
another saddle that's it yeah it's
really easy to take down dungeons for me
now unfortunately this game needs some
new challenges but that was pretty
pretty cool and if you're wondering
where this is the coordinates are X
minus 521 and Zed 81 and if I ever need
to find it again I have this video so
that's it guys for the adventuring today
maybe I'll show you one other thing so
when I go spelunking what I like to do
is I bring a bunch of bones with me and
a few seeds and generally I don't even
bother bringing any food with me how
would I do if I need to recover
just plant some soil plant some soil put
down some soil and I'll make myself your
mom and it's a fertilizer very simple
and you can pretty much get them
connected doing this as long as you have
bones and you get bonus keep exploring
when you kill the stove it's so that's
what I do and then you just make bread
from it as otherwise it takes up I
usually forget to bring food with me
what to toss just like that okay let's
get back well I'm gonna keep exploring
here but next thing you see will be at
my face okey so the bad news I fell down
like this hole in the cave and it was a
tight closed area and I got pushed
against the wall by two zombies and
there was no way out and I died so I
lost about a stack of iron stack of
mossy cobblestone think about ten
diamonds and a bunch of other stuff gold
redstone but I went back to the same
cave and I got even more stuff I have
some redstone again which is good that's
the main thing I was upset about I lost
two stacks of redstone
but anyway some people were wondering
myself included where general spaz came
from last episode and I did a little
investigating and I found this little
hole here where he came up apparently
next to there's also a deep hole that
was covered and there's another one over
here even and the sand was just being
held up by the sign here very strange so
what I think happened is he somehow
walked over this hole fell down was
saved from fall damage from this water
break above and this water stream
carried him to this door thing
it's a diagonal stream so that the hinge
doesn't get in the way and this door
seems to have been controlled by a
pressure plate down here it's an
inverted door so it would be closed if
something was on the pressure plate and
then he would be freed when this item
responds in five minutes which is very
strange so I think however this worked
I believe this hole here was for
throwing an item down and then spaz fell
down here
and then he was timed properly for this
door to open at the right time when that
despawn and then there were seems to be
solid water source blocks all the way up
so very clever little device by spazz
don't know how he came up with that one
I don't really know what happened at the
end of the last episode I was knocked
unconscious and I woke up here so I
don't know who won
so this spot here used to be blank but
now I've added trapdoors here so I knew
I left it blank for a reason and
something else I noticed apparently this
thing is broken again and I just fixed
it like a few days ago so now I need to
fix that again while we do it some other
time
I want to do some work on eats today
this place still looks rough over here
the one thing I want to try to do today
is get my boat elevator working here
again so I suppose I brought some stuff
with me already get started there's a
few ways you could do this so I'm gonna
experiment with these one way I think is
just to put signs here and need some
more signs I go through so many signs
okay and I'm going to put one over here
and that will flow good and then this
will come down here so I'm going to set
up a little ez loader here to do some
testing I guess I'll just put this out
here got some pressure plates with me
and do that that I think you get the
boat underneath the ladders you need to
put the ladder at the end of the ez
loader so stupid water currents so right
over here
J let's make us a boat and see what
happens here place in the center oh well
I didn't work J so the boat won't rise
like this I think I can put wood over
there and here and then I think if I get
rid of this nope
hmm why isn't it rising going to put a
pressure plate over here oh is the
pressure plate doing it okay very
interesting so two boats I guess
pressure plates count two solid blocks
okay so I can probably put that back and
let's try this again I hope science
don't count as solid blocks otherwise
this isn't gonna work okay that time it
went under the ladder and it stops there
so it's one block the ladders one block
away from the easy loader here
let's see why isn't that working ouch I
probably have to get rid of this block
here and this one here it seems like
signs do affect the boats as well let's
do a little test with that we're gonna
put one just over here and if the book
if the boat stops there it means it
affects them yep okay um so I'm gonna
have to do a different method then I'll
see you in a little bit okay so to get
the boat to rise I'd seems I need to use
solid water source blocks for this so I
can put a glass casing around the water
or I think what I'm just gonna do is
these ladders to hold the water in place
oops
suddenly place one of those glitch
ladders and then I'm gonna do that for
this side here just like that and I
should be able to fill this up no
problem
well don't know what happened there
just like this
although placing the water is going to
be a bit of a challenge for this corner
here Oh missed oh no is that stupid
glitch where it destroys a ladder again
okay well this is getting annoying quick
so what I'm gonna do is just place
blocks all the way up so that's
something to place the water against and
then I'll destroy it
yes like this okay I filled it up to the
top I just had these two last ones to
place and I have that problem with it
not going to these two blocks here so I
can trick it doing this force the blocks
the updates there just like that
this is what it looks like
water's being held in place by the
ladders I could use glass instead or
some other block but kind of like how
that looks okay let's try it out to see
if it works pretty sure it will unless I
overlooked something
oops that happens if you try to enter a
boat when it's moving quickly the odd
time that will happen gonna wind up
going up going up good
that's fixed
I didn't do the fancy quick rise
elevator just because this is such a
little rise but I'll experiment with
that later - all right guys so it's
doing a little bit of an experiment here
I built something I've never built
before this is called pulse limiter
it's a redstone circuit I saw on the
Minecraft Wiki page and what this does
it lets out a short pulse to the door
here or whatever you hook it up to and I
plan on using this for my each Road
doors for the dispenser so it only lets
out one boat instead of two like your
husband so I'm gonna show you a little
test I did here when I hop on the
pressure plate the items fall down and
then when I hop off they just stay there
so that's the exact trade I was looking
for so I think this should work I'm
gonna try add this to my eats Road now
and hopefully hopefully it does what I
wanted to
all right so I got a little bit
distracted here I was gonna hook up
pulse limiter to the door but then I
started wondering if I could use
trapdoors instead as just kind of
curious to see if they would work like
this and the way I have it set up here
does not work and I'll show you why
we're loading a boat this door here will
hold the boat like I wanted to and then
when its flipped down the boat goes but
for an actual dispenser this does not
work because in order for you to use
this the pressure plate needs to be a
jacent with the trap door and so the
pressure plate overrides any redstone
wiring you might hook up to it so when
I'm honest the door is up and when I'm
off it it's down so it's the reverse of
what I want it to do and also I would
still have problems with boats do boats
going through I think this one here does
absolutely nothing the boats will pass
by it if it's up and if it's down so and
I can't put a pressure plate
it's diagonally from it like I want to
because your player is on the right side
so case you didn't know this for the e
throw to all these pressure plates when
you go over them you only go over the
one on the right and the one on the Left
doesn't get activated
so yeah I'm gonna try one more thing
here
I wanted to experiment with this a
little bit more the other trap door idea
I wanted to test wasn't as simple as I
thought it was gonna be so I just
skipped doing that and I went back to
using a door I went ahead and wired
everything already
since you know redstone wiring doesn't
interest a whole lot of people but this
is how this works and you hop in the
boat the door does this just lets out
one boat now but remember I also need to
hook this pressure plate up to this door
as well do the same thing so this one
does a quick policy as well and then
this one here just is the holding system
so let's take a look at the wiring now
that I got the hard part done
so this is the further pressure plate
comes to here lights up this torch and
other closer pressure plate is above
here and it goes to the same torch so
they share the same pulse limiter over
here
it's pout is unpowered this wire here
which lights up this torch goes to pulse
limiter here goes down lights up this
torch and the door is right above this
block here pause the video if you need
to get a better look okay so let's go
for the first each row test that I've
done in a while full lengths of the road
is set up right now I just have a loop
at the very end so we'll come back to
here so let's try this out three boats
oh dang it I bump the boat let's see if
it works
that's fine it's fine
always use three boats when you're
testing to make sure only one boat what
was let out there exactly what we want
and then I cut out the rest of the song
and here is my loop which I hope works
yep and now we're heading back i might
hook up a song to this side too I don't
know see how I feel it's a fast those
coordinates change approaching our newly
constructed water elevator here
works just fine holding area hopefully
works yep
let's out another boats to replace the
one we just stuck from the other side
assuming we had another dispenser set up
at the other end which we don't so that
other boats that's going to leave that
here too yeah let's go to the other end
one more time I'll show you what my plan
is I have plan on making what if you
eats roads actually at this end here and
hop out oops
broke it oh I marked out where my other
dispenser thing is going to go right
over here and what I plan on doing is
kind of having a little dome area here
they'll be a road I think to the right
one to the left it's maybe and one going
that way as well and in the center there
will be a boat elevator to go to the
surface so five Direction intersection
is the plan
over here is my spawning system by
general spazzes house or his what do you
call it I want to say cavern but I don't
think that's right big hole in the
ground
general spazzes big hole in the ground
yeah
so that's eats at the moment I will keep
working on it I plan on doing different
styles of road just to give people more
ideas this is the style I like the 8 or
the 6 wide style you can make it a lot
smaller though of course and use
different materials there's a lot of
freedom with the way you can build a
nice road well sorry guys I guess it's
time to call it the end of this episode
it's getting long it's been fun I'll try
to keep you up to date with what I do
with eats and so I've decided to start
the secret project now or very soon
anyway so I'll be putting my world up
for download again this will be the last
time you can get an update of it until
the secret project is done is the plan
and so I expect it will take at least 2
weeks to do the project
I mean it's raining
about two weeks it might take longer I'm
not sure it's kind of a complicated
project
I might have to invent a few things to
make it work it's a unique idea and I'm
not sure how well it's gonna turn out
but hopefully they'll be cool and worked
the way I want it to but yeah if you
want to download my world check the
video description for this episode for a
download link and as I build the secret
project I'll be recording secret
episodes which I'll upload once it's
done and while I'm building it I plan on
continuing my regular episodes so
hopefully I don't think it'll interfere
with that
I think that's it guys so
thank you for watching that rain is very
loud and I'll see you again next time