hello everyone how's it going we're just
hanging out up in the sky here on our
new spawning pads and some of your
relatives and the grass has finished
spreading and we're going to get to
going to work on them some more fish
finish things up up here um so we need
to set up our water canals and actually
you know what I'm gonna turn sound down
and we're gonna need a lot of signs and
everything seems to be working pretty
good still the mobs don't to walk off
our spawning pads that only seems to
happen if someone pushes them and so in
order to get them go down we're going to
need to push in with water and so that's
the center I'm going to need to move
this passageway up
but I think ideally we want to place the
water eight blocks from the center so
one two three four five six seven eight
so it makes it right to the edge without
going over and we'll probably place
signs there other side and we should get
some stairs you know what we're going to
use wooden stairs this time and same
trick that I do with the hostile mobs
take the spaces under the signs just
like this and place the stairs in the
direction you want the water to flow
and they'll the mobs will be pushed up
the stairs by the water get out of my
way and I'm going to do that for all of
them and we'll see you in a second these
guys are annoying mainly crazy bye bye
I think hardly wait to kill them all
move it ah I really should have made a
sword
okay so we got water canals all set up
we made a bunch of fences we're going to
put all around and yeah so these fences
aren't going to be for the mobs because
the mobs won't walk off I think mobs
only walk off if something is I think
they'll only walk off if the drop is
only three or less blocks so this is two
over here underneath our signs is three
I think if you want one block deeper
they wouldn't walk off because they take
fall damage but these fences are because
well ah ah I had a leg spike okay some
people were wondering what this f3 graph
thing does I'm going to explain it to
you from what I understand um I don't
know exactly how it works but basically
the graph is keeping track of your frame
rate your frames per second you'll
notice some of the it like some places
are higher some places are lower the
higher places are that places are like
frames where you are legging more um
yeah the higher the spike is the higher
the fewer your frames per second are
Maude yes and the lower the jumps are
I'm legging again you see that high
spike that's a leg spike if they are red
that means you are getting less than 60
frames per second and if they are green
that means you're getting 60 frames per
second or more so red means you are
losing frames and your performance could
be better
so since I'm recording there's a lot of
there's another like spike there's a lot
of a red in the graph and that's
basically what that does then you got
your ex excuse me your x y&z coordinates
where is the Sun Sun is moving this
direction which is you see how the Z
coordinate is changing when I walk this
way
that's east and west and then x
coordinate is
north and south and why is up and down
another leg spike and some people have
said that another one that's some people
have said that the y-coordinate is at
your feet and other people have said
it's at the top of your head I don't
know which it is but regardless you can
use it to figure out roughly where you
are in the world like sea levels around
64 I don't know which level exactly it
is right now I'm at 95 if I go up one
block it'll be 96 so you can subtract
differences to figure out changes in
height that you've made another leg
spike yeah
so these fences like I was saying I'm
lagging so bad are for I plan on like
moving the tree farm up here probably
eventually the trees will probably be
all around this fenced area and they'll
probably be other things up here too a
lot of people have commented that my
world looks ugly now well
it's a work in progress let me down let
me down I actually really liked how the
soil looks although I do like the really
green grass - um yeah if you looked at
the like that doesn't look very good
eventually there's going to be a huge
building all around the sink hopefully
but function comes first and then looks
come second I'm going to stop my Dean
for a second I'm lagging too much all
right we're back so I don't know what
all the numbers at the top left of this
f3 thing oops
are for maybe someone else will comment
on it
top rights is memory usage and I think
it might be bugged because it says I
have 989 Meg's but I actually have 16
gigs in my computer so no idea what
that's about and another thing I wanted
to point out a lot of people have
commented that light doesn't pass
through stairs anymore that is
definitely not true um and I'm going to
show you this because behind this stair
here and this stair here is a block
instead of lava and you'll notice that
they are darker these two sides while
all the other ones are being lit up by
the lava still so I'm not sure why that
rumor is spreading around but light
still passes through stairs and I plan
on abusing that glitch until it
fixed like I do with everything else all
right
another big change I've made is I've got
the new hostile mob system up and
running kind of and I've changed all
these tubes around before we have a tube
for spiders and one for the tall mobs
ounce this one two by two two that goes
all the way up and so we only have four
spawning pads set up and it's very
efficient pretty much equal with what I
had before because I spent another about
our lighting up tunnels but I still have
some more tunnels to light up as you saw
in last episode and I don't really have
this thing doing anything yet they're
just drowning over here so I got to hook
this up so that I can collect their loot
because I'm running low on TNT and I'm
getting close to 5,000 subscribers so
need to start saving up soon
so well I got to sit down
so connects right over here I ripped
everything out that was over here
and this is all shut down still and by
comparison this one is probably six
times bigger than the one I'm using now
and then oops
I'm convinced that like the popular
opinion on the Minecraft forms and
everywhere else is that in order to make
a really good mob system you need to
make something huge I don't think that's
true
I think all that's important is that you
light up the tunnels around the area and
then it'll work pretty good so this is
for spawning pads that I've split in
half to four sections so there is four
times four twenty not sixteen of these
6x6 pads
I got the four-way knob evader working
pretty much perfectly - I'm going to
make a tutorial on that soon show you
how to build it from scratch yes that's
all that's down here pretty cool so even
with the new mom system I still want to
use this timer thing because it's pretty
convenient just to walk over here and
pick up everything so I need to kill the
mobs up there and send their loot down
here for both the hostel and I want the
Friendly mob drops to be routed to your
- so we're going to try to hook up two
pipes I think and I forgot how I built
this thing so let me ripping it apart
this wire is from the loop levers that
used to control the junctions um
okay that's a dispenser let's try to try
to find the best place to drop the loot
probably J this is the center he's right
on this line here the signs probably not
needed
oh never mind
so from the center one two three one two
three okay start it start to destroy
check it out
I really hate this glitch where you
can't jump out of the water okay
I'm just wasting tons of time in this
episode hope you guys don't mind so I'm
going to run a tube all the way up from
here I just this water isn't need it
anymore and I just that sign isn't
needed
so I'm going to have two pipes one for
the hostile drops and one for the
friendly mob drops and I'm going to
still use these two levers to turn them
on or off there'll be a minecart teeth
that controls whether or not the loop
can fall so if I don't want to mix the
the hostile mob drops with the friendly
mob drops I can turn them on or off
using these levers to light that's what
I want to hook up okay other pipe goes
here
double-check that it's centered oops I
kind of want it to look - even - yeah I
think that's right that's still from the
old piping
you guys say I never build anything on
camera so if you don't like this episode
that's that's why because I'm actually
building stuff it's hard to talk and
build stuff at the same time okay looks
good yep
all right so they'll fall down the pipes
and get sent here still don't need to do
anything with the lights someone
suggested I should change all this
cobblestone with wood I might do that
too I'll probably do that off camera if
I do um need to figure out how to run
the redstone
I will do that another time I should
probably wrap this episode up pretty
quick here oh yeah I decided what I'm
going to do with this room finally
firstly I'm going to get rid of all this
lava because my storage room keeps
catching on fire randomly it doesn't
that doesn't really burn the thing down
but they'll be random fires everywhere
and the odd time a block will disappear
too like for example I accidentally let
this tree grow that I planted and the
bottom block on it burnt and only it and
yeah that happens to a few blocks so
I'll probably replace it with torches
did I say what it's going to do here
this is going to be like a control room
I'm going to have all the options for
the mop system in here like if I want to
send mobs to my record studio I'll have
a lever that I can flip or if I want to
send chickens to a chicken coop I'll
have a lever it'll probably be a bunch
of options I'll dance that another
episode
but I should probably open this up
before we and it's just to make sure
here they come
that looks really funny
awesome
yeah we got a chicken so much carnage
thank you killing me before I push them
off oh okay um until next time until
next time thanks for watching guys and
I'll see you later I almost forgot
there's a lot one more thing I wanted to
mention I've been putting up this LP
world up for download on a site called
fire file serve and many of you have
complained about this website and some
of you even said it wants to charge you
money just to download the file
definitely don't do that I am going to
upload the LP world to another website
you guys suggested mediafire and so I'm
going to upload the world to mediafire
and put a link in the description and
I'm going to do that right now so thanks
everyone see you