and we're back hello and welcome to
episode 3 of our let's play series last
episode when we left off we had just
caught this creeper here and now I'm
going to tease them a little bit just to
be mean because I hate them and it's fun
oh he's shy it's okay you can come out
that's weird
come on apparently he doesn't move after
he's caught now thinking it through the
doors hmm oh well well well where'd you
go oh man where do you go don't be down
here no you must've died somehow okay
anyway this episode I am going to
dedicate to three parts we are going to
build a tree bar and talk about tree
farms
so the tree farm is going to go over
here ah of course
at least our spawn is closed because
that really sucked but I guess I deserve
that doing right no harm no foul
okay so our tree farm is going to go
over here still and so trees they take
about a five by five space each and I
usually make my tree farms the same way
every time we're very similar um this is
the pattern I do something like this
oops it's a lot easier when there's
ground underneath
oh wait I'm doing this wrong I think
yeah yeah so I have like a ring on the
outside of the half steps and then with
cobblestone I'll do that then I'll put a
soil block in the middle and torches on
the four corners for light and then the
tree sapling goes here and basically you
repeat that for however many trees you
want so I'm going to get some more
resources so if you don't want your
trees to grow too tall
like I don't like it when you get the
big trees all you need to do five six
seven is place a glass block above the
tree about seven blocks high and then
the tree won't grow too big
just like that use a glass box so that
light can still reach the tree so even
if there's leaves above the tree here
these torches will allow you to plant
the sapling and allowed to continue
growing even though there's no sunlight
above and so I'm going to repeat that
pattern a few times and I'll be back
okay so to make a long story short I
tried to stay out all night working on
the tree farm I thought I could and then
I ran and then I panicked and Here I am
and yes I am aware of the irony of all
this oh I got him right where I want him
yes
so these guys pretty much chased me down
I did get a bit done though um y'all
work on an idea in the morning I'll work
on the road for now see you sir all
right we're down here at the road it's a
still dark out so I'm going to actually
make some stairs
make things a little nicer down here and
that was a dumb idea and there's
probably a bunch of guys out there okay
now I'm going to built the wall a little
bit and they'll be a wall here and the
wall here and yeah that's a dispenser
that's the return system the return
system links to the dispenser and it
makes a loop I'll show more how to do
that another video might be day yes okay
I'm going to head up to the truth on I
think
and fairly safe oh and of course I get
no more meat now we're going to catch
another creeper only one only one oh
crap what is he doing ah that was fun
there seems to be an issue with the mob
trap they get stuck on the doors um yeah
anyway I'll even blew it up that's great
do a little repairs oh there's all my
stuff it is new so we're back here at
the tree farm I've made spots for nine
trees I think we have enough torches to
finish it but it should be good to go
anyways I put glass stoppers it above
every tree so the trees will stay small
and easy to harvest and so I should
probably explain a little bit about how
trees work in case you don't know
basically you need to be within a
certain range of the trees otherwise
they won't update and they won't grow I
think you need to be within sixty four
blocks correct me if I'm wrong of the
trees so that they'll grow so building
the tree farm in the middle of the
island is a good idea because I can be
off over there doing stuff in the trees
over here will still be growing if I
move to another Island I might make
another tree firm on the other Island
but yeah what else
you can grow trees underground if you
want as long as you have enough lighting
having these four torches is more than
enough light to make them grow and
you'll need it you'll need enough space
above each tree to at least I think 4
maybe 5 blocks is the minimum you need
these I have there's a seven blocks
above each tree so that's plenty of room
and they'll spread 2 blocks each so this
will be solid green when they're all
grown I'm hungry
come on come on give me some meat yes
finally um what else
trees won't grow as fast if if there's
not enough space and I'm just doing a
test here I'm pretty sure trees ignore
half-steps so when this tree grows I
think it's going to destroy this half
step that's what I want to check out and
I might I'm going to place one above a
tree to just as a experiment
it's happened to me before so yeah I
recommend building tree farms in your
world they're a great source of
renewable wood this one drew a little
weird normally they grow straight and
you should put a fence around your tree
farm I'll do that some other time and
it's good to have an entrance the place
to store tree saplings and oh boy and a
place to have
oh man I have to travel I have to hey I
go to stuff like I'm hurt oh so close
oh yeah alright that's the end of this
episode and thanks for watching