hello everyone this is etho and I have
another excellent episode for you today
playing Minecraft something that
everybody seems to be doing now is
building slime farms people have been
suggesting to me to do this for a long
time but it's never really interested me
because really what's the point but now
we need slimes to make sticky pistons
so there's actually a point to making a
slime farm so that's what I'm going to
be doing today
I've already started kind of I found the
location where I'm going to be building
it I did this it's a little bit
complicated
basically slimes have a very low chance
of spawning they can only spawn in
certain chunks as well and these are
decided randomly by your world seed so
they're kind of randomly placed all over
the place about every 10th chunk there
will be one chunk order slimes and spawn
and using simple online
I don't you call it online application
or whatever made by a guy named trunks I
have determined this is the best spot to
build my slime farm because there's
three chunks next to each other one here
here and one here
and my ex position is minus and 96 and
that is at 48 this point right here is
where the three chunks meet so that's
pretty good normally slime chunks or
just all on their own
occasionally they'll be two together but
if you can find three together that's
really good if you find forty other
that's very rare so I found three
together yeah so I'm just going to build
here I'm going to do a hole straight
down
pretty much yeah and dig straight down I
don't care what I know this is a bad
idea but that's just the way I do it and
I will see you in just a little bit if
I'm still alive and a lot of you are
going to say don't dig straight down but
not a complete idiot when I do it I can
see slightly where these two blocks meet
I can see a little bit of blue through a
crack which tells me there's no lava
below me but just to be safe since I'm
close to the lava level
I will alternate blocks towards the
bottom as well so slimes they only spawn
below level 16 which is where we're
we've passed now so this area here you
can actually spawn in I'm just going to
go all the way to bedrock nice cool
thing about building a slime farm is
you'll probably get redstone diamonds
gold all that good stuff and we hit
bedrock no lava that's good um yeah so
I'm gonna widen this out in the shape I
want it I brought my good friend with me
and it will be back oh yeah if you guys
are wondering what the f coordinate is
it's pretty obvious it's what direction
you're facing so I think zero is West
two is east and don't ask me what one in
three is because I always mix it up
okay I'll see you in a bit and we're
back so I just put ladders all the way
to the surface
okay so I need to get out of here again
the three chunks not the slimes then
spawn in meets there's one here there's
one here and there's one here so this is
the point where all three of them meet
right here this point right here and a
chunk is a 16 by 16 area so I need to
hollow out a 16 by 16 square diagonally
from here here and here if that makes
any sense
I think I forgot to say this but I'll
link the online application that trunks
made in the video description if you
want to find slimes in your world you
can use it it's not a mod it's just kind
of like a calculator type thing it
figures out the algorithm for you I
found some diamonds
one two not a huge score I found some
coal gold and I just found some more
iron so pretty good way of getting
resources build a slime farm I don't
know exactly how I'm going to build this
yet they'll probably copy a few things
from people and I might make up a few
things on my own whatever I think works
good first I want to make sure it works
so before I do too
before I do too much with this so I'm
just going to haul out these three
chunks and see if I can get slime
spawning in them
and what's the deal with these tunnels
well what I did is I just went all
around the perimeter of the three chunks
and I'm going to rig these with TNT all
around here and I will blow it all up
with the simple pull of a lever and only
one some more gold some of the resources
will get blown up by the TNT but I don't
really care more iron gas elope that's
the perimeter of the three chunks we
went in
oops like we went in here goes in all
around and then comes back out here so
I'll rig it with TNT and then I will be
back all right here we go so one my
favorite parts of Minecraft blowing
stuff up so it goes all the way around
that perimeter I dug which is uh
actually one block shy of the edge so
so like the chunk boundary is over here
but the perimeter is one block from that
edge if that makes sense
Jay make a lever and hopefully it'll go
all the way around without me having to
hit it a few times here real more
diamonds and I think it stopped ah
that's annoying okay one two three four
five let's try this again another
failure
I'll probably just mine out the rest of
this like what doesn't get blown up by
the TNT but the TNT is going to do most
of the work here
all the way around nice haha oh crap
he's gonna kill me so as you can see it
is working already and I hardly have any
of it hollowed out so I'll be back when
I get more done alright so there's lots
of blocks of mine out yet so I decided
to use TNT after all and I just cut out
these little slats here or these little
tunnels by doing this I was able to get
all the diamonds and stuff out of them
and gold or at least I think I did at 21
diamonds so far from building the slime
farm about two stacks of redstone ten
gold thirty iron so and pretty good so
far
let's set this off yeah I don't like the
new TNT very much
all right cool
I'll just my not the rest of this stuff
now there's not much left and then
should be pretty good
I should really light this place up -
yeah I'm actually amazed just how well
this works already it's not even done
not even close to done and I just went
up to the surface for a little bit and I
got tons of slimes here so it has a lot
of potential I think I'll kill them down
here although I kind of would like one
and would like a slime farm that
transports some of you anyway now one
thing I've noticed is that they don't
split if you kill them like with your
axe like if you kill a large one with in
your axe they won't split they'll just
die
and you won't get any slime balls from
them so I killed that big slime with my
arrows and it killed them and it killed
them ends he split into all these little
slimes so I'm guessing you need to you
either use arrows or a sword if you kill
them manually but I'm pretty sure they
split if they suffocate or stuff like
- so now it should be really easy for
you to visualize where the three chunks
are that spawn slimes clearly see this
three sixteen by sixteen squares and you
get to get to between zero and two slime
balls each slimy into small slimy guilt
the bigger ones don't drop any really
sure broadsword Jay so this isn't really
is it tilt excuse me this isn't really a
tutorial on how to make a slime farm
this is just to show you how I made mine
I can't really make it a tutorial on it
until I've at least made one otherwise I
would kind of be leading you blindly but
you should be able to pick up a few
things from this one thing that kind of
realized just now is that your slime
farm and your hostile mark your hostile
mob farm like with the creepers skeleton
zombies spiders the two are going to
interfere with each other
so if a slime spawns down here for
example that means that that's one less
mob spot for say a creeper to spawn in
your other hostile mob trap so ideally I
would like to be able to shut the slime
farm off and also the hostile mob farm
off so that I could choose between
spawning slimes or spawning the other
hostile mobs like spiders creepers
skeleton zombies is you know or to have
them both going at the same time
if you do stop the hostile other hostile
mobs from spawning then you will get
tons of slimes I'm pretty sure because
the only mob that can spawn then is
slimes even though it's very rare for
them to spawn if nothing else can spawn
you'll get lots of slimes so actually
I'm going to test I'm gonna go shut off
my hostile mob system which
unfortunately I can only do right now by
placing torches with pistons though you
could set up floodgates to spawn to
flood the spawning pads and then no mobs
would be able to spawn on the spawning
pads but just first test I want to I'll
just shut off with torches all right
here we are my normal hostile mob
spawning system and it's all lit up now
so this is where most of the hostile
mobs were spawning let's head over the
slime farm now and see what happens okay
so I'm definitely noticing a major
increase in the spawning rates of the
slime since I've lit up my hostile mob
system so that tells me one way to
increase spawns liming rates is to
decrease areas where creepers skeleton
spiders and zombies can spawn the other
way to increase slime spawning rates is
to increase the amount of area that
slimes can spawn inside your trap why is
this filled in here
where is the skillet so you might think
you have all the caves lit up around
your world but there's always always
more places you least expect and so
since this galton spawn there that's one
slime that can't spawn because that's
skeleton is using up that mob spot
anyway let's check out the slime farm so
I did recently switched it from peaceful
to hard
most of my tails are lit up there's just
a few places probably where hostile mobs
and spawn still so pretty much only mobs
that will spawn though our slimes down
here you can see one two three four five
six seven eight nine and 11 have spawned
Center since I switched it too hard
another thing I found out can't make
them split using a sword it just kills
them so you have to either use arrows
from a bow or just hit them with your
fists make them split this guys are
strong see he split
let's just use your bow or your fists if
you're killing the magic but they will
also split bicep feeding and possibly
from lab and stuff I don't know I have
to try that out as you can see you can
get slime balls really quick I already
have three stacks just from testing so
which is probably more than I need even
because I don't go through that many
sticky pistons and I'll probably get
another stack just from doing this well
anyway guys that's that's where I'm
going to end this episode
you got a bit done this is a big project
really to more despond yeah so I'll be
setting up like water canals and stuff
and spawning pads and I will probably be
making its multiple layers just to
increase the surface area for them to
spawn on I can go up to I think level 15
for the y coordinate or level 16 yeah
still not entirely sure how I'll do it
but I'll think about it
and I might do some of it off-camera but
anyway thank you for watching and I will
see you again next time