greetings all this is evil and I have a
very very special video for you today
this is something I've been working on
for a while and I'm sure my regular
viewers know what's going on here
basically I had this entire land mass in
front of me
rigged to blow up I have TNT place
throughout it yeah in these tunnels you
can see there's over 800 TNT placed here
and they're set to go off in a chain
reaction and even if the chain reaction
was to fail there's a fail-safe setup so
that it'll keep going keep on going so
just about all of this TNT should go off
just by activating one of them so this
this will be pretty cool oh all eight
hundred plus of the stand he was
handcrafted from gunpowder found from
these buddies of mine which are
everywhere in my world and it was all
placed manually - so no mcedit or in in
vedat used it all in this project so
this is should be pretty cool yeah of
course I could have achieved the same
effect by clearing the grass and placing
torches on this island but my viewers
voted that I blow it up this is a this
is to get my mob system working better
when I build it so where did you come
from so this is uh this is gonna be good
and we're gonna do this Hollywood style
so after the first explosion we're gonna
set off the same thing over and over
again from different angles kind of like
they do in in movies to make the the
explosion better you know they show the
same thing over and over from different
angles and anyway enough talking let's
get let's get to this so any last words
why did a quiet as always okay guys
enjoy
EPIK so there's a few blocks left here
but we got most of it alright let's
check this out let's set up from some
other angle here
well that's it guys I hope you enjoyed
this I had a lot of fun setting this up
and testing it and it turned out pretty
good I have to clean up all these loose
blocks yet and level of the ground here
make it all even then I need to fill it
in with water and let it freeze over so
anyway that's it for today thank you for
watching and if you could please put a
like to this video if you enjoyed it and
you can also favorite it my viewers
suggested I should try to get this video
viral when it when I make it so if you
want to help me out with doing that
please like favorite subscribe and I
very much appreciate it and also I want
to thank it say thank you to all my
subscribers this is kind of Maya 25k
special and also my 4 million view
special so thank you everybody
much appreciated having a lot of fun
playing Minecraft and you guys make it
better for me anyway that's all for
today this is etho take care