hey guys so I was off exploring looking
for a desert find the cactus and I
wasn't going to record it because I
didn't think anything interesting was
going to happen
but I guess I was wrong I'm pretty sure
the whole force will go up in flames
yeah and so oh and dangerous now oh
let's follow the fire let's see what
happens I think it might've stopped
oh whoa guess on my sword broke all
right I'm gonna move a sword
and then prepare to well for this trip I
think the fire is contained now this is
what started it and yeah so I've been
looking around for about 15 minutes for
a desert and I finally found one and
it's only this big and there was no
cactus on it
no cacti so I have to keep on looking
and different outlook I got away safely
just barely and I thought this was a
desert here but it's just a giant beach
kind of disappointed did find some clay
though and I actually am going to
harvest it I guess I have no room for it
just kidding um yeah there's a lot of
water in this world lots of trees lots
of rainforest I have not found much for
desert anywhere so I'm going to keep on
looking
alright there's a party going on down
there
three creepers I think Rose that if
there's a desert over here let's find us
a cactus
still don't see any cactus what the heck
salt it's weird it's all square
and what the heck there's no cactus
check that whatever ah
alright I guess I'll go oh is that clay
I think I see some clay and sand not
let's Santa okay back to searching you
finally found some took me about 20 to
30 minutes but I finally found some and
it's a pretty simple Oh
it looked like a small desert I guess it
keeps going back there all right cool
finally got tactus and we are 773 blocks
away from spawn all right so we got them
growing and multiplying and as you've
noticed this clay is officially in the
way so I think it's about time we
harvested it for real this time
no jokes you ready you ready gonna
harvest it now say goodbye to the clay
ah no I'm not [ __ ] I would never do
that
Gracchus click there's so much of it to
maybe the biggest thing I've ever found
of it I know how creepers going to come
now - and kill us and destroy all the
play whoo that was big total three and a
half stacks Wow
this one though I am going to leave
because it is fine where it is
and anyway so the storage room is coming
along I better deposit this clay before
it dies storage room is coming along
it's gonna take a lot of work to finish
them now the reason I wanted the cat
this cacti not really sure which one is
proper the cacti if you're referring to
more than one
down in our mob area a lot of people
have been asking me to make it tutorial
for this and main reason why I have it
is I've had a few issues with it
namely spiders were clogging up the
system and I finally figured out how to
solve that just need one block of slow
sand because apparently spiders can't
find slow sand well it seems like they
can kind of but normally that spider
there we've climbed up and gotten stuck
and then none of the mobs would be able
to get through and I kind of countered
that before by digging a 2x2 hole up in
the roof to kill the spiders by drowning
them and that worked too but then you
lose most of spiders
this is a bad idea so yeah one other
thing I'm trying and testing is putting
a slow sand around the pads to see if
it'll stop spiders from climbing up so
far it doesn't work if it's just on the
top block and get any speed both blocks
on the bottom and the top which is quite
a bit of it because these pads are big
it takes a lot of slow sand to do that
and I know it's called soul sand but I
hate calling it that so don't correct me
but yeah what I want to do with the
cactus is some of these pads are pretty
far away from our mob evader over here
so if they if it takes some more than
like 30 seconds yet within that elevator
range there's a good chance you're going
to de-spawn
so one way to prevent that from
happening is to damage the mobs and that
resets their idle counter down to zero
again giving them another 30 seconds or
whatever to reach the mob evader so my
idea is to somehow place cactus in these
streams so that they're forced to take
half a heart damage to hearts every so
often and that way all the mobs should
be able to reach the mob of a turret
without the spawning so I'm going to
work on figuring out how to do that the
best way and also determine if using
slow sand is is worthwhile for the pads
they keep the spiders in their place
and once I figure all that stuff out
then I'll make a tutorial on the whole
system okay but we're going to end the
episode here and thanks for watching and
I'll see you next time