[Music]
hello everyone
welcome welcome to my 100th lp
episode special
and also a little bit late but the 40k
subscriber special and i just saw i
passed 7 million views as well so very
cool
very happy about that and it's been
forever since i last released an lp
episode it seems
not really it's only been a few days but
a lot of people seem to think i have a
lot planned
in all honesty i don't i've been playing
canopy carnage
been trying to finish it before 1.8
comes out and that's
why i haven't made an lp i've just been
having a lot of fun playing
carnage i guess but i am basically done
that now
i got all the episodes recorded for it
which is nice
and now i am ready to start doing lps
again which is good
i have been playing my lp world a bit
though too
i've been working on the trivia game a
little bit
got a few new things done to it and i've
done some
stuff with the ice base with the mob
system
stuff like that i have not worked
on the rude goldberg machine since
i started that that one episode so maybe
today we'll spend a few minutes doing
that
since i don't really have anything
special planned and i'm not just saying
that i honestly don't
i had like some spaz stuff planned but
never got around to doing it so
since i should always say let you down a
little bit
i will instead try to do all the
different things you guys suggested i
should do for my
100th episode special
one of those was to make it an hour long
so oh i'll try i don't know
if i'll be able to make it a whole hour
but i'll record as long as i can before
i get
tired of it
another thing
well there's a few things
we'll try to do a few things today uh
one thing you guys wanted to see
was my statistics so how about we check
those out achieve let's do achievements
first
okay what have i done
the lie wheat sugar milk and eggs does
that mean i've done it
or haven't done it it's flashing i don't
know
getting wood taking inventory oh yeah
i've done that
time to mine getting an upgrade
a hot topic construct the furnace out of
eat stone
delicious fish okay i haven't done that
haven't done on a rail
acquire hardware oh i've done that a lot
let's see what else do we have time to
strike
monster hunter cow tipper
yeah i've done that a few times
fly a pig off a cliff i have not done
that yet
i never actually tried to do the
achievements when they came out so
never actually done some of these
didn't really care about the
achievements too much and still don't
moving on let's check out statistics
now keep in mind these may not be 100
accurate
but they are relatively accurate i would
assume
times played 329 wow
world's played 23
don't know what that's about oh
okay i think i might know what that's
about i've started a new world and
deleted it
several times for after
for certain things i won't go into
detail saves loaded 306
which is 329 minus 23 is 306.
multiplayer joins i think that's how
many times i've joined
smp maybe two
i don't play s and p much as you can
probably guess
i like s p because of the other player
interaction
being able to play with other people i
do not like smp
due to lag and
a lot of the things don't work that work
in single player
and there seems to always be politics on
servers about
you having to be a certain rank to build
certain things i don't like stuff like
that although in all honesty
joker has allowed me to play on his
server
and i've gotten invited to a few other
cool servers like the voxel box
and stuff like that which i may check
out
again sometime soon i haven't played s p
in a month or two at least games quitted
quit 276. so
i'm guessing if you minus 329 or 329
minus 276 equals the number of times
your game crashed maybe
minutes played 9 days 9.5
9.45 days i'm a little embarrassed about
that but keep in mind
sometimes i leave my game running when
i'm not there
distance walked 946 kilometers
it's pretty far each block counts as a
meter there's a thousand meters in a
kilometer
if you're from the us although you
should know that either way because it's
part of life distance swam
20 kilometers distance fallen
17 distance climb 10
distance flown 2.47 that's it
distant stove 15.94
so i've actually gone down in water
almost as much as i've
gone horizontally in it interesting
distance by minecart 14.66 distance by
boat
oh yeah take minecarts but 67.6
distance by pig oh that's sad
i should do that sometime almost a
hundred thousand jumps
three 300 seventy nine items dropped
damage dealt fifty three thousand and
eleven
i wonder if that counts like each of
these i'm assuming
represents a heart each of these numbers
but like say a mob has 2.5 hearts and
you do
five damage to it would that count the
full five
or would would it just count
what they were given because i could see
like tnt
racking that up pretty quick because i
think tnt can do
over 50 heart damage no problem
and same with damage taken fifteen
thousand eight forty nine
deaths fifty two that's quite a bit
quite a bit indeed mob kills
three thousand nine fifty two
player kills one must have been when i
was on s
p fish caught i have caught fish in the
past just not since
statistics came out okay
yeah some of these are have been
affected by my canopy carnage
playthrough as well especially the
blocks i'm assuming
uh let's see times crafted is on the
left
times used is the middle times mine's
right i'm not going to read all these
numbers you have eyes that's what
they're for
look at the numbers yourself cobblestone
seems to be the big winner here though
time's used thirty eight thousand two
fifty
that's probably mostly due to the mob
systems because
on chocolate island i used it and also i
space
i used a ton on the mob systems
wood trees sand okay
here's a good one times mind
gold 253 iron
2004 cole
uh i do mind call when i see it and it's
convenient when i'm splunking but
i don't like go for every single piece i
see just if i feel like it usually
so in my tv systems i have a lot of coal
laying around still
uh wood again these are affected by
canopy carnage and other things i've
done too i'm sure
lapis 124 yeah since my world is so old
like
i started this months and months ago we
we didn't have lapis blocks when i
started this world so
the majority of my chunks don't have
lapis in
so yeah i only get lapis if i mine
places farther away
sandstone i have used 2167
that's right that's because it's so
awesome
no blocks i don't use much rails i don't
use much
pistons i use a lot
often that's the thing though this
counts recycling as well because often
i'll put down a block then i'll mine it
put it down somewhere else pick it up
put it down pick it up
so it's counting the same one over and
over
don't know what that is but apparently i
have
mined it 178 times
and doesn't have a a tool tip for some
reason
this one as well i'm guessing this one
is like glitched out pistons maybe
23.
uh-huh
see and this is wrong it says zero for
times crafted i just made a ton of iron
in my lp world so that that's not
accurate for some reason
iron blocks i mean half slabs i've used
48.51
brick used 136
not in this world i think i've only
placed one in this world so far
and that's in the storage room tnt
1711. that sounds about right
yes indeed never
use bookshelves
the one in my storage room mossy
cobblestone
i got a lot of that stuff actually like
i think i'm up to about 15 stacks of it
in my lp
world from raiding dungeons
obsidian i tried to avoid torches
78.75 that's the thing with obsidian
though i might need to start using it
since endermen seem to be able to move
blocks
now i might have to convert my spawning
pads
into obsidian or something else that
they can't move
we'll see diamond 154
yes yes again i don't know how accurate
all this stuff is but there it is
redstone 797
gotten a little bit of netherrack
glowstone is fairly high
probably due to canopy carnage because
of the diamond trees are full of
glowstone i don't know
cool alright that's the blocks
items times depleted is on the left
times crafted middle times used is the
right
iron shovel used about 45 000 times
i usually never make diamond shovels
iron are good enough
uh times crafting
was this charcoal coal you can't craft
coal
what's what's the deal with that diamond
iron ingot 2623
i have a lot of iron gold
maybe that's something else we'll do
we'll take a run around the storage room
and look at my inventory
quickly redstone i have placed
4 900 times boats i've made 150
minecarts only three
cool cool cool
and that's it that's my statistics i
hope you've enjoyed that
let's go do something else
okay moving on another
one of the most requested things for my
100th
episode special was that i show my face
for the first time
because apparently everybody is
wondering what it looks like
well if people insist so much i guess
you will see it for the first time
nobody's ever seen it before i've been
hiding behind a mask so to speak so
here it goes are you ready
beautiful okay there you go there's my
face
i hope you enjoyed it hope i didn't
scare you too much
okay okay
maybe one other thing we could do is uh
check out what i've
changed to the trivia game i haven't
added much i think just one thing
since i last showed you i was having
trouble so
it's taking me a long time to build this
let's see we have the wires from the
buttons above coming down here
i still have to add the cheat prevention
to it i haven't fully
decided on what method i'm going to use
for that
obviously i want to use the simplest and
most effective but i don't know what
that is
[Music]
uh what i have added since last time is
the memory
array so this thing will hold
what questions or what answers are
correct so
three of these blocks will be glass and
one will be a solid one
which will represent the a b c d
the solid block will be the correct
answer one and if it's correct the power
can transfer
through the solid block to this wire on
the other side
and that is the wind detection
correct answer detection
but when i was building this i was
having a lot of trouble getting
these blocks to cycle properly i did do
the
five by three instead of the five by
four like i was going to
thanks to help from everybody especially
armitage
his video was very helpful i actually
watched it again
because i'm in trouble and it seems i
was just
activating the blocks in the wrong order
so thank you for your help buddy
and let's see i have
yeah so if i send a pulse to this wire
here it causes three things to happen
now
this wire here one it will send
power to
this cycle here which causes the
glowstone to go around a loop
and that just indicates what question we
are on
that's the only purpose so right now
it's showing we're on question number 10
and it also that wire also cycles this
thing which again keeps track of what
question we are on but for the sake of
the scoreboard memory
okay so let's see how does this work
again i think if i just hit this button
yeah so since we're on question 10
if we get the right answer we send power
to that and then
the light comes on for the one directly
below
and then the third thing this wire is
connected to
is the memory unit
so it cycles to through the questions so
that the answers keep changing like we
need them to
so you can see the sandstone is at the
top too here if we hit the button
it'll cycle around if i can figure out
how to get out of here
that's the thing i don't really like
about doing one hour thing one-hour
videos i kind of get half-assed at doing
stuff i hope you don't mind
today i'm a little bit more natural i
guess
not so worried about making mistakes in
this video
or for saying stupid things i guess okay
let's hit the button
you see those things cycled
oh can't go down that way
just a mess working with this redstone
uh yeah okay over here so you see they
moved
they're going down right up left down
right
up left and these pistons
all have a wire running across to
activate them
can't move
the wire comes down from there goes here
first one it goes to is this set of
pistons then it goes
over here one torch delay to
this lower set
continues going this way another one
torch delay to
the lower right set there and then
another one torch delay
to this upper right set here and that's
that's the order they're they're firing
at the pistons
right cool
all right awesome and that's all i've
done on the trivia game not much
i don't know if i had this all done here
this is this is the final
way i'm doing the the panel i'm pretty
sure i think it looks good
cool
so i did not fully figure out how i'm
doing the cheat prevention somebody sent
me a video a while ago i'll have to look
for it again where they were
they somehow had i don't remember
exactly how it worked because it was so
long ago i saw it but
he somehow a repeater and a sand block
with a
piston underneath
i'm not sure
yeah i don't know somehow he had it so
if the person kept hammering the buttons
the sand would stay up and the power
wouldn't transfer through i think he was
using a delay
probably
[Music]
i know that wasn't very informative so i
was playing around with something
similar to what he did
and i figured out an interesting
monostable
circuit i believe they're called or
pulse limiter i don't know
something that converts a long pulse
into a short pulse
which i found a little interesting so i
have repeater
with a sticky piston below the sandstone
block
and on the other side is another
repeater
so if you send a button press which is
usually a one second
power time
you can see this wire here is lighting
up
so if you had tnt next to it or
something it would probably get
activated
but you can see it's not enough time for
this torch to switch states
the pulse is too quick
and so this piston doesn't move if we
lengthen
the pulse time another torch delay
then you can see it's enough time for
the torch to switch states
which is cool um
and you can lengthen it even more if you
want
oh i don't know i thought that was kind
of interesting
i was trying to use it for cheat
prevention so if the person
keeps hammering a button
you can see the sticky piston above
there only activated once even though
i've been
pressing this button lots of times
let's see it stays
i don't know something i was playing
with i don't know if it's useful
for anything actually
actually since i'm trying to kill time a
bit today
maybe i'll show you a useless thing i
made the other day
an rs door latch that uses sand
for its switching mechanism it's very
large
and quite sloppy but for some reason i
like it so i'll show it to you
if you press this button if you activate
this piston
it's a sticky piston but the sand does
not stick to it when
it retracts so it falls down
powered repeater sends a signal through
to the other side
door opens if you hit it again
the state stays the same
and then on top we have another repeater
or another piston sticky piston
with the repeater set to two
if you hit it
hit it again this state stays the same
so it's an rs nor latch
kind of fun kind of weird
so another thing that was very highly
requested for
my hundredth special is a tour of my
world
there's really not a lot to see to be
honest but
maybe i'll give you a basic tour with
commentary
no fancy musical video for you or
anything like that
this is my front yard it's very
very messy that needs to be burnt down
yet
those tubes need to be removed
i have a bad habit of changing my mind
about things and nothing ever gets
done unfortunately
my goal is to eventually make this place
pretty though and it still is
this is the clay get to know it well
welcome to chocolate island that's what
i call this island here because
all the grass has been removed almost
using your mum so that the passive mob
system would work better
and it did help a lot with 1.8
i've heard someone said mobs
passive mobs will spawn on soil as well
i don't know if it's true but if it is
true i will replant the grass here
probably
because in all honesty i'm gonna use the
mob system at the ice base instead
this one's just for
[Music]
just for the retro feel
and this here is the storage room this
is one of the first
buildings i built in my lp series it's
probably the largest and
as far as looks go it's one of my
favorites
it's very nice lots and lots of
different blocks in here different types
of blocks
very strange storage
systems pretty basic whatever you see
above the chest
is what's in the chest so you can spot
what items are in the chest from a
distance
and we also have dispensers so if you
need one of one item
for example let's say i need a bed
empty okay let's say i need
a slime ball you get one slime ball or
you can
pick them out as you choose very simple
some of these have additional storage
below here these are chests
cool cool
yeah this building has changed a lot
over time
patches keep messing things up and i
keep fixing them
this in here is supposed to be the
control room which
doesn't really control anything anymore
or at the time anyway there's furnaces
in here
also have a nice view of the mob evader
for the mob
system below which i guess is off right
now
i should turn it on yeah
and we have water columns in each of
these corners for an abstract look
but they also have a purpose to them too
because
they will take you downstairs in places
like here
yep so this is downstairs
a very unpolished part of my house
again this is the control room
in here is a suicide booth which you can
use to
get to the ice base quickly if
if that's the last place you slept
another view of the mobs is
the mob evader here this is the item
despawn timer
which plays that zelda tune whenever
it's time to pick up items there it goes
perfect timing
cool we got stairs here
uh we have an old mob system here which
has been retired
and also an old minecart setup that's
been retired
watch older episodes if you want to know
more about these
and here's the motivator again
okay where what else do we have
secret project here not many people
reacted well to that it's okay i can
take it
can't win them all
to be fair though i didn't reveal it
very well
and the other thing is it's an idea i
had about nine months ago
back when i was a lot less experienced
in this game
and since then i've come up with better
ideas so
people weren't too impressed with that
idea
and this is eats road let's go for a
ride i suppose
again i am having trouble with my eats
roads oh yeah
this is the quick kit
which i still never set up
the idea is you press a button and all
the items you need to re
you need for recovering your items will
be given to you
coolio okay yeah let's go for right on
the eats road it's been a while
since i last did that i am having
trouble with it still
that's why i still haven't released a
tutorial for it
as always it seems to have trouble
this is how you load boats into it
the problem i have is it's like if i
go away from here and come back
sometimes the boats just
are gone i don't know what happens to
them they just disappear all the time
and i don't know why
so let's go for a ride
this leaf area was all built before
oh yeah let's player tuned
cave story theme
yeah all that leaf stuff was done before
you were able to
collect leaves with shears oh okay
these boats are still in place i don't
know
it seems weird there's a lot of boats
there actually
there's like 10 votes there
maybe they're getting released
hmm oh i should have saved one
oh well this thing is
a boat elevator to the surface
people said i should call it the etho
vader i never did release a tutorial for
it because
it also has a serious flaw
maybe i'll load a boat into it to show
you
all right that's how you load it boot
comes up here
goes to the left you hop in and the
pressure plate
gets activated and you float to the
surface
there's probably going to be a boat up
here
yep
and then if you step on this pressure
plate it drops down
and you are free to jump down as well
safely
yeah this is a problem with this see the
boats there it's being held in place by
the trap door
by exit and then
enter there goes
so that's why i never released a
tutorial for this you're better to use
pistons
to hold the boat down instead of
trapdoors
and here is further plan for the eats
road which
goes
down
but i haven't done much with that
okay
what else what else maybe we'll go up
oh yeah over here
is another mob system this was done for
a tutorial the original mob system
tutorial
this is by general spaz's old house
and it doesn't work very good
hopefully i have a bed near here
hopefully
yeah here we go the heck
wait a minute wait a minute wait a
minute
okay seriously i did not remember
rebuilding this house
where did it come from or did it just
not fully blow up
okay just did not fully blow up i see
there's the huge huge hole
uh maybe i'll skip today here wow let's
go check out the greenhouse
this is a greenhouse i made for
harvesting
flowers in that flowers and seeds
this was before people showed me
the dark room exploit the smurf
as static calls it
so basically i showed the tutorial for
this and then
smurf caught on as the popular one
yeah this thing here is what i called
the greenhouse i had a tutorial on this
if you want to
know more about it basically it's used
for
harvesting flowers and seeds from tall
grass
using bone meal
and you place water here and any tall
grass
on the grass gets harvested above and
below
but shortly after i released the
tutorial for this people figured out the
dark room trick
so this became obsolete basically
okay back to the storage room here this
extends over to this area here
on the left we have a cactus farm
chest for holding the cactus cacti
furnaces on the left and right for
making
green dyes
pretty cool we can go up here
spiral water staircase just for fun
and there it is the auto harvesting
cactus farm
like many you've seen they all fall off
and get sucked to
the center there and then end up below
on the other side we have a tree farm
and i s i'm still really happy with this
tree farm design it works really well
this is where basically all the wood in
my lp world comes from
it's intended you use bone meal
and usually it requires three stacks of
bone meal to grow
all these trees
takes a little bit of time
for my new ice space i plan on making
all the farms
tree farm tattus farm sugarcane farm
mushroom farm pumpkin farm watermelon
farm
etc etc and
redesigning everything for the fun of it
but yeah this is definitely damn up
and i'm out of fertilizer so i won't
show it in action but basically
hit the dispenser you get an axe and
then you
go all around this loop
harvest all the wood then get stuff
above you
leaves will die the saplings fall in the
water below
and then they end up
over here and then you can put them in a
chest
it's also a water staircase
so we have a chest for fertilizer which
is empty
one for saplings furnaces here for
making
charcoal uh
there's a storage chest here for any
extra wood we get and there's a storage
chest here
for charcoal that we produce here
so very fun cool stuff
and you can hop through you can hop
between the two farms
through this walkway here up in the sky
then on the right here i never made a
proper
way of getting to the top but there's
kind of like a little
garden up here dark green wool for fake
grass since i can't have real grass
little pool
there's a bridge going across the two
farms and a little
water stream here which is way up in the
air
glass below
cool stuff i actually really like this
bridge
even though it's simple and again over
here we have
a nice little garden area with a tree
canopy above
again this was done before we could
control
leaves as well as we can now i could
actually put some more
over here to cover up all these logs
look better
and there is all the original mob system
stuff
which i experiment with quite a bit
actually i've redone it a few times too
at top of the storage room
alright back in the storage room here if
we continue straight
we have these sliding doors here
which take you outside underneath the
two farms
the plan was to make this kind of a
garden area as well but i never
got around to it yet got a creeper face
over there
that was done before we could uh place
leaf blocks
ah but over here this is my pride and
joy
this is my house this is where i sleep
spend most of my time it's got a light
it's even got a window
yeah you can look through it it's very
nice good view
pride and joy right there
okay
then we can go down here
to our hostile mob system
so it looks like this thing has
two major features there's a spider
spawning option flip that lever all
these half slabs come up which prevents
spiders from spawning and then you can
pull them down again
and there's also a lighting switch
turn it on or off go to easy
mobs start spawning pretty quick
very nice very nice
and again there's a tutorial on i'm not
going out there
there's a tutorial on the system if you
want more information
i think i called it hostile mob system
revised or something
it's not exactly like this but similar
to up here is the lighting
room with all the wiring and stuff
lava died in here once
there we go
and this tour is mainly intended for new
people new subscribers who have not seen
all these parts of my world my
subscriber count has been growing
rapidly
actually
so thank you everyone who has subscribed
recently
and who has subscribed for all this time
especially
over here is the surface elevator
pistons take you right up to the surface
again
yeah that's that's about it can't think
of anything else
maybe we will go to the ice base now
oh i guess i forgot a few things uh
mainly in the front here
this is my abandoned mine shaft
one of the first things i made
in this world which i don't use anymore
because we have the tornado below here
which replaced it uh you can drop down
like this
takes you to a little room i hollowed
out doesn't really serve
much purpose anymore
uh down below here is my
nether portal and my instant nether
just walk through you're in the nether
very nice
and i'm not allowed through that portal
there
um what else what else
that's about it got a minecart here this
takes you up the tornado
[Music]
pretty simple
just like that
[Music]
this sign prevents water from wrecking
rails okay
i was wondering what that was
yeah okay so what else what else
i suppose we got the cannon back there
we could go to
gonna make a boat
i got a lot of junky stuff around this
world that i don't really use anymore
so i don't know if it's worth showing oh
i guess there's a slime farm yet
hmm lots of stuff really
over here is general spazzes tower and
some experiments which i've never
cleaned up
i recorded a few tutorials over here
oh yeah our smart piston loop i wonder
if that's still set up
i made all this stuff when the pistons
came out
powered powered
oh
um oh yeah
just like the day i made it okay
got the rgb machine over there i'll
probably end the episode over there
again i didn't work on it at all yet
you know me i like to put stuff off and
forget about it
but i do intend on completing it
eventually just not today
gotta be in the right mood to work on it
okay this is the 360 cannon
pretty sure it still works i haven't
played with in a while
actually i have some tnt on me oh i put
it down
darn i had some tnt on me
wiring for it
good stuff
and i have another one of these in
another but i don't think it's working
at the moment
and i'm pretty sure i wrecked something
on it
so i won't bother showing you that
let's head down to the slime farm
down here is the slime farm which i
still never finished
it had a control for turning spawning on
or off here
quite excessive really
but yeah like many things unfinished
common problem i am
making a much bigger effort now to
finish projects i start
like the trivia game i definitely am not
buggering out on that like i
tend to do this a really bad habit i
have i enjoy starting projects i just
have a hard time devoting the time
needed to
complete them but
putting forth a bigger effort now
let's see what else what else
uh let's head over there i guess
okay we're over here by the trivia game
again
just wanted to show people what this was
in case you're wondering
uh this is the original location for
the donor cannons this is where i
started
but then i realized i needed a lot more
space
uh today i think i'm at
at least 60 donors and about two
thousand dollars
so again thank you everyone that's
contributed
in all honesty it did help me put out
more videos
really encouraged me
and these cannons blew up can't remember
if i ever checked out these caves
yeah i did okay cool
also near the trivia game are these
other canons here i made one for each
donor at the time
and uh when you launched them they made
like a little firework show it's pretty
cool
but the 1.6 patch killed them all so
they don't work anymore unfortunately
and finally our world tour takes us to
the ice base
this is where a lot of the future
projects are going to be
i got lots of plans for here
we have emp units this is definitely the
most complicated part of my world
there's so much wiring and pistons and
stuff like that
in such a small area
but it's getting to the point now where
i can work on finishing up
and actually building onto this
structure
which i'm looking forward to i'm i
really want to start
building farms and stuff and
stuff that looks nice instead of working
on mob stuff all the time
not that mob stuff isn't fun
and yeah you can see i've actually added
a second tower now
still hasn't been made pretty yet though
these towers are for the hostile mob
system the ones i'm climbing right now
but then we also have the passive mob
system over here
which needs to be adjusted yet
but currently functions
[Music]
pretty cool pretty cool
so much work has gone into this little
area already
one thing we need to do soon is the item
collection
system here needs to be finished
and we need to do the tubing for the
hostile stuff but i might do that off
camera
since we've seen it a million times but
yeah let's check it out
here we go i
am quite happy with it
hopefully it gets going here
actually i should check to make sure i
don't have any lights on in it
now they're probably off
i think i have spiders off at the moment
though so it's a little bit slower
but yeah it works really well
with two towers i can make a stack of
tnt
in every every 10 or 15 minutes now
like i just get so many drops
yeah i got some tnt here
it's so cool so i will need to adjust it
though when endermen come out
because apparently they can move
cobblestone
we'll have to figure out what to do with
that
but overall it's working very well
yeah so after about five minutes this is
how many items are on the ground
it's actually enough to lag my game
quite a bit while recording
[Applause]
that's one sided
well that's the other side what do we
get
just about two stacks of gunpowder every
five minutes two stacks
two and a half stacks of feathers one
got a stack of oh two stacks of arrows
and about two stacks of bones that's
like every five minutes at this rate
but we have not reached max potential
yet it can still be sped up
about a time and a half to two times
that speed
so i may build the third tower yet i'm
not sure
just about all the caves are lit up so
in total i need about 1500 spawning
spaces for the mobs to reach max
potential
it seems roughly
well that about concludes the world tour
i hope you guys enjoyed it
if you've been a long time subscriber
maybe it brought back some memories
of my older videos some of our older
projects
and if you're a new subscriber that will
give you a little bit of background of
some of the stuff
i've worked on i've been getting lots of
new subscribers it's great
and that's that's about it for today
i really haven't built a whole lot of
stuff i guess in this world
maybe in the future i'll build stuff
more often i don't know
i tend to do a lot of research and
experiments
it's more of the type of thing i enjoy
doing in minecraft i'm not like
i'm going to build a castle today and
actually do it
and since i play legit i don't really
have resources to do that kind of thing
all the time
yeah really enjoying minecraft still
love the game thanks the notch for
making it
much appreciated uh
i want to say a big thank you to all my
viewers
all my subscribers thank you for liking
my videos leaving comments
telling your friends much appreciated
helps me out a lot
uh yeah
really looking forward to the 1.8 patch
i think it's supposed to come out on
monday
i've seen a few videos of it looks great
randomly generated stuff is looking
pretty cool the new biomes
strongholds villages that kind of stuff
most of that won't work in my world
unless i go very far which i might do
but then there's other great features
about the 1.8 patch
like there's new blocks
i'm really glad they added dashing
you have no idea from what i've seen
people
can pretty much run around all the time
as long as they have food
which is what i was hoping for
you know something simple like that will
just save me so much time playing
minecraft i'll be able to get a lot more
done
so i'm happy about that
so i'm really looking forward to the
creative mode that's going to be added
in 1.8 as well
it's going to be very handy for me
especially like for making tutorials and
stuff
they'll save so much time being able to
spawn in blocks and
being able to fly around it's going to
be great
yeah another thing i'm thinking maybe
getting into soon is making adventure
maps
i really enjoyed canopy carnage by vex
i'll probably play the legendary series
as well if it still works in 1.8
but that's kind of the type of map i
would like to make
very challenging maps with like a lot of
mechanical
devices in got some pretty good ideas in
store if i do it
so that might be in the future
but yeah so i also want to give a
special
shout out special thank you to my
youtube buddies
of course there's dot cam 77 most of you
know him
static joker armitage
uh branny beast
e he had his army invade me the other
day
was awesome uh co-stars helped me out a
lot
and ralph david
david i don't i feel i said his name
wrong david
i think he's it's david he's got a
swedish accent
um yeah thank you everybody
for being so nice unfortunately
the rgb machine has not
been added to yet i've wanted to i just
haven't
gotten to it been busy doing other stuff
in lp
and it's difficult to work on this and
make episodes constantly
but maybe sometime soon we'll
focus an episode or two building this
and then it'll actually get done
but for today we'll see it in action
again if i can remember
where the switch is i don't think i had
a switch actually
uh
let's make a switch
piggy
there we go
works good
any time now
i think i messed it up
yep messed up oh well sorry about that
i'll have to uh
this thing here is not very reliable i i
might have to remove it
anyway that's it for today thank you for
watching i will see you guys again next
time
oh