Wow
wasn't that awesome guys that was very
cool I have an intro now finally took a
while but I got one big thank you to L
the Hedgehog who made that for me it's a
very nice intro I like that it's short
and I didn't even have to do anything I
just was checking my PM's one day I saw
a message from him and he's like hey hey
II thought I was bored today so I made
you an intro you can download it here
use it if you want doesn't get much
better than that so I liked it I'm using
it hope you guys like it too so thank
you Elda Hedgehog for that hey everyone
thanks for joining me this is Ethel and
we're here at my alpha base I don't know
if I showed you this before that I got
quite a bit done on my hostile mob
system now mainly I just added a killing
thing for the tall mobs and I have a
junction here so they go down here swim
up then to the right and then the lava
kills them without destroying their
drops and the drops fall down here
there's a trapdoor which I can use to
turn them on or off the loot if it's
open the loop continues on its merry way
to another trapdoor this is the main
trapdoor that turns hostile mob drops on
or off at the main collection area
and it's working pretty good I'll have a
wire running here to control this
Junction if it switched the mobs through
this way and I was playing around with
this trap door idea apparently it
doesn't work very good because quite
often the moths will just go right by it
like like you just saw there so it's
kind of like a semi Junction not
reliable anyway willing to switch the
peaceful real quick cuz they got mobs
all over my roof yeah so things are
going well in Minecraft I got the new
EMP design so this one is obsolete now
I'm really happy with the new one and
there's a Skelton anybody I'm getting
out of here what else is new oh yeah I
did a little bit of work around here
underneath the floor I just did a bit of
sandstone here we got a nice viewing
area for the mobs going up the mob
evader I'll probably add glowstone in
the back there so you can see it better
and actually I brought some glowstone
with me that I wanted to put right here
I'm gonna shut this off temporarily get
rid of this
and glowstone nice go for underground
stuff I love using sandstone because
it's such a bright block okay there so I
can swim up these things to get back to
the control room kind of a cheat bladder
but I like that method and I added
finally a proper access room to my
despawn timer for my collection area you
know that thing that plays is ltitude
I got the loop and yeah you know what's
down there I don't want to go down there
again yeah I got a storage chest here
and some crafting tables and a suicide
booth haha why a suicide booth well this
is kind of a because of Futurama I love
I love that joke with the suicide noose
I want I was gonna make like a glass
booth like a telephone booth like they
had in Futurama but yeah this works too
so the idea is before you go in it you
place your items in the chest like that
so that they'll be waiting for you when
you come back you step on the pressure
plate which causes this piston here to
go up or this a block to go up by a
piston and then this block here comes
down and crushes you so I'll see you on
the other side oh you've got to be
kidding me
how did it creeper get in here oh that
sucks I don't want to see the damage
ah
we'll be right back
okay I'm scared to look glass block
destroyed creepers still there yeah
we're gonna be doing this on peaceful
little stone they get destroyed that's
good that one's still there and the
water is flowing here I don't think I
had any wiring here so that's good hmm I
think I got away pretty good there
actually
so I'm gonna try fix the damage and then
I'll be back okay so I've been repairing
the damage it wasn't that the suicide
booth still works the wiring didn't get
damaged which is good and nothing in
here got destroyed the chest didn't get
destroyed so there is this a few blocks
missing no no the glowstone got
destroyed which is good and since the
Mafia got blown to bits I decided I
would just redo it now that make it look
nice this little section so I got
glowstone in the back now and sandstone
all around to brighten it up and now I'm
just gonna fill it in with water just
gonna be a little hard to do with
because it's gonna spill out all over
the place as I'm doing this so I'm gonna
do the back side first and work my way
up it's actually staying in so that's
good a little bit higher and I think I
need one more right there okay now I go
to close side any one right there
possibly one there I'll put one just to
be sure it's a little bit hard to see
any one there one there okay now it's
gonna start spilling out or not there we
go
I drilled this hole here so when it go
all over the place there and one there
should be pretty close to done one there
and here I believe I just need one more
where the alternating sign is there's a
sign yeah hollow here good that should
be it I can put glass here and we have a
nice little view now excellent although
it's pretty dark but it's it looks
better than it did before
okay so now we'll do the suicide booth
test again that mess is all cleaned up
so like I was saying before put your
items in this chest
we don't any surprises again just like
that and what the heck it is sort of
creeper
oh okay so suicide booth the point of
this you go in it and you die force
can't get out of it once watching why
would you do that well this is what I'm
using to get from my starter base to my
new ice base because this is where I
slept so this is where my spawn point is
and so I instantly get transported here
instead of having to walk over a
thousand blocks so that's very handy and
when I get here I have all my items in
this chest waiting for me if I need to
get back I can use the nether portals
or in one step through the nether
going to get
and that takes me to my fake nether this
is man-made as a trick and just because
it's cool and then we walk through this
portal and we're down here I need to set
up some easy way to call my cart here
from the tornado because right now it's
the only way to get it down is to step
on this pressure plate and then wait for
it gotta move these out of here sometime
there it is go up the tornado woohoo
and we're back at our alpha base so that
works pretty good for getting getting
around I like it a lot
I was thinking of laying down a huge
minecart track but this seems like a
good way of doing it for now anyway I
know what the problem is I have my
junctions which I'm going to the top of
my roof instead of dying and I think
that's where that ended up
anyway so then we can come down here get
our items again and we're good to go
at our alpha base or if we want to go
back to her ice base we just get very
slow
yeah and here we go and we're back so I
was playing around with glowstone you
guys had glowstone melted ice a few
people said it doesn't so I figured I
better try it myself just to be sure and
you can see with it one block off the
ice it melts one two three squares away
from it
so that kind of sucks redstone torches
don't seem to and
I think last episode I mentioned I was
going to get rid all the grass on this
island and I seems to be you guys want
me to blow up the island is what the
common common desire seems to be so I'll
leave it up to you guys just to be sure
I don't mind blowing it up that sounds
like a fun project I don't have enough
TNT to do it now but I think I I think
it is doable
I would only blow it up to that barrier
there and I've gotten pretty good at
placing the charges so it blows
everything up without making a huge mess
so it's definitely doable if I do blow
up this island I'm gonna do it all at
once and record it because I think
that's that's the way you would have to
do it and there'd probably be a few
hundred TNT involved and it would be
pretty cool well guys it seems I'm gonna
have to redo all this at the end which
is okay I don't mind redoing it I'd
rather get it right there's a few
reasons why I need to redo it mainly
I've redesigned the EMP units so if you
saw my EMP tutorial that's what I'm
planning on doing that design instead of
what I have here I realized I'm gonna
have to get rid of a lot of this ice
here or possibly all of it since
glowstone melts ice I need some form of
lighting so I can't have this all ice
because it's gonna melt and the other
reason is you guys have said that you
don't really like the sandstone because
it clashes with the ice color and
not the size color but this is a snowy
biome and it doesn't really match and
that makes sense to me because I believe
this yellow here is the negative color
of this blue so on the light spectrum or
whatever I think these two are opposites
so that probably explains why it clashes
and also this is a snowy biome and when
you're in snowy biomes you don't really
think of sand or sandstone that's kind
of kind of like a warm tropical area
type thing so yeah I'll probably not use
sandstone I think my material of choice
is going to actually be snow snow blocks
look pretty cool they're bright like
sandstone so I think they're a good
substitute and they're fairly easy to
collect they're just a little bit of a
pain to deal with because they turn into
snowballs when you destroy them but yeah
I think that's what I'm gonna do so I'm
gonna work on switching this over to the
new style of EMP units and also the new
style of blocks and went ahead and
ripped out the first EMP unit here and
I'm gonna try build the new model out of
snow or see how it looks
oops
it'll be careful not to misplace blocks
not that it's a huge deal it's this
inconvenient yeah do like that and
leavers glass blocks actually I'll
probably put fences on naval track glass
first and then we'll do barrier still
have the tutorial fresh in mind because
I recorded that today like this
I would like to use ice box and set
glass but they will melt so I chant and
gonna have snow up here something like
this but wall here
it looks pretty cool I think I will have
to get rid of this ice here this will be
snow actually I figured out if I'm using
glowstone in the plus sign method I also
have to get rid of three more blocks
here something like that so leave quite
a bit of snow it looks pretty good and I
instead of ice here I might use that
light blue wool
I think that'll look pretty good in my
snowy biome and I may also put snow up
along like this yeah I think that's what
I'm gonna do let me know what you guys
think yeah I think that's pretty sharp
looking that's what I'm gonna do let me
know if you disagree though and you have
other suggestions if you have them
otherwise I believe this is what I'll be
doing because I like how that looks okay
I probably won't be doing half slabs
here someone H ans I AG and sahi or
something sent me a pretty good video on
a better way of doing this so be nicely
hidden if it works and I'll do that next
episode maybe but for now this is it for
today thank you for watching as always I
think this is gonna look good when it's
done and most importantly it's gonna
function well it's what I want
but thank you for watching see you next
time