hey everyone this is your buddy etho
here I've been doing a little bit of
work on our control room got vertical
wiring running all the way up now and I
think all these torches are lighting my
game warm but I'm not sure and this side
too
i was like building and I realized that
was gained a little bit carried away
building stuff without you guys so I had
to stop and start recording because I
was working on the spider killing thing
but it's pretty simple I'll explain it
to you here got the separator right over
here the stream of water that pushes
them into this chamber and then they
swim up and it's kind of dark down here
it's the the soil part here is just a
temporary killing thing I set up for the
tall mobs and absolutely swim up here
this is the thing to collect there drops
so the drops fall in here they get sent
to the stream here they fall one block
and they run along the door top here
they keep going around the bend and
through our minecart deep it's actually
a lot bigger than I was expecting it to
be there's such a simple thing but yeah
I wanted to show you guys it before that
too far ahead so it's gonna be even
harder to see things once it's all
closed up here oh ouch
so we're gonna finish this up here we've
got we got it set to peaceful just
because we're working on the mob system
this world is so lady now I think all
those torches had a big impact on my
framerate
okay so we are going to make them go
over and we need them to swim up I think
at least one block every time I jump
down major leg not quite sure why
[Music]
all right so we got to get the water
onto the glass here and we'll have this
covered I think
[Music]
I guess we want gonna put two sides one
on both sides and we can place water
here just making this up as I go along
here okay will you push the here then
they have to swim up so we'll fill this
with water - that'll drown
I should have built the infinite water
pool up there I suppose
yeah that'll work
[Music]
let's see yeah how to do this
and outworked so there you're gonna get
pushed to this corner here actually you
know what I'm just put a block here I'm
going to try to hook up some lava here
to kill him faster or just about at the
next level
everything he builds in minecraft seems
to take up so much space and we're gonna
figure something out with lava here okay
so from two of these sites we will be
able to take damage not that one not
that one that one and that one so I need
to place lava
[Applause]
on this side right
yeah I think either this side or this
side will work so we're actually changes
water we want it diagonals Ord this
corner and so it is now that's good
guys probably can't see very well and
then we'll place the ladder here and
that's working
and I'm going to test it up that's what
I want all right we're ready for a test
run here I think I'm gonna go make it
day and then we will check it out all
right we finally got some spiders and
waiting forever like 15 minutes for a
spider I changed that we now have five
lava blocks
needs to work pretty good
I'm happy with that
well if this door is open spring falls
now it's supposed to run so long
top runs to our our main collection
point here I'm quite happy with it so
another thing we're gonna look at today
a lot of you have been wondering about
with farms am I going to build a squid
farm I actually started kind of working
on one like two weeks ago it's
incredibly simple to do although this
biome I'm in is probably the worst one
for collecting squid and stuff because
there's so much water all around the
island if you can believe it I'm gonna
get some more soil and then I'll show
you what I've been doing we got some in
here don't may be in here
yeah so to make a squid farm you have to
take advantage of one of their
characteristics that they they can't
swim up so they'll spawn randomly
somewhere within these thousands and
thousands of water blocks they'll choose
one by random and then they'll sink to
the bottom of the ocean and they'll swim
around and they'll keep getting lower
and lower and they'll keep traveling
towards the lowest spot in the ocean
haha it's probably pretty hard to see
but basically there's thousands of water
blocks but for like this section here
like probably at least thirty bucks all
around me and he Swift that spot in that
space will end up right here give it
enough time because it keeps swimming
lower and lower and it all kind of
funnels down to this point here and then
I've cut a hole in here and they will
fall into this room and so once you do
that you can build water we'd only need
one block space so you can
dig like water channels that had one
block wide and then set up water streams
to push them through and keep doing that
and make like a central area for them
all to collect and you just connect all
the the water channels together so like
I need to make a lot of those collection
points because even though that covers a
large area there's so much water all
around so I probably need to make
probably 10 collection points and that
all travel to the center of my base and
they'll bring the squid somewhere
underground you will need to do a bit of
terraforming probably like if you have
any holes in your in your floor you need
to level them out otherwise squid can
fall into those and then they won't end
up into your squid farm and so here's an
example I think we have squid here still
yep they've collected to this little
point here there's a little spot here
this guy has been in here for a few days
now but what I would do is I would just
fill this in fill it all in so that if
he spawns in this area here
decrease the number of collection areas
we need to make we can do that and then
it'll more likely end up over here and
then we can make a collection point here
[Applause]
and yeah it's pretty simple definitely
possible it's a lot easier if you're in
a different biome but not impossible and
yeah and now we have a collection point
here and then you would just branch that
towards the center the problem is I've
tried like making water stairs for squid
to get pushed up they don't seem to want
to go upstairs even if they're being
pushed by water so they're gonna end up
somewhere below ground not a big deal if
you want to somehow get them above
ground you will need to use minecarts
you can put squid in microts and make
some system to bring them up but you
know it's really up to you I probably
won't be doing that okay
so if it wasn't clear what I meant by
that don't worry I will be setting up a
squid farm of what I have there wasn't
really anything and it's just a hole in
the ground to test to see if they would
all go into the collection point and
they did in a test I did and so probably
in a few episodes I'll show it to you
when it's all done won't take long to do
but it is a low efficiency
squit farm plan because obviously
there's so much water around here the
only way to make a high-efficiency Swit
farm is to have only like less than 100
water blocks you would want but yeah
it'll work low efficiency but after
about a minute or two of swimming around
all the switch should go into a central
collection point and then you just built
them wherever you need them like I'll
probably need one around there probably
one around here here here here all the
way around and then terraform it so
that's it works but we are out of time
guys if you guys don't like watching me
build stuff just let me know and I'll go
back to showing you I'm not sure if my
episodes have been as interesting lately
but I like to try different things and
[Music]
well we did get one thing done anyway
I'm pretty happy with this thing and
yeah thanks for watching I'll see you
guys later