[Music]
what's up everyone this is etho
and in today's episode of minecraft we
are going to be focusing on trying to
finish up
our passive mob system uh
today we're going to be working on the
mob sorting mostly
there's been a few changes since uh last
episode i got this
ceiling section kind of planned out a
little bit better now
let's go up there mob system still
working great i haven't suffered the
mob's not spawning glitch yet so i'm
hoping i never will
and these are just a little
this is where we're going to connect
with our emp units at all these plus
signs we have
and the big one over here is for the
spiders
uh right now the mobs are just falling
down this
soil section here and hitting the ground
and dying
collectively all the other in the middle
up here i think the only change i've
made since last episode is i
did end up lowering the stream here
one block because the mobs were kind of
jumping out of it
back into these side ones which was
slowing them down just a little bit
so it should work a little bit better
like that which is good
faster moving mobs is more efficient
system
i still haven't had the walls in here
um that's because uh last episode
hasn't gone out yet i was rushing to
finish it
yesterday and i think it was like 2 30
a.m or something crazy
by the time i got it done and when it
was done
i saw my internet wasn't working so i
wasn't able to put it out anyway
after after i kind of rushed through it
which sucked so i don't know what you
guys think
about the change that changes i've made
yet if i've gotten flame
for the sandstone or what people want me
to use for the side walls
i have no idea so we're gonna
wait on finishing that part up uh
yeah so what we need to do with all
these emp units
going to go up here this is our glass
tubing and we got to bring it all the
way up to the top there
and the mops will fall down these tubes
these glass tubes
and i'm hoping uh they look kind of cool
when they're all done too
kind of crazy crazy looking i hope
okay so they come up here
i need to run them all up here or at
least all the ones we're working on
[Music]
today
a little bit laggy that ceiling won't be
completely flat like it is right now
in the end but uh one thing at a time
so that's what the tubes are gonna look
like there will be a back wall
all around here so it's not like you're
going to be looking at sky
lighting in here i still haven't figured
that out i'm
almost thinking if i put lighting here
it won't melt the ice below from what
i've
tried
and we are playing on peaceful today
because that's what i feel like playing
on
okay so uh let's head back up there
actually i'm gonna run these pipes for
all the passive mobs we're working on
today
and then i'll meet you up there
all right guys it's mob sorting time
are you excited i'm excited
yeah how could you not be excited
so the pipes come up here now so this
one's gonna be for chickens
i've decided and this one's gonna be for
wolves
this one's gonna be for pigs
this one's gonna be for sheep and cows
but firstly for sheep if we ever figure
a way to
separate them the cows will go in this
one i think
so i might leave this one vacant
for right now so sheep and cows in that
one
how do we begin this well we gotta get
rid of this
dirt junk don't need it anymore
[Applause]
okay i'm gonna put down our snow
over here don't need to kill the mobs
anymore
and we will run glass
tubing down here
you know what i'm gonna cover this
because they're gonna get really
annoying if they keep coming down here
aren't you piggy yes you are aren't you
chicken
that guy will live okay so we first
thing we gotta do is separate the
chickens we
do that using gravity uh from our
experience on chocolate island we pretty
much know how to do
all of this okay so we're gonna have a
water stream
right over there we're gonna keep it
held up using signs
like okay
still haven't uh rebooted my computer
from last episode
okay so there'll be
a water stream
up here flowing to the right and i
think what we're gonna do let me
come out over here
okay and
it'll flow out of the way
across here and then forward to this
tube here
that's how we're gonna do the chicken
one fairly simple
everything else the sheep uh
cows pigs wolves and
if any squids show up above they should
fall through here too
i don't know if we're gonna deal with
them or not we can if we
if we want to
um
should i use snow
i may as well use snow okay so oops i
already messed up that's why i don't
like using snow
okay
we are going to keep this
raised up one block because we're going
to need that one block height
for separating the walls i believe have
that closed
gotta try to get this all done today
guys gonna hurry
[Music]
okay this will continue on
probably shouldn't be using snow
let's continue on uh right here we're
gonna have
half slabs
and we're gonna use these kind because i
think they'll look best with snow
the old plain original half slabs
okay we'll have one
there it's safe to put our water here
now
so we get pushed to the right we're
gonna have our pig wolf separator here
next and i believe
i want them to go
to the right yeah to the right
the one i made on chocolate island big
separate i had on chocolate island
was only
one wide really this one we're gonna
make at least two wide because the odd
time i was finding pigs
made it past the pig separator and
ended up with the sheep in the cows
when there was when there's a lot of
pigs entering the thing at a time
uh yeah we need half slabs here too
and we will put
glass here
so the idea is we'll have a stream a
water stream right here that's going to
flow
this way and also diagonally
this way
oh you know what we're doing this wrong
guys we're doing it wrong
it's been a while we don't want half
slaps here
we want solid blocks here
pigs are one block high sheep and cows
sorry pigs are one block high wolves are
less than one block high
so they'll fit through this one high gap
okay sheep and cows they're about a
block and a half just under
so they won't be able to fit through
here they'll continue going on
this way
right and
so we'll build this up and place some
soil temporarily
glass over here
and the trick i found with separating
pigs
and wolves 100 from sheep and cows was
to make them rub their heads against the
ceiling
the other methods before i figured that
out had
the water on the ground and they would
bob up and down
and most of the time they would get
separated but sometimes it wouldn't
so in order to get this working
100 you need them to rub their heads
against this
glass block here
which continues oops to here
um not sure how long we're gonna make
this
probably probably at least five blocks
and the water will go here it'll flow
[Music]
yeah this is probably good enough it can
probably
wide enough i should say probably wide
enough
so the pig and wolf area here is two
blocks wide get out of here
the one on chocolate island was only one
wide and they would sometimes jam
up
so we'll run this and
just temporarily we'll have that there
kind of trying to be careful not to
spill water everywhere
uh let's get some more lighting
so if we place water right now it's
gonna flow
like this
and that was some lag
uh break time
yeah sometimes when fraps uh splits my
recordings up
the new the new file it creates
is super laggy when it's recording so
i need to stop recording and restart
that's what happened there
but i skipped a day got some more snow
uh i think i did some other things i
can't remember
anyway let's continue on here
we're 13 minutes in already so
gotta hurry up guys i want to finish
this today
well at least get very close to finished
okay we have
have it like this how far is this it
goes
since the water is there it goes one two
three four five
six seven eight so that's as far as
water will go
so if we put a block here it'll be safe
to put water down
here without it pouring everywhere
because that's that's where it'll end
okay
so now in this stream we should have
wolves and pigs
and in this stream here we'll just have
sheep and
holy
wow okay that scared me
ah
uh break time
okay continuing on i've changed my mind
about something
so this is going to be chickens now this
will be pigs
this will be sheep and cows this will be
wolves
this will be banking vape vacant
decent oh i'm so bad with words
i can't remember what it is now the
reason for that is wolves are
rarer than the other mob types and they
don't drop anything
the first ones i'm going to come up to
first one i'll come to when i
walk to my emp units will be this one
and this one then this one
so if wolves aren't dropping anything i
want to be the first
the furthest one away from me
uh okay so continuing on let's go
let's go here we go you can cover this
up
pretty sure
boom done okay
next so all three of our streams here
are incomplete at the moment
which one should i work on this one's
pigs
we can probably very simply
just run it like this straight there
and that's another reason why i kind of
want that pigs because i think it will
be really simple
uh i forgot that
we went up two blocks here so i didn't
really need to have this raised off the
ground
at the start because we gained the block
anyway
uh anyway does it doesn't matter much
it just makes it kind of easier
so yeah we'll go like this
right to here
and the pigs will fall down
wrong did it wrong try again
we need a diagonal water stream to
separate the wolves
from the pigs so this needs to come out
one more block
like so glass
water stream will go here pushing
them kind of that way
and
first
how to do this how to do this okay i
think we can put
a ladder here that'll be our first
separator for the wolves i think we'll
have
two that's all we need
i'm hoping so
run this up have another ladder here
and so the way this works is pigs are so
fat that they won't
fit if there's a ladder there but wolves
are able to fit through
that gap because uh ladders have a
little bit of a
physical collision mask
makes makes it a little bit thinner here
than if it was a full block
width okay
now let's add another torch so you guys
can see
so we have diagonal water stream going
that way we will have
oops block there
and there
that'll be our split
yeah this should be really easy so we'll
have
snow there
oh
i'm just worried now that the
water streams we need two here and they
might create a
dead no no i just get rid of this
yeah so now we only need one water
stream for this
okay maybe i'll just use glass
here and i just killed a torch so now
you can't see
and run it right to our wolf
ah dang that's not our wolf one is it
that's our shaping tower
how quickly i forget so we like we gotta
go all the way over here
how do we do that the best way
snow gets destroyed so quick with
shovels
you gotta be careful
oh yeah that's the other thing we have
our stream here they might interfere
with each other if we're not
careful
okay well we'll go
[Music]
we only need it one block high
and we can have a half slab going over
top okay this will work
this will all work good pretty sure
okay go all the way along let's
go here
you get the idea so they'll come
all the way to here
the longest stream is the wolf one so
it's a good thing they're the rarest
because that's the least efficient one
okay pigs go down here
uh it's safe to place our water now
i believe yes
oh we need a sign there
we don't want water flowing down
so we'll put a sign there to keep the
water from falling down
and now we will place our water
good so it's a diagonal stream going
that way wolves should go through
these two gaps and whatever's left
should be pigs and they'll fall down
here
if i figured this all right oh
you know what we actually want our glass
here
i'm so clumsy today
[Music]
okay glass here
and fill this in good
get rid of this stuff i want as clean as
possible
i got more glass cooking right now
because we may run out
that should be it for our pigs
i am gonna get some more water and then
we will be back
dang we're like 22 minutes in guys we
gotta
go go go hurry hurry hurry
look at all those guys okay to be fair
last time i
did all this mob stuff this mob sorting
stuff it took i think at least five
episodes so we're
doing great on time if you consider that
kind of mess this up we don't want it
too high in here
necessarily try to keep it one high i
believe would be better
since uh both the pigs and the wolves
will fit in a one-high gap
let's get rid of this
keep it cleaner not again
holy ah i'll see you at the top
right so the wolves are going to come
out here
they'll either fall in the stream over
here
or over here doesn't matter they go to
the same place
right so we can cover this
keep them from escaping
and yeah
okay so this part here it's gonna get a
little bit more tricky
actually let's do the chicken stuff
that's really easy
okay chicken stuff so our water stream
there will
go right and then over so that's one two
three
four blocks so far
that's the fourth block that's a fifth
block
uh let's just run it this way six seven
eight maximum length of water is eight
blocks
so now we will go down one level
and keep on extending it further we
can't use
stairs or half slabs when dealing with
the chickens because they can get stuck
in them
so we need to go down a level
old school method to extend our water
stream
or else resort to using pistons somehow
but that's uh not really the best
solution
because it will lag your game if you
have to use pistons
that's five six seven eight
and one more level it's worked out
pretty good
ends there and we will have
a sign there assuming we had a sign
to keep the water stream from flowing
down
so let me get rid of this i gotta make
sure i don't fall
down it again
this will extend
and this will go like this
not like that ah darn it fell off
so build up the sides for over here
uh actually we should try place our
water if we can
i don't think we can without destroying
a block
we'll get to that in a bit
gotta hurry gotta hurry
wasting too much time here i actually
wanted to like test this all out this
episode
see the emp stuff in action but uh
don't know if that's gonna happen now
okay we only want this one high really
drop there place our water stream
already
and go down a block here
then we'll run it right to
the end here not super
complicated or exciting that's how you
do it
need more water should have set up a
pool an
infinite pool down there although i
guess this isn't too far
see put that there goes to the end
cover this all up so i don't fall down
there again
good okay sweet
awesome
okay i'm going to attempt to place water
and then a glass block quickly so it
doesn't
pour out everywhere
that's how you do it like a pro awesome
so chicken separator should be done
chicken separator is done pig separator
is done wolf separator is mostly done
sheep and cows they gotta get over they
gotta get
over here so we can do that
fairly simple we're allowed to run a
half slab over top here
we'll go underneath it i'm expecting
maybe we'll put a glass block over
over here wolves should go underneath
that
this can just cross over top
let's see how long is that
stream starts there one two three four
five
six seven so far i can go one more
okay if we destroy this it shouldn't
spill out
good very good
very good okay
and finally we can run a short little
stream
to here
[Music]
maybe we'll just have it on the ground
level doesn't really matter
am i out of glass a little bit left
oh i thought i fell down again okay i'm
gonna get more glass and more water
see you in a second
okay over 30 minutes now let's finish
this quickly
okay we'll have a sign here keep the
water from flowing down
our long tube
sheep and cows will fall down to the
stream stream will push them down the
hole
very simple okay
let's fill this in
and one there
blocks there
a little bit hard to see all this glass
gets confusing we may as well uh
fill in our sides
okay sheep and cow should be done now
pretty sure so lastly we have
wolves we just need to extend the stream
i can't remember how i used to do that i
think i would just have
two half slabs build this
up and we need
sign here i need two more signs i think
should have made them before i started
recording
oh well
go go okay
yeah so one sign there one sign here
and build up this other side
so that the water doesn't spill out and
now we can place
water here wolves will go up the stream
and now we can extend it further
cover us up
that there put our final sign
here so once again the water doesn't
flow down
the tube ah we need more water
so yeah we built pretty much a whole
passive mob sorter in one episode i
surprised
to be honest and i didn't uh cut much of
the footage
so it doesn't take that long i guess
it helps if you've done it before
okay finish it up and now let's really
hope this works
wolves should be done everything should
be done
so we're going to open up those
blocks we placed in the center
and then we will see this in action
he's been patiently watching us this
whole
time i can't believe it
okay the last thing i forgot to mention
is i like to have a door here so that i
if i fall down the water streams above
and end up in the center here we can
just walk out
so it's kind of a maintenance access
door
okay that also makes it very easy to get
rid of these soil blocks
and see it running for the first time
might not work too good at for the first
time because we have
a huge abundance of mobs
but it looks like all the pigs got
separated amazingly
all the chickens are getting separated
don't know if we'll get any wolves
this episode but i'll keep an eye on out
for them
but yeah i think i think it's working
all right guys
let's go down below
to our emp units with
i didn't do all the tubes because i
didn't have enough glass at the time
oh yeah they straight fell so they died
all wool in there all pork in
there and bunch of chickens in here
so it is it is working guys i'm happy
awesome
that's great so we have our passive mob
system
up and running now
and even have a egg farm if we want now
so if we were to have an egg farm
what we would do is we would just uh why
yes they're dying anyway
but we'd have those guys die the pigs
die and the chickens living
have water
yes they're not going to swim up
all right we'll talk about some other
time you get the idea it's working now
very cool this episode super long hope
you guys learned a lot
this is kind of like a tutorial on how
to build it of course you would have to
adjust it slightly
if your setups different which it most
likely will be
but you should get the idea
i do get a lot of brown sheep here in
this biome and also i saw
one pink sheep so far so
it's looking good and i have seen a few
wolves but i don't know if they're that
common
in this biome they don't seem to be
not like on chocolate island
but yeah that's it for today guys thank
you for watching and i'll see you again
next time
[Music]
cooked pork chop anyone
that features working great they die
from the fall damage
and since they're on fire they still
make a cookboard chop
getting lots of wool
i forgot something though
i forgot the freaking squid so let's go
back up here
really quick i just want to show you
what to do if it's a concern for you
it's not really for me because i have
lots of water around my world so they're
more likely to spawn
in the ocean and not thousands of blocks
of water
i have in the ocean than the few dozen i
have
in my passive spawning pads
but if you're in a dry area it's a
possibility
i would suggest either digging up this
block or
probably probably just
this block here
yeah okay dig that out
so what you're gonna do is you're gonna
take advantage of the fact that squid
sink and water and all the other mobs
will try to swim in water
get rid of that
and the squid will go up that half step
he might
stop in a little bit of air there
if he does any other mob that comes by
will push him into this water here i'm
hoping you actually
maybe make this too wide
there's a chance of them falling in a
one wide and a one
in one block like that is pretty low
yes left two
and then just make a
make your stream for them however you
want
oops i don't really know where i'm going
with mine yet so
i'm not going to worry about it i really
doubt i'll get any
squid in mine even but you can uh play
around with the
idea
fill that in and they should swim into
the stream here
the other passive mob should swim over
top that hopefully
you can see it happen
let me tell may take a little while here
come on guys
yeah when i'm up here past the passive
mobs aren't really going to spawn
because i'm too close to them
i'll get a few though
yeah they still swim up against the
ceiling there so it's still working
that's my recommendation or else you
could try over here
like this block here and there's a
chance that the squid
will go down instead of going up this
half slab
but you'd have to play around with it
because i don't know for sure
all right that's it bye bye thanks for
watching hope you enjoyed
take care