hey everyone it's been a while hasn't it
you still remember who this is right
he's so evil so mr. Heath oh yeah Uncle
Leo I mean II though this is Ethel okay
guys let's play some minecraft so if my
voice sounds even worse than normal
today it's because I'm still sick
yep I'm sick I've been sick for a few
days now I'm on my fifth box of Kleenex
now my nose is a nice bright red and
nobody's saying soft kitty to me yet so
I need to play some minecraft to lift my
spirits so that's what you're gonna do
today
excuse my coughing throughout this video
and as you can see all the loose blocks
and junk are gone it's all levelled out
here from our an explosion in last
episode that turned out really good by
the way thank you everyone that helped
try making viral and got close to 5,000
likes I think about 1400 favorites or
something so did pretty good that's over
five times the normal at least I don't
think it will go viral but it did get
quite a few views and Brittany Beiste
helped a bit with that - thank you ready
but yeah looks good so we gotta fill
this all in with water get to later this
episode got lots of stuff to do um so
next part of building my base here is
setting up the spawning pads maybe we'll
go over to that spiral over there first
talk about that so all the grass is gone
now pretty much there's a few loose
grass blocks still in that junk which
will disappear when I for
use it over but most of it's over here
now so this is where all the mobs are
spawning pretty much for the passive
mobs and I just need to run the grass up
high because the spawning pads are gonna
go up high like they were in the Alpha
base so that's what the spirals for just
to bring the grass up it takes grass a
long long time to spread not really any
shortcuts ie a stupid healthy Pig he was
a sick Pig I woulda let him live so it's
got a ways to go here yet when running
grass up though I strongly recommend you
do this bigger spiral method let's go
down I'll try to explain why
so the way I set this up is I just built
like a two-by-two tower up into the sky
and put lights up it's when I had it all
hollowed out okay good enough so what I
did is I had it up like this started
digging down making this spiral connect
at the bottom with the grass I had there
but if you try to run grass up that
it'll take
I don't know years it'll take forever so
the next thing I did is I just made this
wider I went like this this is how I did
the spiral and that'll get the grass up
a lot faster if your soil is wider and
you do that all the way to the top
and make sure you have torches otherwise
the grass won't spread probably although
in the might I don't know okay so that's
how I am moving the grass up you can see
cow just spawned up there so it's gonna
work out pretty good when it's all done
the plan for this ice base here is to
build five different mob systems
okay so there's gonna be a squid system
I'll probably do that last because it's
the most work I think it'll be a slime
system for collecting slimes I have a
good idea in mind that's unique that I
haven't seen before
and it should be pretty effective so I'm
excited to do that sometime so we get
squid slime there'll also be the passive
mob system
haven't fully decided how I'm gonna do
that yet I'll probably make it similar
to the one I have on
chocolate island the only difference is
I would like to although be two main
differences number one I won't use the
canal system like I have with the water
stairs and sign trick that I came up
with I won't be using that because
checking you got stuck in the stairs so
I'm gonna use a different method for the
canals and also for the spawning pads I
would like to have it on off for the
passing lobs and the only way of doing
that is water really so I need come up
with a design that the water will spread
evenly over all the pads if you have a
square though it doesn't do that
it's a problem and I like to use the six
by six pads ideally but I don't think
the water will cooperate with that too
well so I might have to make a diamond
shape possibly or I may just skip to the
idea of having an on/off with water
okay so this is kind of these four
blocks or the center you place water on
them though it won't spread all over
take the shortest route down so
gonna be a problem another way to do
something like roboticus did is having
signs all the way on the outside hold
the water in and still let the mob's
pass through but that seems like more
work than I'm willing to put into the
idea so probably either be a diamond
shape or I'll just forget about having
an on/off
okay so squid slime passive mobs and
then there's gonna be two hostile mob
systems the first one's gonna be pretty
much the same as the one I'm using now
this is my favorite it's a 6x6 pad and
then I have these four half slabs to
prevent spiders from spawning when
Pistons came out I had the idea of
attaching Pistons to the half slabs and
retracting these so that I could turn
spiders spawning on and off when I
attempted the wire though I deem up on
the idea because it just seemed like a
huge hassle but then it wasn't long
after that my viewers start sending me
video responses with the idea as well
and they actually showed how to wire it
so kind of regained my interest in it
and that it'll probably use it
unfortunately it was a long time ago
that people said to me these video
responses so don't remember who it was
but if you want you can send them again
to this video and that way you can get
credit that you deserve I did change the
wiring though from what they showed me
this is how I'm doing it I think and
probably just have a redstone torch
underneath somewhere here and then have
canals on the outside here the wiring
has to go underneath the canals which is
the main issue oops
okay so I need a break again one sec so
I'll have the spider option on/off and I
also plan on setting up a light system
for above each of these pads to turn
hostile mob spawns on or off as well in
the system so this should work out
pretty good and this is the fifth mob
system I'm gonna be building also a
hostile mob one
the main difference though this is aimed
at high efficiency its main purpose will
be to collect gunpowder as quickly as
possible the way it works is mobs should
spawn on top of these pressure plates
zombies skeletons and creepers only
spiders won't spawn in here I don't
think and as soon as they spawn
there's Pistons all along here sticky
pistons they get activated and pushed
the mob off the pressure plate and the
plan is to make them fall to their death
as quickly as possible to make an
efficient mob system the goal is to kill
the mob as quickly as possible to spawn
them as quickly as possible and kill
them as quickly as possible but this
thing is not perfect like there is a
reason for having to they have
advantages and disadvantages over each
other for example this one you can spawn
spiders if you want or not this one you
don't have any option for that this one
this is the one I'm gonna be hooking up
to the EMP units so I'll be able to do
different things with that feature
with this style you can manipulate mobs
while they're still alive while with
this one you pretty much have to kill
them instantly nothing special you can
do with them and you know stuff like
that another big thing this 6x6 by let's
say three high pad has 32 blocks that
mobs can spawn on and by comparison this
7 by 3 by 8 long section here there's
only 16 spots that mobs can spawn on so
this one's way bigger and it has less
sin well has half the spawning space so
yeah that's a disadvantage I also plan
on oops
putting a light system in here as well
and I will only have one of them going
at a time so if I want to click
gunpowder this one will be on if I want
them to go to the EMP unit this one will
be on it's a plan acid mob system and
both these hostile mob systems are gonna
be built up in the air but like 30
blocks are so high above the middle of
my base here and that's so I can take
advantage of gravity I still do
recommend the hostile mob system I use
on chocolate island if you want a
practical one
the nice thing about it is you gain
resources when you're digging it out
it's easy to set up you know and it you
don't have an ugly spawning pad up in
the air you know messing up the look of
your base if you go with the system I
use on chocolate island after you build
one in the air though a sky trap style
the advantage is you don't need to use a
mob Vader which takes time for them to
swim up you can just drop them down no
problem so
most instant so it's much more efficient
because he can kill the mobs quicker
doing that but you know they each have
their advantages and disadvantages use
whatever style you wish moving on I got
this item collection system for all my
EMP units working now just need to put
the floor over this turned out really
well
items will fall in these water streams
and they will get shot right to the end
of course they're freezing right now
because there's no floor over this this
will be too high in here flip the floor
over it
so that I can still come down here and
do maintenance if I need to and I have
all these piston things set up and they
turned out really well
waters on waters off let's see a working
one with a fake floor here this is a
block that moves these barriers are open
so the water is free to flow a big
concern of many of my viewers was that
the water was going to destroy the
levers I was also worried about this but
there's a trick to it if you timed this
block moving just right oh nothing wrong
there is it gonna flood it does a little
bit but it doesn't wreck anything so
that turned out perfect why this works
is a little bit complicated should I
attempt to explain it yeah I'll do my
best here
okay so the water is right above here
right behind this piston so it needs to
move one block to where that piston is
then over one more that's two three four
five so five blocks movement over here
is equivalent to twenty five ticks
because water moves five ticks each time
ooh not doing well on the explaining
here okay time it takes water stream to
move over one block is five ticks so
here is five five block changes here is
six so that's 30 ticks okay if we go
around to the back here the way I have
it wired the lever for the water control
is over behind the snow block here goes
over excellent activates the piston to
let the water out but it also branches
off here goes down there's one torch
okay
okay it comes down there's that torch
there's another torch here that's two
torches over to here and towards my
third torch oh yeah
this is my third torch plus three
torches and there's three repeaters set
to four for a total of fifteen torches
and one torch has a delay of two ticks
so in total that comes to 30 ticks which
is the same as the water remember I said
water moving six blocks is 30 ticks the
redstone current passing through fifteen
torches is also 30 ticks so it's the
same amount of time let's go back up so
when the water gets to this glass block
here that's when this block moves down
so that it finds the opening here and it
goes straight to the hole instead of
spreading everywhere now when its watch
right when it gets here so when that
goes down the reason it does that is
because I believe the piston cuts the
water so it only retracts one two three
four five blocks instead of six or
twenty five ticks so there's a
difference it doesn't take as long for
the water to disappear as it takes for
it to appear which is why we don't need
any fancy wiring to achieve this effect
it's very simple I just made it very
complicated for no good reason and as
you can see moves the items
all is good assuming of course my water
streams down here down here aren't
frozen this should work good they won't
freeze once the floor is on
so it's pretty cool pretty cool and this
corner these corner ones have extra
logic to them there's an or gate so that
this one's on this is open these are
both on still open only this one's on
it's still open ooh oh that might be a
problem no that's that's fine even if it
does that because it goes over the hole
I can't believe I never saw that before
it's only if they're both off that this
block comes back and we have our solid
floor again so if this or this then that
so I use it or gate for this and I
believe I showed it already
take another fall here ouch so this is
one wire goes to this torch here and
there's also the other wire oops
which goes to the same torch so this
torch here is the or gate sends power
above which activates this repeater
which sends power to this block and
activates the Pistons and all that fancy
stuff which we saw in an earlier video
so that's how that's working now okay so
I set up this diagonal string of ice
here just because I wanted to show you
something fun you can do with ice if you
got to fill in big area with water this
is pretty cool plates torches all along
here
make the ice melt for the big area
normally if you try to place water with
buckets to fill us in you'll have to
deal with the water freezing and messing
up your fill pattern and it takes a long
time to do even with buckets so else is
kind of weird
the water isn't spreading okay nevermind
- this didn't work for some reason water
doesn't seem to spread if it did spread
okay you know what I'm gonna do I'm
gonna wait for them all to death ah then
I'm gonna place a torch and see what
happens next to it
no keys they're all water now wasn't
expecting this but if we place a block
next to the water it should force them
to update so this should still work I
think actually that won't work okay
let's try this out yeah that's pretty
cool
self-creating lake sea ice is already
starting erected not you have some
splainin to do kind of a glitch that was
pretty fun actually now we have a huge
lake and I just have a little bit left
to fill in yet this episode is getting a
little bit long now I would like to wrap
it up pretty quick here the last thing I
wanted to talk about is the aesthetics
of this building here I think I might
refer to it as a lab from now on I'm not
sure originally what I was planning on
doing was having like a black was it
black no I think a green blue I think um
having a blue outline something like
this doesn't really match with this
pattern here so I'd probably fill this
make it straight and make that five wide
walkway type thing
something like this and then fill center
with black wool this is the color scheme
wise thinking of originally something
like that so there'd be a walkway on
this right side it'll go around and then
come back on that side there and then
they'll be stairs coming up to this
section here or going down to this
section here I'm not sure yet and this
will be the walkway another thing I was
thinking of is using green or purple
instead of the blue but you know I've
never really used color wool for
aesthetics before so it's not really my
specialty so let's look at one other
thing I was thinking of the other thing
I was thinking is that like a sandstone
floor like this with snow on the other
side
or possibly keeping it straight again
I'm not really sure really my favorite
blocks to build with our wood planks
sandstone logs Leafs leaves I should say
snow glass that type of stuff if I do
snow and the wool blocks you know I
probably won't do the sandstone and that
kind of look so I need to decide they'll
probably be some kind of centerpiece in
this room I just don't know what it is
yet but if you have other ideas let me
know too or else let me know between
those two ideas I've had yeah like I
said aesthetics is not my specialty
so the spotting pads will be up high
here glass tubes it'll be going to the
ceiling somehow I'll try to make the
spawning pads look good I know I said
that on chocolate Island and I still
haven't made that happen but hopefully
hopefully I'll make it look good here at
least and ideally make it look good for
both both my bases but yeah that's it
for today thank you for watching as
always and until next time take care